<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: /es | theta trades]]></title>
  <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/categories/slash-es/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-03-17T18:05:30-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[theta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Short-Term Traders Continue to Dominate]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/14/short-term-traders-continue-to-dominate/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-14T17:09:23-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/14/short-term-traders-continue-to-dominate</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ll give a short market update on the broad market indices and then save a post later for possible trade ideas.</p>

<p>Today&rsquo;s price action continues to show some short-term traders here dominating. On the /ES, we tagged the single prints separating the two distributions on Friday, and then instead of pushing prices lower, we backed off and traded back upwards. This shows that shorter term traders are just trading responsively, and it also shows that they&rsquo;re just lacking confidence to push this higher or lower. Furthermore, we closed on a Doji today, so another reason we&rsquo;ve got a low confidence market.</p>

<p>SPX is still on track to tag the 2060 level, though to me, the market feels really heavy, and we might not get there. Watch for a possible reversal or breakout tomorrow, as we basically spent the whole day today balancing thus forming that Doji:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03142016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03142016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-14 Daily Time Frame - Target 2060 - Doji" /></a></p>

<p>NDX crept higher today, and will probably slowly float upwards to the 61.8% fib level:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03142016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03142016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-03-14 Daily Time Frame - Target 61.8% Fibonacci ~ 4415" /></a></p>

<p>DJX also looks like it wants to tag that trendline resistance:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03142016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03142016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-03-14 Daily Time Frame - Target Trendline Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>RUT here kind of stalling. Continue to monitor that trendline to see if we break it to the upside or fail back down:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03142016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/03142016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-03-14 Daily Time Frame - Trendline Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>Continue to monitor the markets closely. Again, I feel like traders are just tired of pushing prices higher, but we also have Janet stepping up to the mic on Wednesday, so be careful and trade cautiously.</p>

<p>Stay tuned for trade ideas coming up, and <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive/">follow me on Twitter</a> to get notified real-time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Short Term Traders Dominating]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/10/short-term-traders-dominating/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-10T19:09:16-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/10/short-term-traders-dominating</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The market has been doing nothing other than balancing over the past 8 trading sessions. We&rsquo;re bracketing, and it&rsquo;s apparent that the market is being dominated by the shorter term traders looking to buy at the bottom of balance and sell at the top. We&rsquo;re unable to push prices higher, and today, we look below and failed. All of this price action over the past couple of weeks paints a very clear picture: traders have extremely low confidence.</p>

<p>While one can argue that the market seems bearish because Mario wasn&rsquo;t able to push prices higher with his market manipulation techniques, one can also argue that if we were truly bearish, we wouldn&rsquo;t have look outside below balance, and then come back in. We settled today at the point of control, which has just been getting more and more prominent over the past couple of weeks. Traders just like it here.</p>

<p>Today we formed a poor low in the /ES. Expect that to be repaired in the (possibly near) future.</p>

<p>/CL seems a bit confused about where it wants to go. We&rsquo;ve had back to back days that just completely engulfed the previous days, until today, when we closed on a Doji:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03102016/cl_f.png"><img src="/images/blog/03102016/cl_f.png" alt="/CL - 2016-03-10 Daily Time Frame - Doji, Fibonacci" /></a></p>

<p>Crude looks like it wants to hit 40 or the 61.8% fib level. I&rsquo;ve set up the 39.5/40/40.5 balanced butterfly for a 0.30 debit.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today. Good luck and happy trading in in the markets tomorrow.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
