<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: /es | ThetaTrades]]></title>
  <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/categories/slash-es/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-05-26T09:44:53-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[theta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Expecting Some Consolidation]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/05/26/expecting-some-consolidation/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-26T05:57:04-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/05/26/expecting-some-consolidation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here&rsquo;s the volume composite again on the /ES over the past month:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05262016/es.png"><img src="/images/blog/05262016/es.png" alt="/ES - 2016-05-26 - 1h Chart - Volume Composite" /></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m still watching the high volume nodes at 2075 and 2085 to see how they develop.</p>

<p>This past week, we&rsquo;ve seen value area gapping higher, which is bullish. After a few sessions, expect a pause and some rebalancing before the trend either continues or reverses. We may get that pause today as we&rsquo;re trading near the highest high volume node.</p>

<p>Yesterday we put on call calendars on AAPL and NFLX. AAPL hasn&rsquo;t done much since, but NFLX looks to be trading up 4 premarket. This is good for our short term calendar, but our longer term call ratio will be hurting a bit here. No worries as we have time to work it out, and our breakeven is a bit above 105, which is the gap fill. We&rsquo;ll see what happens and adjust if necessary.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today&rsquo;s morning market outlook. We&rsquo;ll be doing more trade adjustments today, so as always, make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me there</a> to receive tweets about our trades in real-time.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Watch Development of HVN at 2075-2085]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/05/25/watch-development-of-hvn-at-2075-2085/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-25T06:27:07-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/05/25/watch-development-of-hvn-at-2075-2085</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>/ES broke out of the descending channel yesterday and closed strong above it. This is slightly bullish, but in a long term perspective, still neutral:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05252016/es.png"><img src="/images/blog/05252016/es.png" alt="/ES - 2016-05-25 - 1h Chart - Volume Composite" /></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m expecting tomorrow&rsquo;s action to pause a bit, especially after such a rally. If this happens, it only makes the developing volume node at 2075 more prominent.</p>

<p>Watch how the volume composite develops throughout this week. 2075 to 2085 could become the high volume node over the past 30 days. Also, developing value at the upper end of the balance area primes us for a stronger breakout to the upside.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for the market outlook. As always, we&rsquo;ll be entering new trades and adjusting/exiting our existing positions, so be sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow us on Twitter</a>.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Market Still Remains in Balance - Be Theta Positive]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/05/24/market-still-remains-in-balance-be-theta-positive/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-24T05:17:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/05/24/market-still-remains-in-balance-be-theta-positive</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In a market that barely moves these days, it&rsquo;s great when the core of your portfolio is theta positive. We already are, but this is just an emphasis on that fact.</p>

<p>The market is still stuck within the large balance area between 2080 and 2012, with 2052 being a very prominent volume node:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05242016/es.png"><img src="/images/blog/05242016/es.png" alt="/ES - 2016-05-24 - 1h Chart - Volume Composite" /></a></p>

<p>The next prominent HVN over the past 30 days appears to be 2075, which is towards the upper end of this balance area. 2075 would be the first upside target to aim for if we see the market move higher. Placing a butterfly there for a credit would be a great play, or some kind of a call ratio with more room to the upside. I&rsquo;ll be looking for something to do here.</p>

<p>Volume has been extremely low during these past trading sessions, but for us, it doesn&rsquo;t really matter. Keep that in mind, though, as a breakout of the balance area may cause volume to start picking back up again, and depending on your portfolio, you may need to adjust.</p>

<p>Yesterday we opened new trades on $NFLX, $TGT and $ES_F. These all seem to be looking good so far. Keep an eye on $NFLX - I think it&rsquo;s going to be interesting seeing how it plays out.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for the market outlook. As always, we&rsquo;ll be entering new trades and adjusting/exiting our existing positions, so be sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow us on Twitter</a>.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets today!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Market Remains in Balance]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/05/23/market-remains-in-balance/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-23T05:25:23-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/05/23/market-remains-in-balance</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last week, we had a whole lot of nothing, closing the week flat where we started:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05232016/es.png"><img src="/images/blog/05232016/es.png" alt="/ES - 2016-05-23 - Weekly Chart" /></a></p>

<p>Notice the developing high volume node around 2050 on the /ES:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05232016/es_profile.png"><img src="/images/blog/05232016/es_profile.png" alt="/ES - 2016-05-23 - 4h Chart - Volume Composite" /></a></p>

<p>Traders love this spot, and it&rsquo;s smack in the middle of our big balance area. Consider buying wide, weekly butterflies in this area to capture a lot of theta.</p>

<p>So what I&rsquo;m looking for this week on the /ES is for us to continue staying in balance along this descending channel:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05232016/es_channel.png"><img src="/images/blog/05232016/es_channel.png" alt="/ES - 2016-05-23 - 1d Chart - Descending Channel" /></a></p>

<p>Watch for bounces off of the channel support and resistance.</p>

<p>Last week we booked many winners. We had a few losers which were the small calendar debits we payed for, but they were offset by the winners significantly. As always, we&rsquo;ll be entering new trades and adjusting/exiting our existing positions, so be sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow us on Twitter</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nothing New]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/05/13/nothing-new/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-13T05:32:26-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/05/13/nothing-new</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="/images/blog/05132016/es.png"><img src="/images/blog/05132016/es.png" alt="/ES - 2016-05-13 - 15m Chart - Volume Profile" /></a></p>

<p>Yesterday, we had another day where value area overlapped the prior days&rsquo;s value area. Again, this spells low confidence - traders have a tough time getting prices to trend in any direction whatsoever. We had liquidation breaks followed by short squeezes closely following each other in many of the recent sessions (yesterday&rsquo;s price action showed that very clearly), so the struggle between the Bulls and the Bears continue.</p>

<p>The /ES is currently down approximately 4 points at the time of this writing. For today, I&rsquo;m not expecting much, as I&rsquo;m still neutral here until we get out of this low confidence environment and are able to establish a trend. Remember guys, don&rsquo;t be fooled by price; continue watching those value areas, and keep in mind the HVN at 2050 below us, and 2075 above us.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today&rsquo;s market outlook. As a side note, I&rsquo;ll be out of town until 5/23 and will have limited access to the blog during this time; however, I will still be managing our trades, so make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> - that&rsquo;s where I post all of my trade entries/adjustments/exits in real-time. To get the most out of Twitter, turn on notifications specifically from me to be able to get my tweets on your phone as they come.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets, and enjoy the weekend.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
