<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: /es | ThetaTrades]]></title>
  <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/categories/slash-es/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-04-25T20:37:05-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[theta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Watch for an Upside Move]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/25/watch-for-an-upside-move/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-25T20:11:37-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/25/watch-for-an-upside-move</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Value continues to build lower:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04242016/es.png"><img src="/images/blog/04252016/es.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-04-25 - 15m Chart - Volume Profile" /></a></p>

<p>That&rsquo;s definitely not a bullish sign; however, just to stay alert, I wanted to point out one thing that I noticed over the past two trading sessions that has me prepared for a move back to the upside, and this is the way in which the Bears have attempted to push prices lower. You may have noticed the slow and steady grind lower during Friday&rsquo;s action and today&rsquo;s action. This has me thinking that the Bears aren&rsquo;t really confident, and they&rsquo;re struggling to push prices lower, but ultimately unable to. You can see this clearly during the past two trading sessions, where much of the grind lower gets wiped out by a big rip to the upside towards the end of each session.</p>

<p>Also, notice that today, we managed to close above the intermediate balance area high. I would not be surprised tomorrow if we hold above that level and trade near the POC from last Monday, Thursday, or Friday, which is around 2085. If so, I would consider that bullish, and would be looking to put on some type of a credit trade that captures a move into the 2100 level going forward.</p>

<p>For me to switch my bias to bearish, I would need to see the 2067 level fail. If we close below there with signs of stronger selling, I&rsquo;ll be looking to target the other side of balance, which is down at 2012. More intermediate targets would occur along the way, but they&rsquo;ll be noted when we do break 2067.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today. For now, I&rsquo;m still keeping my bias neutral, but watching for any bullish/bearish signals.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Will the Bears Continue the Selling Pressure?]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/21/will-the-bears-continue-the-selling-pressure/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-21T18:49:01-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/21/will-the-bears-continue-the-selling-pressure</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We saw a nice liquidation break today, and actually saw the first sign of sellers being able to keep that pressure on throughout the entire RTH session. Let&rsquo;s take a look at the overall volume profile over the past 20 days:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04212016/es.png"><img src="/images/blog/04212016/es.png" alt="/ES - 2016-04-21 - Volume Profile - 20 days" /></a></p>

<p>We can see that today, not only did we clearly create value lower, but also look where the point of control migrated to: basically back to where it was on Monday. We&rsquo;re now exploring this area to see if this is the fairest price to do business.</p>

<p>And if we zoom in and take a closer look at the past couple of weeks:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04212016/es_zoomed.png"><img src="/images/blog/04212016/es_zoomed.png" alt="/ES - 2016-04-21 - Volume Profile - Zoomed In - Value Area Gapping Lower" /></a></p>

<p>Notice today, our value area not only migrated lower, but also it did not overlap yesterday&rsquo;s value area. When value areas gap like this, it <em>generally</em> signifies the start of a new trend (although a larger gap would&rsquo;ve been better to signify stronger selling pressure). Will the selling continue tomorrow? We can only wait to find out, but until then, bias is neutral.</p>

<p>Going forward, here are important reference points to keep in mind: I&rsquo;ll be watching how the <strong>2081.75</strong> level holds tomorrow. <strong>The area between 2067 and 2081.75 can be considered a balance area</strong>, which was formed last week for a few days before we broke higher out of it this Monday. If we fall back into this area tomorrow and we start seeing some really strong selling pressure (watch the internals), look to target the other side of that balance area, which is <strong>2067</strong>.</p>

<p>Before wrapping up, I&rsquo;d like to propose a trade idea, which I haven&rsquo;t in a while. Here&rsquo;s <strong>HAL</strong> on the daily:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04212016/hal.png"><img src="/images/blog/04212016/hal.png" alt="HAL - 2016-04-21 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m looking to position a trade around <strong>HAL</strong> that assumes the analog of what happened last year would happen again this year. If so, a trade that captures a slow retracement to the bottom of the right orange rectangle over the next month or so would probably be ideal.</p>

<p>I couldn&rsquo;t find any butterflies/put backratios that were great, so I was thinking a small calendar play may work here, specifically, the JUN/MAY 36 PUT calendar:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04212016/hal_calendar.png"><img src="/images/blog/04212016/hal_calendar.png" alt="HAL - 2016-04-21 - Put Calendar" /></a></p>

<p>This is a much longer-term play, and we&rsquo;ll need to wait probably around a month or so for the premium to really start coming in. If you have a slight bearish bias on the energy sector, this could be the play for you.</p>

<p>One thing to note is that this company does have earnings coming up, but I&rsquo;m not really expecting the stock to move much to the downside, and we have quite some time for the trade to work out for us. I&rsquo;ll be looking to put this trade on tomorrow, so be on the lookout for that.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today - as always, make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a>. That is where I post all of my trades in real-time. Make sure you turn on notifications specifically from me. Just go to my Twitter profile on your mobile device, select the Settings gear, and then select the option to turn on notifications.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets tomorrow, and remember to keep those reference points in mind on the /ES.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Value Building Higher]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/20/value-building-higher/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-20T21:40:42-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/20/value-building-higher</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Value builds higher:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04202016/es.png"><img src="/images/blog/04202016/es.png" alt="/ES - 2016-04-20 - Volume Profile" /></a></p>

<p>Towards the end of the trading session, we had a nice liquidation break, and we bounced right off yesterday&rsquo;s value area high. So still, very short term reference points in play here. Regardless, this is still bullish, as value continues to build higher, and volume POCs continue to move higher. This liquidation break only strengthened the market.</p>

<p><em>Bias is still bullish until sellers step up.</em></p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today. If you haven&rsquo;t already, make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a>. That is where I post all of my trades in real-time. Don&rsquo;t forget to turn on notifications specifically from me. Just go to my Twitter profile on mobile, select the Settings gear, and then select the option to turn on notifications.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Value Building Higher]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/14/value-building-higher/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-14T21:38:50-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/14/value-building-higher</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Market remains strong as value builds higher:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04142016/esm6.png"><img src="/images/blog/04142016/esm6.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-04-14 - Market Profile - 20d Zoomed In" /></a></p>

<p>We were able to hold above the balance area for the second trading session after the breakout. Stay with the trend, and that is up. Any kind of a pullback on not-so-bearish internals can be considered buy points, as short term traders are still the most dominant traders out there in terms of price action. 2067 would be that point.</p>

<p>We are at some very interesting points in the broad market indices, so just wanted to briefly present them.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the SPX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04142016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04142016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-04-14 - Daily" /></a></p>

<p>We&rsquo;re just about 10 points away from 2092 on the SPX, which would be the trendline resistance point by tomorrow. As mentioned yesterday, we expected a consolidation day today, and that is exactly what we got today, that Doji. Watch for either a continuation or a reversal tomorrow.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the DJX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04142016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04142016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-04-14 - Daily" /></a></p>

<p>We just barely tagged the high from back in November, closing on a spinning top. Again, watch for a continuation or a reversal tomorrow.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04142016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04142016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-04-14 - Daily" /></a></p>

<p>Very similar here as it&rsquo;s also closing today on a Doji like the SPX after tagging that trendline resistance.</p>

<p>And the RUT:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04142016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/04142016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-04-14 - Daily" /></a></p>

<p>Touching that trendline resistance today and closing on a spinning top.</p>

<p>These are all very similar patterns across all the indices, so we shall see how this all plays out tomorrow.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today. I&rsquo;ll keep posting new entries/adjustments on Twitter, so be sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> to get all of my updates in real time.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets and good trading!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Breaking out of Balance]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/13/breaking-out-of-balance/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-13T18:18:12-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/13/breaking-out-of-balance</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The market broke out of balance very clearly today to the upside as we mentioned yesterday:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04132016/esm6.png"><img src="/images/blog/04132016/esm6.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-04-13 - Market Profile - 15d Zoomed In" /></a></p>

<p>We attempted to trade back below balance, but failed as buyers kept the market up.</p>

<p>On the SPX, we now have clearance to tag the uppermost trendline resistance this Friday at around 2090.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04132016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04132016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-04-13 - Trendline Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>Also, from now on for the SPX chart, the pink rectangles will be removed - the target here has been reached.</p>

<p>Watch for the top of the balance area to hold as support, because we can just as easily fail tomorrow and fall back into the balance area, which is not a strong Bullish signal. If that&rsquo;s the case, I&rsquo;ll be looking for a rotation all the way back down to the bottom of the balance area (2012) as a weekly play. However, tomorrow, I&rsquo;m looking for some consolidation before any moves higher.</p>

<p>One of the plays that I&rsquo;m looking at currently is the SPY MAY2/APR5 211/210 Diagonal Call spread, currently going for about .26 debit:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04132016/spy_call_diagonal.png"><img src="/images/blog/04132016/spy_call_diagonal.png" alt="SPY Diagonal Call Spread - 2016-04-13 - Risk Graph" /></a></p>

<p>This has breakevens at around 206 and 212 over the next few weeks. Given the low volatility that we&rsquo;ve been having and the low confidence in any downmove, as long as we stay in this range, we should be good to milk some premium. I&rsquo;ll be looking to put this on tomorrow.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today. I&rsquo;ll keep posting new entries/adjustments on Twitter, so be sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> to get all of my updates in real time.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets and good trading!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
