<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: balance | ThetaTrades]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/categories/balance/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-02-28T08:32:51-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[theta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Market Still Remains in Balance - Be Theta Positive]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/05/24/market-still-remains-in-balance-be-theta-positive/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-24T05:17:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/05/24/market-still-remains-in-balance-be-theta-positive</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In a market that barely moves these days, it&rsquo;s great when the core of your portfolio is theta positive. We already are, but this is just an emphasis on that fact.</p>

<p>The market is still stuck within the large balance area between 2080 and 2012, with 2052 being a very prominent volume node:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05242016/es.png"><img src="/images/blog/05242016/es.png" alt="/ES - 2016-05-24 - 1h Chart - Volume Composite" /></a></p>

<p>The next prominent HVN over the past 30 days appears to be 2075, which is towards the upper end of this balance area. 2075 would be the first upside target to aim for if we see the market move higher. Placing a butterfly there for a credit would be a great play, or some kind of a call ratio with more room to the upside. I&rsquo;ll be looking for something to do here.</p>

<p>Volume has been extremely low during these past trading sessions, but for us, it doesn&rsquo;t really matter. Keep that in mind, though, as a breakout of the balance area may cause volume to start picking back up again, and depending on your portfolio, you may need to adjust.</p>

<p>Yesterday we opened new trades on $NFLX, $TGT and $ES_F. These all seem to be looking good so far. Keep an eye on $NFLX - I think it&rsquo;s going to be interesting seeing how it plays out.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for the market outlook. As always, we&rsquo;ll be entering new trades and adjusting/exiting our existing positions, so be sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow us on Twitter</a>.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets today!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Still in Balance]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/11/still-in-balance/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-11T20:31:30-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/11/still-in-balance</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We had another late-day selloff. Don&rsquo;t be surprised if we gap up tomorrow morning as we have been doing so much these past couple of weeks.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04112016/esm6_15d.png"><img src="/images/blog/04112016/esm6_15d.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-04-11 - Market Profile - 15d" /></a></p>

<p>We&rsquo;re still trading within the balance area between 2012.25 and 2067, so things still look neutral to me. The next, intermediate downside reference point is 2026. If we can build value near that area (remember 2025 is the POC from the Janet Yellen day - this is the day with the three blue distributions), then I&rsquo;d give the edge to the Bears. Until then, bias remains neutral, but be ready because those reference points below us are weak, as can be seen in the 20-day chart:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04112016/esm6_20d.png"><img src="/images/blog/04112016/esm6_20d.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-04-11 - Market Profile - 20d - Weak Reference Points" /></a></p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today - I&rsquo;ll be posting/adjusting more trades tomorrow, so be sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> to get all of my updates in real time.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets tomorrow!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
