<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: ndx | ThetaTrades]]></title>
  <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/categories/ndx/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-04-25T20:37:05-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[theta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mixed Signals from Indices]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/24/mixed-signals-from-indices/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-24T14:38:16-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/24/mixed-signals-from-indices</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We ended last week on diverging signals. It&rsquo;s important to look at all broad market indices, so let&rsquo;s do that.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the SPX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04242016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04242016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-04-24 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>We have a very clear look above and fail, topping tail pattern, which is generally a bearish signal. However, although we closed below trendline resistance, the week did end up positive, so keep that in mind.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the DJX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04242016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04242016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-04-24 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>This one is a little bit more bullish than the SPX, as we closed just a bit above that 100% retracement level. I do think we start consolidating around this area for a while before we break any higher.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04242016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04242016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-04-24 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>The weakest of the bunch again due to weak earnings from GOOG. It has been unable to close above that trendline resistance, but do keep a close eye on this.</p>

<p>Finally the RUT:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04242016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/04242016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-04-24 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>The most bullish of all indices. This one clearly closed the week above the trendline resistance and has a lot of clearance to continue running to 1200.</p>

<p>Going forward, keep a close eye on all of these indices. They&rsquo;re currently divergent, so it&rsquo;s hard to say whether we should remain bullish or bearish going forward. For now, bias remains neutral.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for the recap - make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a>, because that&rsquo;s where I post all my trades in real-time. Make sure you turn on notifications specifically from me. Just visit my Twitter profile on mobile, select the Settings gear, and then select the option to turn on notifications.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets tomorrow!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Still Bullish...]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/19/still-bullish-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-19T21:29:48-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/19/still-bullish-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Markets still remain bullish.</p>

<p>We&rsquo;ve had mini-liquidation breaks throughout the trading day - all that does is strengthen the market, as it eliminates the shorter-term, weaker hands, allowing buyers to continue doing what they do - buying.</p>

<p>Taking a look at the SPX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04192016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04192016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-04-19 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>We had a nice strong close by the end of the trading session.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the DJX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04192016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04192016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-04-19 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>Also a nice follow through here.</p>

<p>However, the NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04192016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04192016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-04-19 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>Still the weakest of the bunch. This is one that casts a shadow of doubt on the rally - eventually, this, or one or more of the other indices will catch up to the other.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the RUT:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04192016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/04192016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-04-19 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>Consolidating after a move higher from yesterday. Watch for a continuation tomorrow. Our <a href="/trades#RUT" title="RUT Call Calendar">RUT calendar</a> is still looking good, and we&rsquo;re holding on to it - no need to panic out.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today. As always, make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a>. That is where I post all of my trades in real-time. Make sure you turn on notifications specifically from me. Just go to my Twitter profile on mobile, select the Settings gear, and then select the option to turn on notifications.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets tomorrow!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bias Still to the Upside]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/18/bias-still-to-the-upside/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-18T19:01:23-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/18/bias-still-to-the-upside</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Market trucks relentlessly to the upside, and bias remains to the upside until market starts to show signs of sellers.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the SPX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04182016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04182016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-04-18 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>We closed just above that trendline, which can now be considered broken. The next target here is 2100, followed by 2115.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the DJX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04182016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04182016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-04-18 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>Bullish here as well. We closed above the highs of November from last year. The next target would be around 181.9.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04182016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04182016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-04-18 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>The weakest of the bunch, but it closed at the trendline resistance and has room to run to the upside. First target is the gap fill of 2016, which is just about 20 points away.</p>

<p>Finally the RUT:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04182016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/04182016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-04-18 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>This broke the trendline resistance very cleanly. The next major resistance is around 1200.</p>

<p>Today, we put on the trade discussed yesterday for the RUT - you can see that post <a href="/blog/2016/04/17/remaining-cautiously-bullish/" title="RUT Call Calendar Spread">here</a>. If you missed the entry, it&rsquo;s not too late to get in the trade. More importantly, make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a>, because that&rsquo;s where I post all my trades in real-time. Make sure you turn on notifications specifically from me. Just visit my Twitter profile on mobile, select the Settings gear, and then select the option to turn on notifications.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today. Good luck in the markets tomorrow!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Remaining Cautiously Bullish]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/17/remaining-cautiously-bullish/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-17T12:37:47-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/17/remaining-cautiously-bullish</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m continuing to remain cautiously bullish going into next week, given the massive overhead resistance we still have.</p>

<p>Looking at the broad market indices on the weekly, here&rsquo;s the SPX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04172016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04172016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-04-17 - Weekly Chart" /></a></p>

<p>We finished last week with a wide body candle after <em>consolidating</em> for a couple of weeks prior. This leads me to believe that, if we do continue moving up, the trendline resistance up ahead is less likely to hold, given how close we consolidated just under that.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the DJX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04172016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04172016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-04-17 - Weekly Chart" /></a></p>

<p>The previous trendline resistance (now support) is holding up nicely. The same thing can be seen here - consolidation right underneath the 100% Fib level from back in November. This makes me think it&rsquo;s not hard to pierce that resistance level.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04172016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04172016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-04-17 - Weekly Chart" /></a></p>

<p>Again, same thing.</p>

<p>The RUT probably paints the clearest picture:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04172016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/04172016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-04-17 - Weekly Chart" /></a></p>

<p>We&rsquo;ve consolidated over the past two weeks below the trendline and closed the week right up against it. That trendline can easily be invalidated, in which case we&rsquo;d have clearance to run up to the 1200 levels again.</p>

<p>Given what we just saw in the RUT, come Monday I&rsquo;m looking to put on a Call Calendar (again?!) in the RUT (unfortunately, the market has been extremely boring recently, and this is one of the bread and butter strategies during times of low volatility):</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04172016/rut_call_calendar.png"><img src="/images/blog/04172016/rut_call_calendar.png" alt="RUT - 2016-04-17 - Call Calendar" /></a></p>

<p>We&rsquo;ll manage this over the next month. The debit here is quite small for the potential gains we can achieve. If you have a bearish portfolio, this could be quite beneficial if the market does continue running higher.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for this weekend. I&rsquo;ll be posting that trade, along with all other entries/adjustments, live on Twitter, so be sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> to get all of my updates in real time.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets this week!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[More Low Confidence]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/06/more-consolidation/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-06T19:08:41-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/06/more-consolidation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Market continues to consolidate here. As I mentioned yesterday, I just didn&rsquo;t see enough sellers, and that spells low confidence.</p>

<p>Looking at the SPX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04062016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04062016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-04-06 - Daily - Look-Above-And-Fail" /></a></p>

<p>Yesterday&rsquo;s look-above-and-fail pattern failed, and now we&rsquo;re back up above the trendline support. All of this just spells low confidence.</p>

<p>DJX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04062016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04062016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-04-06 - Daily - Bounced off Trendline Support" /></a></p>

<p>Couldn&rsquo;t continue lower after testing the support. Once again, consolidating just above the trendline support.</p>

<p>NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04062016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04062016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-04-06 - Daily - Seller Shutoff" /></a></p>

<p>We&rsquo;re still consolidating here, though we have a wide body candle.</p>

<p>RUT:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04062016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/04062016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-04-06 - Daily - Bullish Engulfing" /></a></p>

<p>We&rsquo;re now back up above the 61.8% Fib level - again, this spells low confidence. When a price level is traded through many times, it&rsquo;s not a sign of trend confidence, but rather a sign of consolidation, or low confidence.</p>

<p>Today, we put on a couple of new trades, specifically calendar spreads in CMG and EEM. We also made some adjustments to our TSLA position (currently our worst trade so far) and closed out our AAPL calendar (at a profit). Check them out in the <a href="/trades" title="Ongoing Trades">Trades</a> page. If you want to be notified when I enter, adjust, or exit trades, make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> so you can receive my updates in real-time. Again, to make the most out of Twitter, make sure you turn on notifications specifically from me. Just visit my Twitter profile on the mobile app, select the Settings gear, and select the <em>Turn on Notifications</em> option.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today. Good luck in the markets tomorrow!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
