<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: calendar | ThetaTrades]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/categories/calendar/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-02-07T18:21:22-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[theta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Expecting Some Consolidation]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/05/26/expecting-some-consolidation/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-26T05:57:04-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/05/26/expecting-some-consolidation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here&rsquo;s the volume composite again on the /ES over the past month:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05262016/es.png"><img src="/images/blog/05262016/es.png" alt="/ES - 2016-05-26 - 1h Chart - Volume Composite" /></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m still watching the high volume nodes at 2075 and 2085 to see how they develop.</p>

<p>This past week, we&rsquo;ve seen value area gapping higher, which is bullish. After a few sessions, expect a pause and some rebalancing before the trend either continues or reverses. We may get that pause today as we&rsquo;re trading near the highest high volume node.</p>

<p>Yesterday we put on call calendars on AAPL and NFLX. AAPL hasn&rsquo;t done much since, but NFLX looks to be trading up 4 premarket. This is good for our short term calendar, but our longer term call ratio will be hurting a bit here. No worries as we have time to work it out, and our breakeven is a bit above 105, which is the gap fill. We&rsquo;ll see what happens and adjust if necessary.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today&rsquo;s morning market outlook. We&rsquo;ll be doing more trade adjustments today, so as always, make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me there</a> to receive tweets about our trades in real-time.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Remaining Cautiously Bullish]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/17/remaining-cautiously-bullish/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-17T12:37:47-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/17/remaining-cautiously-bullish</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m continuing to remain cautiously bullish going into next week, given the massive overhead resistance we still have.</p>

<p>Looking at the broad market indices on the weekly, here&rsquo;s the SPX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04172016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04172016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-04-17 - Weekly Chart" /></a></p>

<p>We finished last week with a wide body candle after <em>consolidating</em> for a couple of weeks prior. This leads me to believe that, if we do continue moving up, the trendline resistance up ahead is less likely to hold, given how close we consolidated just under that.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the DJX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04172016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04172016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-04-17 - Weekly Chart" /></a></p>

<p>The previous trendline resistance (now support) is holding up nicely. The same thing can be seen here - consolidation right underneath the 100% Fib level from back in November. This makes me think it&rsquo;s not hard to pierce that resistance level.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04172016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04172016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-04-17 - Weekly Chart" /></a></p>

<p>Again, same thing.</p>

<p>The RUT probably paints the clearest picture:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04172016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/04172016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-04-17 - Weekly Chart" /></a></p>

<p>We&rsquo;ve consolidated over the past two weeks below the trendline and closed the week right up against it. That trendline can easily be invalidated, in which case we&rsquo;d have clearance to run up to the 1200 levels again.</p>

<p>Given what we just saw in the RUT, come Monday I&rsquo;m looking to put on a Call Calendar (again?!) in the RUT (unfortunately, the market has been extremely boring recently, and this is one of the bread and butter strategies during times of low volatility):</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04172016/rut_call_calendar.png"><img src="/images/blog/04172016/rut_call_calendar.png" alt="RUT - 2016-04-17 - Call Calendar" /></a></p>

<p>We&rsquo;ll manage this over the next month. The debit here is quite small for the potential gains we can achieve. If you have a bearish portfolio, this could be quite beneficial if the market does continue running higher.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for this weekend. I&rsquo;ll be posting that trade, along with all other entries/adjustments, live on Twitter, so be sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> to get all of my updates in real time.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets this week!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
