<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: aud/jpy | ThetaTrades]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/categories/aud-slash-jpy/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-12-04T20:16:04-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[theta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Grandma Yellen Stepping to the Mic]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/03/15/grandma-yellen-stepping-to-the-mic/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-15T23:49:16-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/03/15/grandma-yellen-stepping-to-the-mic</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We&rsquo;re in a holding pattern, as Janet Yellen is stepping up to the mic tomorrow, so watch out for movements afterwards, and stay on the sidelines in the meantime.</p>

<p>Trade idea that triggered last night was the AUD/JPY. I&rsquo;m still waiting on UNG to go a bit higher before shorting. <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive/">Follow me on Twitter</a> to get my real-time updates on my entries and positions.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[More Trade Ideas]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/03/14/more-trade-ideas/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-14T17:49:12-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/03/14/more-trade-ideas</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday I mentioned a possible long/short trade on AUD/JPY depending on how we close today. Unfortunately for the Bull case, we weren&rsquo;t able to close above that lower price level. Still for the Bear case, I&rsquo;d like to see us breach the 85 level before initiating a short, so this is still a wait-and-see.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03142016/aud_jpy.png"><img src="/images/blog/03142016/aud_jpy.png" alt="AUD/JPY - 2016-03-14 Daily Time Frame " /></a></p>

<p>I also mentioned shorting natural gas if UNG floats up to the price level shown here:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03142016/ung.png"><img src="/images/blog/03142016/ung.png" alt="UNG - 2016-03-14 Daily Time Frame" /></a></p>

<p>We did not get that today, so this is also still a wait-and-see.</p>

<p>Looking at /GC, we&rsquo;ve stalled since ECB, and we&rsquo;re currently testing some trendline support levels:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03142016/gc_f.png"><img src="/images/blog/03142016/gc_f.png" alt="/GC - 2016-03-14 Daily Time Frame - Target 1200 Support" /></a></p>

<p>If we do break lower, I&rsquo;d imagine the next level of support is around 1200, and if so, we could easily reach that target within the next 2 weeks. One trade idea here is the 1210/1200/1185 unbalanced butterfly:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03142016/gc_f_risk_graph.png"><img src="/images/blog/03142016/gc_f_risk_graph.png" alt="/GC Risk Graph - 1210/1200/1185 Put Unbalanced Butterfly - Max Profit at 1200" /></a></p>

<p>This trade can basically be put on for free or even for a credit, but will need to be managed in case gold does plunge back down hard. I will be monitoring /GC and will be tweeting out my entry.</p>

<p>Another one is BIDU:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03142016/bidu.png"><img src="/images/blog/03142016/bidu.png" alt="BIDU - 2016-03-14 Daily Time Frame - Topping-Tail Hammer" /></a></p>

<p>Below 178.92 is a short, but I&rsquo;ll be watching FXI for follow through as well:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03142016/fxi.png"><img src="/images/blog/03142016/fxi.png" alt="FXI - 2016-03-14 Daily Time Frame - Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>If FXI stalls at that resistance, I&rsquo;ll be looking to sell some call spreads on BIDU. One trade idea is the 200/205 call spread, currently going for 1.03 cr.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today. <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive/">Follow me on Twitter</a> to get my real-time updates on my entries and positions.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Commodity and Volatility Play]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/03/13/commodity-and-volatility-play/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-13T12:18:23-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/03/13/commodity-and-volatility-play</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Natural gas has been one of the commodities that just can&rsquo;t seem to get it up. Observe the chart below:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03132016/ung.png"><img src="/images/blog/03132016/ung.png" alt="UNG - Natural Gas - 2016-03-13 Daily Time Frame - Trendline Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>A good place to short this commodity would be at the horizontal price level, so wait for a bit more of a retracement higher before entering. If we do turn lower before getting up there, then we&rsquo;ll have missed out, but our risk/reward would have been better as well.</p>

<p>My favorite currency pair to look at for market volatility opportunities is the AUD/JPY:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03132016/aud_jpy.png"><img src="/images/blog/03132016/aud_jpy.png" alt="AUD/JPY - Australian Dollar / Japanese Yen - 2016-03-13 Daily Time Frame - Trendline Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>When volatility starts picking up, look for the AUD to weaken and the JPY to strengthen. This pair should head lower if we do start to see volatility increase. If AUD/JPY starts to roll over, then the first target would be 85, then 83.3, and then 82. But if we continue to see strength in the markets, this pair can break into the region bounded by the two horizontal price levels. Look for the strength of the breakout and the tempo in the equities market as well as confirmation to enter, with a tight stop just below the lower price level - the 85.61 from the highs of Thursday&rsquo;s session would be a good place.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ll be looking to enter these trades. If you&rsquo;d like to keep up with my trades in real time, <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive/">follow me on Twitter</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
