<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: conscious business | ThetaTrades]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/categories/conscious-business/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-02-27T09:30:38-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[theta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How I Improved My Trading]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/02/15/how-i-improved-my-trading/"/>
    <updated>2017-02-15T08:55:30-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/02/15/how-i-improved-my-trading</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I first started trading, I lost a huge amount of money. During this time, I had a full time job, and I would wonder what was the point of working if I’m just going to re-invest it back into my trading account and potentially lose it all again. I felt like I was at a constant loss. I felt like a victim. For days, I beat up myself - sulked around, stopped going to the gym, underperformed at work, and just felt like settling for a lackluster life. Needless to say, this was a pretty big obstacle for me.</p>

<p>Then I came across a book called <a href="http://amzn.to/2kypWkt" title="Fred Kofman - Conscious Business">Conscious Business</a> by Fred Kofman. Fred mentions in one chapter the concept of the &ldquo;victim&rdquo; vs the &ldquo;player&rdquo;:</p>

<blockquote><blockquote><blockquote><p>“You must take unconditional responsibility; you need to see yourself as a ‘player,’ as a central character who has contributed to shape the current situation—and who can thus affect its future.<br/><br/>
This is the opposite of seeing yourself as a ‘victim,’ subject to forces beyond your control. The player is the in the game and can affect the result. The victim is out of the game and can only suffer the consequences of others’ actions."</p></blockquote></blockquote></blockquote>

<p>As cliche as it sounds, the lightbulb went off in my head. We only have one life to live, and we better take advantage of it to the utmost of our ability. This means taking action and taking responsibility for the things that we do in our life. More importantly, it means that no matter what external factors that affect us, even the things that are seemingly out of our control (ie. weather, traffic, accidents), we STILL have a choice in how we approach the way we view these circumstances. We still can choose to how we respond to it.</p>

<p>In my particular situation, I came to realize that I can choose to feel the pain, beat up myself, sulk in my losses, etc (be the victim), or I can choose to learn from this experience, work hard, dedicate time and energy to become a disciplined and consistently profitable trader, and conquer all aspects of life (be the player).</p>

<p>To this day, this passage from Fred&rsquo;s book continues to resonate with me; every day, I&rsquo;m motivated to take responsibility for everything that happens to me. And I mean literally everything. I stopped trying to apologize in ways that felt like I was not in control. I went from saying &ldquo;Sorry, I was late because there was traffic&rdquo; and replacing them with &ldquo;Sorry, I was late. I did not account for traffic. Next time, I&rsquo;ll use Waze, and if my ETA will be such that I&rsquo;ll be late to my destination, I will make sure to give you a call.&rdquo;</p>

<p>I hope that each one of you, trader or not, will take advantage of the principles that this book has to offer. It&rsquo;s truly a rare gem, and I continuously refer back to the book every now and then and apply the concepts to all aspects of my life. Don&rsquo;t forget that the most powerful investment that you can make in yourself is knowledge through education.</p>

<p>Cheers!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
