<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: volatility | theta trades]]></title>
  <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/categories/volatility/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-03-30T14:21:40-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[theta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Commodity and Volatility Play]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/13/commodity-and-volatility-play/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-13T12:18:23-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/13/commodity-and-volatility-play</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Natural gas has been one of the commodities that just can&rsquo;t seem to get it up. Observe the chart below:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03132016/ung.png"><img src="/images/blog/03132016/ung.png" alt="UNG - Natural Gas - 2016-03-13 Daily Time Frame - Trendline Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>A good place to short this commodity would be at the horizontal price level, so wait for a bit more of a retracement higher before entering. If we do turn lower before getting up there, then we&rsquo;ll have missed out, but our risk/reward would have been better as well.</p>

<p>My favorite currency pair to look at for market volatility opportunities is the AUD/JPY:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03132016/aud_jpy.png"><img src="/images/blog/03132016/aud_jpy.png" alt="AUD/JPY - Australian Dollar / Japanese Yen - 2016-03-13 Daily Time Frame - Trendline Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>When volatility starts picking up, look for the AUD to weaken and the JPY to strengthen. This pair should head lower if we do start to see volatility increase. If AUD/JPY starts to roll over, then the first target would be 85, then 83.3, and then 82. But if we continue to see strength in the markets, this pair can break into the region bounded by the two horizontal price levels. Look for the strength of the breakout and the tempo in the equities market as well as confirmation to enter, with a tight stop just below the lower price level - the 85.61 from the highs of Thursday&rsquo;s session would be a good place.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ll be looking to enter these trades. If you&rsquo;d like to keep up with my trades in real time, <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive/">follow me on Twitter</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
