<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: rut | theta trades]]></title>
  <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/categories/rut/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-03-22T22:48:11-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[theta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Decision Point]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/22/decision-point/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-22T20:38:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/22/decision-point</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Market stalls here.</p>

<p>We had the SPX close today on a Doji - this doesn&rsquo;t mean a reversal is coming, it just means indecision, or consolidation, before a break out higher or lower. The longer we consolidate, the more forceful the breakout, so do keep that in mind. Here&rsquo;s the SPX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03222016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03222016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-22 Daily Time Frame - Target 2060 - Consolidation" /></a></p>

<p>We actually peeked above the consolidation area not once, but twice, since yesterday. While that may seem bearish, keep in mind we did the same look-below-and-fail today. So still, trade is being dominated by short-term traders.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the DJX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03222016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03222016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-03-22 Daily Time Frame - Trendline Resistance Tag" /></a></p>

<p>It actually tagged that trendline resistance and fell back a bit, which was what we expected. If the markets continue to exhibit weakness tomorrow, I&rsquo;m considering the APR5 177.5/180 call spread going for .98 cr right now.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03222016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03222016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-03-22 Daily Time Frame - Grinding Higher" /></a></p>

<p>It actually continued higher today and was the strongest of the bunch. Not surprising here as it was the laggard for most of the huge rally that the SPX had.</p>

<p>And the RUT:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03222016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/03222016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-03-22 Daily Time Frame - Look Everywhere and Fail - Consolidation" /></a></p>

<p>Yesterday we were looking for either a follow through higher from possibly a bounce off of the trendline support, but we did not get that. Earlier during today&rsquo;s session, it appeared that yesterday&rsquo;s session was nothing but a look-above-and-fail, but by the end of today, we didn&rsquo;t have a look-below-and-fail, either. Again, indecision here, so keep your eyes peeled.</p>

<p>Overall, the indices spell very mixed signals. On one hand, you have the NDX up and the DJX down, but both SPX and RUT aren&rsquo;t sure where to go. The longer the market stays in a tight consolidation range, the more explosive the breakout. Stay aware.</p>

<p>Today we got filled on three trades:</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Still working the fly on it, but in the meantime: SOLD VERTICAL <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24PCLN&amp;src=ctag">$PCLN</a> 100 APR 16 1375/1380 CALL <a href="https://twitter.com/1">@1</a>.25</p>&mdash; theta (@theta_positive) <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive/status/712273450153283584">March 22, 2016</a></blockquote>


<script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>




<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">SOLD -COMBO <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24UNG&amp;src=ctag">$UNG</a> 100 (Weeklys) APR5 16 6.5/6 CALL/PUT @.13</p>&mdash; theta (@theta_positive) <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive/status/712295330461552640">March 22, 2016</a></blockquote>


<script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>




<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="ro" dir="ltr">SOLD VERTICAL <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24VXX&amp;src=ctag">$VXX</a> 100 APR 16 17.5/15 PUT @.58</p>&mdash; theta (@theta_positive) <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive/status/712352871283470336">March 22, 2016</a></blockquote>


<script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>


<p>These trades are now being logged in the <a href="/trades%20Trades">All Trades Page</a> section of the site, so we&rsquo;ll continue monitoring these trades and managing as necessary. Updates will be posted on that page over time.</p>

<p>Potential trades for tomorrow:</p>

<p>Earlier today I was looking at PCLN as a potential candidate for a balanced butterfly, centered around the 1300 level. Here&rsquo;s why:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03222016/pcln.png"><img src="/images/blog/03222016/pcln.png" alt="PCLN - 2016-03-22 Daily Time Frame - Trendline Channel Support" /></a></p>

<p>There is an ascending trendline support which should end up at around 1300 by this Thursday. In the event of a slight downdraft in the markets, we may be able to find support here. There&rsquo;s also a rising channel support going back to the gap up from earnings. This should help the 1300 level act as a support as well.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03222016/pcln_risk_graph.png"><img src="/images/blog/03222016/pcln_risk_graph.png" alt="PCLN Risk Graph - 2016-03-22 - Balanced Butterfly" /></a></p>

<p>The 1310/1300/1290 butterfly is currently being priced for about .80 db. I&rsquo;ll be trying to lowball this for about .50.</p>

<p>And for DIA:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03222016/dia.png"><img src="/images/blog/03222016/dia.png" alt="DIA - 2016-03-22 Daily Time Frame - Short &amp; Long Strikes" /></a></p>

<p>In the market recap before, I mentioned that if the market exhibits weakness and we see all indices drop, a 177.5/180 call vertical on DIA would not be a bad idea.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03222016/dia_risk_graph.png"><img src="/images/blog/03222016/dia_risk_graph.png" alt="DIA Risk Graoh - 2016-03-22 - Vertical Credit Call Spread" /></a></p>

<p>It&rsquo;s currently being priced at about 1.01 cr for the spread expiring on APR5, but depending on when the fill happens and how much the market drops, it&rsquo;ll be lower.</p>

<p>Another trade idea here is GDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03222016/gdx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03222016/gdx.png" alt="GDX - 2016-03-22 Daily Time Frame - Channel Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m looking for a bit of a pullback from this big run that we&rsquo;ve had. As GDX stalls here, I&rsquo;m hoping to collect some premium on the call side, possibly the APR 21.5 naked call, and I&rsquo;m also looking to add a more bearish bias, as we&rsquo;re at the top of this channel resistance. To that effect, I&rsquo;m considering buying the 20/19 put spread, also in APR. Together, this should bring in about .22 cr.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03222016/gdx_risk_graph.png"><img src="/images/blog/03222016/gdx_risk_graph.png" alt="GDX Risk Graph - 2016-03-22 Daily Time Frame - Look Everywhere and Fail - Consolidation" /></a></p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today. I&rsquo;ll be posting my trades <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="live on Twitter">Follow @thetatrades on Twitter </a>, so follow me to get those real-time notifications.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Expecting a Turnaround Very Soon]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/21/expecting-a-turnaround-very-soon/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-21T19:05:51-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/21/expecting-a-turnaround-very-soon</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We continue to grind higher.</p>

<p>SPX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03212016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03212016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-21 Daily Time Frame - Target 2060 - Gap Fill" /></a></p>

<p>The 2060 target mentioned for a while now is just within reach. Due to the slowing momentum, I&rsquo;m looking to enter into a 2100/2110 short call vertical spread on the SPX, currently going for 1.70 cr once that trendline is reached and we exhibit signs of a turnaround.</p>

<p>DJX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03212016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03212016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-03-21 Daily Time Frame - Trendline Resistance Tag" /></a></p>

<p>We tagged the trendline resistance today. I am expecting this to stall around here, while the SPX climbs higher to tag its trendline.</p>

<p>NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03212016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03212016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-03-21 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement" /></a></p>

<p>We crossed the 61.8% fib level today, so the next level of resistance is the trendline resistance. However, given the slowing momentum we have in all of the other indices, I don&rsquo;t expect NDX to actually reach that trendline resistance on this run.</p>

<p>RUT:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03212016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/03212016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-03-21 Daily Time Frame - Trendline Support" /></a></p>

<p>The RUT was the weakest of the bunch today, closing down, but still above the trendline support. We&rsquo;ll need to see more follow-through to the upside if the market were truly bullish, but that may be a bit hard given how much we&rsquo;ve come off from the lows, and also the fact that there is a 61.8% fib level there as well. I do expect some stalling to occur here, but keep an eye out on this, as we could easily fall below that support, making for a classic look-above-and-fail pattern.</p>

<p>The upcoming week is key and will most likely determine whether or not we get the retracement in the market that many, including me, have been looking for. Keep your eyes peeled.</p>

<p>In the meantime, for those that followed me on Twitter, here is the trade we got filled on today:</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">It&#39;s breaking support. BOT BUTTERFLY <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24AMZN&amp;src=ctag">$AMZN</a> 100 APR 16 480/475/465 PUT @-.17</p>&mdash; theta (@theta_positive) <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive/status/711923212490121216">March 21, 2016</a></blockquote>


<script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>


<p>And the risk profile per spread:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03212016/amzn_risk_profile.png"><img src="/images/blog/03212016/amzn_risk_profile.png" alt="AMZN - 2016-03-21 Daily Time Frame - Unbalanced Butterfly Risk Profile" /></a></p>

<p>Looking at the chart of AMZN on the daily:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03212016/amzn.png"><img src="/images/blog/03212016/amzn.png" alt="AMZN - 2016-03-21 Daily Time Frame - Approximate Support" /></a></p>

<p>I expect us to find some support around the prior lows in the area of about 475 to 500. Because I didn&rsquo;t have a specific target in mind, only an approximate area, plus the fact that I think we&rsquo;ll stall around there, a theta-positive, risk-defined trade here may not be such a bad idea. If we aren&rsquo;t able to clearly break support (which we couldn&rsquo;t by the end of today, we actually had a look-below-and-fail) and we end up moving higher, we still make money. As for trade management, since we don&rsquo;t want to take on the max loss here, we&rsquo;ll be looking to manage if AMZN does indeed fall down hard.</p>

<p>Also, given how UNG closed today, I think we are in for another leg lower, and the measured target would be 5.61:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03212016/ung.png"><img src="/images/blog/03212016/ung.png" alt="UNG - 2016-03-21 Daily Time Frame - Trendline Resistance, Fibonacci Extension" /></a></p>

<p>I would like to see us break the lows of 5.78 first, though. As for the entry point, looking at the chart on an intraday basis, a break below 6.4 should trigger us into the short:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03212016/ung_short_entry.png"><img src="/images/blog/03212016/ung_short_entry.png" alt="UNG - 2016-03-21 Hourly Time Frame - Short Entry Point" /></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m looking to sell the APR5 6.5 call and buy the APR5 6 put for about .17 cr. Look out for my tweet on this.</p>

<p>Last, but not least, HD:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03212016/hd.png"><img src="/images/blog/03212016/hd.png" alt="HD - 2016-03-21 Daily Time Frame - Channel Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>I completely got sidetracked by work while an entry was available here today - unfortunately it seems like we&rsquo;re no longer able to get a credit for putting on the 133/135 call backratio right now (currently going for .09 debit). I&rsquo;ll continue monitoring this for a good entry, and I&rsquo;ll post it live on Twitter as well.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets tomorrow, and <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive/">follow me on Twitter</a> to get my updates in real-time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Market Continues to Upside]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/16/market-continues-to-upside/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-16T19:27:04-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/16/market-continues-to-upside</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yellen did it again, and the markets rally higher. Let&rsquo;s take a look:</p>

<p>As mentioned for a while now, SPX is still on track to tag the 2060 level:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03162016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03162016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-16 Daily Time Frame - Target 2060 - Harmonic Pattern" /></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve outlined the range of last year&rsquo;s October rally and duplicated that line over to the rally we&rsquo;ve had from February to estimate the target of this rally (AKA Harmonic Pattern), and it matches perfectly with the descending trendline resistance. Given this projection, we should reach that target zone in about two weeks.</p>

<p>Keep in mind that SPX opened this year at 2038.2. Look for some resistance over there as well. A failure to take this market back up through the open (just like in day-trading when we fail to take out the open) is a short signal. But if we plow through this and move higher with ease, expect 2060.</p>

<p>Taking a look at the DJX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03162016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03162016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-03-16 Daily Time Frame - Descending Trendline Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>Pretty bullish here. It just broke the descending trendline resistance, which makes a big dent in the bear case. The next target is that next trendline resistance.</p>

<p>Moving over to the NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03162016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03162016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-03-16 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci" /></a></p>

<p>This tagged the 61.8% fib today and backed off, but given how all the other indices look, this would have no problem busting through it that, which makes the next target the descending trendline resistance.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the RUT:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03162016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/03162016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-03-16 Daily Time Frame - Bull Flag" /></a></p>

<p>Though it&rsquo;s weak, we could be setting up for a bull flag breakout.</p>

<p>Watch all of the indices closely. The best trade idea for SPX is setting up a butterfly with the short strikes centered at 2060, expiring on Mar5.</p>

<p>That wraps it up for today. Trade safe, and trade small. Good luck in the markets!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Short-Term Traders Continue to Dominate]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/14/short-term-traders-continue-to-dominate/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-14T17:09:23-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/14/short-term-traders-continue-to-dominate</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ll give a short market update on the broad market indices and then save a post later for possible trade ideas.</p>

<p>Today&rsquo;s price action continues to show some short-term traders here dominating. On the /ES, we tagged the single prints separating the two distributions on Friday, and then instead of pushing prices lower, we backed off and traded back upwards. This shows that shorter term traders are just trading responsively, and it also shows that they&rsquo;re just lacking confidence to push this higher or lower. Furthermore, we closed on a Doji today, so another reason we&rsquo;ve got a low confidence market.</p>

<p>SPX is still on track to tag the 2060 level, though to me, the market feels really heavy, and we might not get there. Watch for a possible reversal or breakout tomorrow, as we basically spent the whole day today balancing thus forming that Doji:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03142016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03142016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-14 Daily Time Frame - Target 2060 - Doji" /></a></p>

<p>NDX crept higher today, and will probably slowly float upwards to the 61.8% fib level:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03142016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03142016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-03-14 Daily Time Frame - Target 61.8% Fibonacci ~ 4415" /></a></p>

<p>DJX also looks like it wants to tag that trendline resistance:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03142016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03142016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-03-14 Daily Time Frame - Target Trendline Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>RUT here kind of stalling. Continue to monitor that trendline to see if we break it to the upside or fail back down:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03142016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/03142016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-03-14 Daily Time Frame - Trendline Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>Continue to monitor the markets closely. Again, I feel like traders are just tired of pushing prices higher, but we also have Janet stepping up to the mic on Wednesday, so be careful and trade cautiously.</p>

<p>Stay tuned for trade ideas coming up, and <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive/">follow me on Twitter</a> to get notified real-time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Further Upside Expected]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/11/further-upside-expected/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-11T18:45:36-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/11/further-upside-expected</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m expecting further upside in the market.</p>

<p>Yesterday after the ECB announcement, traders attempted to push the market lower but were unable to do so. We looked below balance, failed, made a poor low, and then came back into balance. Then this morning, we gapped up, but with the internals so strong, no chance of a gap fade play was available, and we continued to ratchet higher.</p>

<p>This is a very bullish signal, regardless of how overbought the conditions are. Here&rsquo;s the current SPX chart:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03112016/spx_daily.png"><img src="/images/blog/03112016/spx_daily.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-11 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement, Trendline Resistance, Range Extension" /></a></p>

<p>For those that took a bullish stance on the market during that time, congratulations. In the first SPX chart that I posted a couple of weeks back, I outlined the potential range extension we could see as possible target areas (via the pink rectangles). This week, not only did we break the 61.8% fib level, but we&rsquo;ve also broken the trendline resistance connected by the tops of November and December 2015. I believe we&rsquo;re headed to 2060. So if you&rsquo;re long, continue to hold that position.</p>

<p>Zooming out and taking a look at the market on the weekly:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03112016/spx_weekly.png"><img src="/images/blog/03112016/spx_weekly.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-11 Weekly Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement, Trendline Resistance, Range Extension, Bottoming-Tail Hammer" /></a></p>

<p>Notice the bottoming tail hammer that formed. I count many weekly bars from before that ended with a higher close the following week.</p>

<p>The same bullishness can be seen in the Dow:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03112016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03112016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-03-11 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement, Trendline Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>We&rsquo;re approaching the trendline resistance here as well. Look for a short there. As a side note, DJX has also put in a bottoming-tail hammer on the weekly chart.</p>

<p>For the NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03112016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03112016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-03-11 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement" /></a></p>

<p>A little bit weaker here, as we have not tagged the 61.8% fib level, yet. Still, this has also put in a bottoming-tail hammer on the weekly chart.</p>

<p>Finally the RUT:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03112016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/03112016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-03-11 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement, Trendline Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>Though it exhibited a lot of weakness a couple of days ago, keep in mind it has come off really high from the lows. It looks like it&rsquo;ll break that trendline resistance, and if it does, that&rsquo;ll suggest more short-covering to come.</p>

<p>That about wraps it up for the week going on to next week. I&rsquo;d just like to finish with another note:</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m not bullish on the market - I think the fundamentals are complete garbage, and I think we&rsquo;ll see a crash like we&rsquo;ve never seen before. However, I can&rsquo;t let my biases blind me from seeing the opportunities out there. Instead of falling prey to cognitive dissonance, we can separate our bias and take advantage of these opportunities as they come.</p>

<p>Enjoy the weekend, and good luck to everyone, bull or bear.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
