<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: reflection | theta trades]]></title>
  <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/categories/reflection/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-03-15T23:53:41-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[theta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thoughts on the Market]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/12/thoughts-on-the-market/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-12T12:14:17-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/12/thoughts-on-the-market</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ll admit, I have not participated as much as I should have in the rally from the February lows.</p>

<p>In hindsight, that is the biggest mistake I&rsquo;ve made this year. It was clearly a double bottom, and when fueled by short-covering, became a very powerful rally. All I had to do was go long the market, or any stock for that matter, and I would&rsquo;ve been able to capture a lot more gains. Instead, I focused on the points that the market could possibly stall and turn around to go lower, and I was prepared to short at those points. And because I was so focused on preparing to short, I did not think about going long.</p>

<p>Obviously, that type of thinking has caused me a lot of lost opportunities. So, in order to correct this behavior, and to help set it in stone, I think it&rsquo;s beneficial for me to write out these thoughts so that I can come back here whenever similar situations occur in the future and set myself straight.</p>

<p>As much as I&rsquo;m punishing myself for missing out on the rally, my sentiment on the market still remains - I don&rsquo;t believe in the rally that we&rsquo;ve had from the February lows. That does not mean I won&rsquo;t be taking advantage of any bullish signals and trading them. It simply means, fundamentally, I don&rsquo;t believe our economy is any better. I believe our central bankers will run out of juice one day. At some point, the market has to correct, and I just don&rsquo;t see us making new highs in our current conditions.</p>

<p>Take a look at some of the famous, big-name stocks like FB, AMZN, NFLX, GOOG, CMG, AAPL, etc. I would&rsquo;ve expected these stocks to rally a lot higher in conjunction with the SPX - at least if it had done so, it would&rsquo;ve shown that risk was back on. Instead, they all look very weak; it doesn&rsquo;t seem like investors are all that excited about these stocks anymore. Furthermore, it appears we&rsquo;ve rotated to defensive sector stocks like energy, and based off of what? Crude oil&rsquo;s fundamentals being better? I don&rsquo;t think so. In fact, I have no idea.</p>

<p>We started this year at 2038.2 in the SPX. We&rsquo;re currently at 2022.19. If we breach 2038.2 with vigor, I believe the next point of resistance is 2060 (highlighted by the gray oval):</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03122016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03122016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-12 Daily Time Frame - Target 2060" /></a></p>

<p>Because a lot of overhead supply is above us, I think it makes sense that we won&rsquo;t be surging sharply higher - instead, we&rsquo;ll probably slowly float upwards. So I&rsquo;ll leave you with a trade idea: the 2055/2060/2070 unbalanced butterfly (currently priced for 0.15 cr) expiring March:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03122016/spx_risk_graph.png"><img src="/images/blog/03122016/spx_risk_graph.png" alt="SPX Unbalanced Butterly - Risk Graph" /></a></p>

<p>The max loss here is the 5.00 - .15, or $485 per spread.</p>

<p>This will need to be price-discovered again on Monday. If the credit is still good, and if the SPX looks like it&rsquo;s going to be slowly grinding higher, I would put this trade on.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for now. Enjoy the weekend everyone.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
