<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[ThetaTrades]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/"/>
  <updated>2018-03-13T21:28:41-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[theta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A China Play]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2018/03/13/a-china-play/"/>
    <updated>2018-03-13T21:17:45-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2018/03/13/a-china-play</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Various Chinese stocks have been roaring higher over the past two years. One of these super stocks is $YY. Please observe the following chart:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.thetatrades.com/images/blog/20180313/yy.png"><img src="http://www.thetatrades.com/images/blog/20180313/yy.png" alt="$YY - 2018-03-13 - Daily" /></a></p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the daily chart of $YY. We have a nice pullback to the 100MA, offering a great trade location to get long with a stop just below the 100MA. Stop loss will be placed 2 ATRs below the 100MA, at $98.72. As long as price stays above the 100MA, we will continue to be long this stock.</p>

<p>Remember to position size properly, keeping in mind that prices can always gap below your stop loss.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Upcoming Trades This Week]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/03/05/upcoming-trades-this-week/"/>
    <updated>2017-03-05T11:16:28-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/03/05/upcoming-trades-this-week</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There&rsquo;s no doubt that the overall trend of the equities market is up. As such, many stocks are simply following the trend, and so should we. We&rsquo;ve been looking at a few charts over the weekend; here are some that stood out as good tickers to get long:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.thetatrades.com/images/blog/20170305/khc.png"><img src="http://www.thetatrades.com/images/blog/20170305/khc.png" alt="$KHC - 2017-03-05 - Daily" /></a>
Here&rsquo;s $KHC. We have a nice pullback to the 20MA, offering great trade location. Stop loss can be placed around 87.52, at which point, we&rsquo;ll wait on the sidelines and look to get long again at the 200MA.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.thetatrades.com/images/blog/20170305/ko.png"><img src="http://www.thetatrades.com/images/blog/20170305/ko.png" alt="$KO - 2017-03-05 - Daily" /></a>
Here&rsquo;s $KO. We&rsquo;ve broken above the 200MA and closed above it. We can look to get long with a stop at 41.51.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.thetatrades.com/images/blog/20170305/so.png"><img src="http://www.thetatrades.com/images/blog/20170305/so.png" alt="$SO - 2017-03-05 - Daily" /></a>
Here&rsquo;s $SO. We&rsquo;ve held above the 200MA. We can look to get long with a stop at 48.04.</p>

<p>As always, think about the risk first, and size up your position according to how much you are comfortable with losing if your stop were to get hit. Once set, enjoy the ride with the trend.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re interested in more ideas like this, <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow us on Twitter</a> or <a href="https://facebook.com/thetatrades" title="Follow @thetatrades on Facebook">Facebook</a> to receive our tweets and posts in real time! And if you haven&rsquo;t yet, subscribe to our email listing below to receive special email alerts as well.</p>

<div class="subscribe-button">
    <button>Subscribe to Our Updates</button>
</div>




<!-- <script src="//z-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/onejs?MarketPlace=US&adInstanceId=3c36f001-e4b7-4c98-bffa-716b4f4878ab"></script>
 -->

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[$CLF - Long Opportunity]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/03/03/clf-long-opportunity/"/>
    <updated>2017-03-03T12:07:18-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/03/03/clf-long-opportunity</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone!</p>

<p>We have another candidate that presents a long opportunity at a pullback to the 50 day MA - $CLF. Please observe the chart below:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.thetatrades.com/images/blog/20170303/clf.png"><img src="http://www.thetatrades.com/images/blog/20170303/clf.png" alt="$CLF - 2017-03-03 - Daily" /></a></p>

<p>With a pullback to the 50MA, $CLF provides a good long entry as is. Stop will be placed at 8.49, at which point, we can step back and observe how it trades near the 200MA. As always, size your position according to your personal risk tolerance!</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re interested in more ideas like this, <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow us on Twitter</a> or <a href="https://facebook.com/thetatrades" title="Follow @thetatrades on Facebook">Facebook</a> to receive our tweets and posts in real time! And if you haven&rsquo;t yet, subscribe to our email listing below to receive special email alerts as well.</p>

<div class="subscribe-button">
    <button>Subscribe to Our Updates</button>
</div>




<!-- <script src="//z-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/onejs?MarketPlace=US&adInstanceId=3c36f001-e4b7-4c98-bffa-716b4f4878ab"></script>
 -->

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oh $SNAP - We're Not Trading It]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/03/02/oh-snap-were-not-trading-it/"/>
    <updated>2017-03-02T09:17:58-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/03/02/oh-snap-were-not-trading-it</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey traders,</p>

<p>You probably know that $SNAP went public less than a couple of hours ago. One question you might be thinking:</p>

<p><em>Should we trade it?</em></p>

<p>This all depends on your own system. However, here at ThetaTrades, we&rsquo;re trend traders, and we look at the 20, 50, and 200 day moving averages. Since it&rsquo;s $SNAP&rsquo;s first day, we don&rsquo;t have the data necessary for our trend following system. Therefore, we will not be trading $SNAP. Simple as that!</p>

<p>If you do trade it, may we wish you the best. Cheers!</p>

<div class="subscribe-button">
    <button>Subscribe to Our Updates</button>
</div>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Look at Energy]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/03/02/a-look-at-energy/"/>
    <updated>2017-03-02T09:01:45-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/03/02/a-look-at-energy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey traders,</p>

<p>The energy sector has gotten a lot of questions recently - here&rsquo;s our take on how to trade it. Please observe the chart below:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.thetatrades.com/images/blog/20170302/xle.png"><img src="http://www.thetatrades.com/images/blog/20170302/xle.png" alt="$XLE - 2017-03-02 - Daily" /></a></p>

<p>For the longest time, the 200MA has held incredibly well. As it&rsquo;s trading around that curve again, $XLE presents a good location to get long. One can initiate a long position at current prices, with a stop around 68.99. Since we&rsquo;re trend followers, we&rsquo;ll continue holding this position for as long as we can, while trailing our stops up as the 200MA curve moves in our favor. As always, our goal is to ride the trend as long as possible, and rely on the rules of the system to get us out.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re interested in more ideas like this, <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow us on Twitter</a> or <a href="https://facebook.com/thetatrades" title="Follow @thetatrades on Facebook">Facebook</a> to receive our tweets and posts in real time! And if you haven&rsquo;t yet, subscribe to our email listing below to receive special email alerts as well.</p>

<div class="subscribe-button">
    <button>Subscribe to Our Updates</button>
</div>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Trade Stocks Like a Pro]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/03/01/how-to-trade-stocks-like-a-pro/"/>
    <updated>2017-03-01T16:35:55-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/03/01/how-to-trade-stocks-like-a-pro</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>(written by M, a member of ThetaTrades)</em></p>

<p>Do you ever feel like your trading is just a grind? Over the months and years, you only produced slow, weak, and inconsistent results. Do you wonder how the hell professionals continue to consistently extract money out of the markets over the long run, and how they’re able to trade without letting their emotions affect their judgment? Well, look no further - <strong>you’re about to find out the answer to these trading questions in this post.</strong></p>

<p>First, I’ll start by mentioning that <strong>the information you&rsquo;re about to be presented with does not reveal the holy grail strategy or the holy grail indicator</strong>. Sorry, but if you’re looking for tips on how to get rich quickly from Head and Shoulder patterns, flags, cups &amp; handles, Fibobullshit retracements, or Ichimoku patterns, please close this window, proceed to follow 99% of the #Furus (fake gurus) out there, and pay monthly fees to subscribe to their predictive voodoo analysis.</p>

<p>Instead, what I’m about to tell you has been what 99% of the traders tend to ignore - that is: <strong>trading psychology.</strong></p>

<p><strong>Average traders have a hard time becoming consistently profitable, and ultimately professional because they employ too much discretionary trading.</strong> What is discretion trading?</p>

<p>You’re probably doing it without even realizing that what you’re doing is discretionary trading. To understand discretionary trading, we must first understand systematic trading, as discretionary trading is the opposite of systematic trading. In systematic trading, you have a strict set of rules that just don’t bend, no matter who, what, when, where and why. You have a system that you’ve backtested properly, and you let this system make all the decisions for you, while you sit back and relax (figuratively, if you don’t have an algorithm doing it for you).</p>

<p>However, in discretionary trading, you trade based off of biases and emotions that randomly form here and there — essentially, you’re not following a set of rules, not because you don’t have any rules set (you might), but simply because you either don’t have the discipline to follow it, or you believe that certain noise around you matters. You think things like:</p>

<ul>
<li>Is the Fed going to have an announcement? Yellen could screw with the interest rates, but then again, the market might not care&hellip;</li>
<li>Have I made enough money on this trade that I should take off some to lock in profits because I’m scared of losing my gains?</li>
<li>Wait, I think that’s a head and shoulders forming? I should get out of my long position, even though it wasn’t part of the original plan.</li>
<li>Is Dennis Gartman bullish on crude in Yen terms, because if so, I should buy some protection on the downside.</li>
<li><em>[Insert generic #Furu trader]</em> suggested <em>[insert any stock]</em> is way too overbought and overvalued, so I’m going to go balls-deep short on this stock.</li>
</ul>


<p>Although you might take a trade based off of some initial rules, throughout the trade, you bend these rules based on the subsequent emotions that come up. However, these emotions ultimately affect the way you can be consistently profitable, because there are infinite variations to your emotions at any time in the market, and if you let these multitudes of variables affect your trade throughout its duration, the only consistency you’ll be guaranteed is inconsistency.</p>

<p>So how can we guarantee more consistency? How can we eliminate the emotions from affecting our trade? We need to start from a fresh slate. Here are the top tips to help you become consistently profitable in trading.</p>

<ol>
<li><p><strong>Simplify<br/></strong>
Seriously, KISS. How many times do you see someone stare at charts that look like seismographs, with Fibobullshit retracements, Brochastics, and Ichimokus, looking for those Cloud 9 setups? And then when the patterns play out in hindsight, they boast about it and say those things matter? That is similar to some fundamentalist telling you that $NFLX is overvalued and on any selloff, they boast about how those things matter. Look, at the end of the day, the only thing that matters is price, because that makes you money. Price is the ultimate source, so just go directly to the source. Ignore everything else - all the noise, all the lines. They’re just confusing you and causing analysis paralysis. If you dumbed down your system to something really simple, you lessen the variables that’ll affect your trade, and you increase the chances that you’ll actually follow every step of your system. You’ll end up going from <em>“If the RSI says oversold, and, if the Ichimoku clouds line up or we’re at a 38%/50%/68% Fib retracement, then I’ll go short”</em> to <em>“If the slope of the 200MA is down, then I’ll go short.”</em> Do you see how much more simple that becomes?</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Understand Expected Value<br/></strong>
You won’t believe how many people out there still think that the way to make money is through “high probability trades.” High probability trades don’t mean jack squat. Unfortunately, popular services like tastytrade promote this concept all the time. Why doesn’t high probability work? Well, you can have high probability with low profit trades, and low probability with high loss trades.<br/><br/>
Think about it - let’s say your win rate is 90%. Every time you win, say you make an average of about $50. Your loss rate is 10%. Every time you lose, you hold and pray that it will eventually come back in your favor, but it doesn’t, so say on average for losers, you lose $500.<br/></br>
This brings us to the concept of expected value (for the mathematical: <a href="http://www.mathwords.com/e/expected_value.htm">http://www.mathwords.com/e/expected_value.htm</a>). When you backtest your system, make sure you consider Expected Value rather than just Probability. So if you find a system with 20% chance of success (80% chance of failure), but every chance of success makes > 4R while every loss is 1R, then you’ve got yourself a system that wins in the long run.<br/><br/>
In his book <a href="http://amzn.to/2luN8En">Trade Your Way to Financial Freedom</a>, Van Tharp mentions the important points to keep in mind when backtesting - we highly recommend the book beyond just the aspect of backtesting, as he also goes into detail about it from the perspective of trend trading.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Trust your edge, follow your system<br/></strong>
This means respecting your system. Staying emotionless. Follow your plan. If your system tells you to cut your losers, then cut them. If your system tells you to adjust your stop, then adjust it. If your system tells you to add to your position, then add to it. If your system tells you to enter, you enter. But if the system isn’t telling you anything, don’t do anything! Don’t be enticed by every little tick the market makes and think that you have to place a trade or muck with your position - remember that the less you trade, the better. Your account is like a bar of soap - the more you touch it, the less you have of it. And you wouldn’t need to trade more than you needed to if you just followed your system.<br/></br>
Every time you don’t follow the system, punish yourself. Every time you do follow the system, reward yourself. You absolutely need to do this. We’re creatures of habit. We like rewards. We hate punishment. When you punish yourself, actually punish yourself. If you’re lazy, run a mile. If you hate your mother, pick up the phone, call her and talk to her for an hour.<br/><br/>
What you should <strong>not</strong> do is reward yourself based on your P/L. You’re trying to promote good habits, which in turn bring the results your system determines it brings in the long run. So focus on the process, and reward yourself every time you are aligned with your process.<br/><br/>
One big way to keep emotions at bay is to size your positions in such a way that if you were to lose R, you wouldn&rsquo;t be tripping out about the loss (even if the trade were to eventually go your way and then some)</p></li>
<li><p><strong>No ego<br/></strong>
Don’t bother going on social media, StockTwits, telling people that your call was right and theirs was wrong. Just stop - you’re not here to prove that your dick is bigger than someone else’s. This isn’t some measuring contest, so you have to get rid of that penis envy mentality. Instead, focus on yourself and your journey, and do not compare yourself with others. When trades don’t work out, admit that you’re wrong and stop holding on to the loser (though if you had done your homework and followed your system, this wouldn’t be a problem). <strong>You have to get rid of that “need-to-be-right” bias.</strong></p></li>
</ol>


<p>As you start to work on all of these areas, you’ll find that you’ll begin to care less and less about trading. In fact, trading will probably start to become boring. You don’t care what anyone else thinks or says. Trading becomes as simple as black and white. Enter, or hold, or exit. No more Fed drama, no more FOMO, no more penis envy. You completely scroll past the permabull fanboys, the bearmongers, the noise, all of it, on Twitter, Facebook, or whatever financial media you’re on. You’ll find that you’ll start unfollowing people because what you’ve subscribed to or what they tweet about has no relevance to your system and is only there to create noise. At that point, you’ve reached the level of a professional trader.</p>

<p>So if you&rsquo;re a struggling trader looking to be become a pro, we hope that this short segment helps you out. If you have any questions, leave a comment below, and our team will get back to you as soon as we can.</p>

<p>May we wish you all success in your trading journeys!</p>

<div class="subscribe-button">
    <button>Subscribe to Our Updates</button>
</div>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Markets Rip Higher (We Don't Care)]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/03/01/markets-rip-higher-we-dont-care/"/>
    <updated>2017-03-01T09:03:51-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/03/01/markets-rip-higher-we-dont-care</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey traders!</p>

<p>As the markets rip higher today, many look towards the news for answers. Thankfully, <a href="http://www.cnbc.com/2017/03/01/us-markets.html">they found one</a>.</p>

<p><strong>But just how actionable was this piece of news for trend traders?</strong> Or any trader? Meaning, if you had known this information before the speech actually came out, could you have predicted that the market would hit all time highs? And if the market tanked, would you have been able to predict that as well?</p>

<p>Sure, fundamentals may matter, but <strong>unfortunately, they only matter after-the-fact</strong>. The truth is, even if you did know that Trump’s speech would have implied positive news for the economy, the market itself may not take it as positive news (think about companies that come out with great earnings, and great outlook, but still miss the unpredictable expectations of the market). And because the job of the media is to explain market moves, they always do so in hindsight.</p>

<p>It’s time to cut out all the fundamentals, because all they do is create noise, just like the media or FinTwit. <strong>As traders, it’s not our job to predict. It’s our job to simply trade the price</strong>, determined by what the moving averages tell us about prices in the recent past. From that, we’re able to determine the trend and follow it, with proper risk management via position sizing. This is what the trading business is all about.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/02/28/fundamentals-should-they-matter/">If you haven’t read about why we don’t worry about fundamentals, please visit our blog post here</a>.</p>

<p>Until then, trade with the trend, and enjoy the ride.</p>

<p>Cheers!</p>

<div class="subscribe-button">
    <button>Subscribe to Our Updates</button>
</div>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Long DISCA]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/02/28/long-disca/"/>
    <updated>2017-02-28T17:57:54-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/02/28/long-disca</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey traders!</p>

<p><a href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/02/27/long-tdc/">Similar to our long idea on $TDC</a>, $DISCA also provides the a great setup for us. Please observe the chart below:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.thetatrades.com/images/blog/20170228/disca.png"><img src="http://www.thetatrades.com/images/blog/20170228/disca.png" alt="$DISCA - 2017-02-28 - Daily" /></a></p>

<p>With a pullback to the 20MA, $DISCA offers a good location to get long. Our stop would be around 26.07. As $DISCA moves up, we&rsquo;ll also trail our stop below the 200MA.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re interested in more ideas like this, <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow us on Twitter</a> or <a href="https://facebook.com/thetatrades" title="Follow @thetatrades on Facebook">Facebook</a> to receive our tweets and posts in real time! And if you haven&rsquo;t yet, subscribe to our email listing below to receive special email alerts as well.</p>

<div class="subscribe-button">
    <button>Subscribe to Our Updates</button>
</div>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fundamentals - Should They Matter]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/02/28/fundamentals-should-they-matter/"/>
    <updated>2017-02-28T07:47:29-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/02/28/fundamentals-should-they-matter</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When people want to start investing in stocks, usually, they are told to look into the fundamentals of the company.</p>

<p>However, before they start doing that, the most important thing that they should do is ask themselves is why they want to invest in stocks. Do they want to invest because they want to make money?</p>

<p>Sounds like a pretty silly question, we know. Obviously (or hopefully), the answer is yes.</p>

<p>It’s important for everyone to take a moment to clarify this simple question with themselves, because many go into the stock market telling themselves that they want to make money, but when the tide starts to turn and the stocks that they own start selling off, they’re unable to let go of their original bias. They begin to come up with reasons why they should continue holding:</p>

<blockquote><p>There&rsquo;s no way this stock can go to 0. With such positive news coming out on the company these days, it has got to start going up.</p>

<p>The CEO is a amazing person - he/she will turn things around, I know it, and I believe in him/her.</p>

<p>I believe in their product. Last year they increased sales, and they&rsquo;ll do it again this year. I believe the company will continue to innovate and produce results. The market is just panicking right now for no reason.</p></blockquote>

<p>At this point, are these traders still investing because they want to make money? Or are they investing simply because they want to be right?</p>

<p>Though they might not be aware of this bias when they first start out, they eventually are guilty of committing this major investing flaw.</p>

<p>Assuming people want to invest in the stock market because they want to make money, if they want to be successful in this endeavor, it’s important to understand that the only thing that matters is <strong>price</strong>. Very often, the fundamentals of a company cannot easily be predicted. And even if you could predict it, it&rsquo;s more than likely a guess, and the market probably would have already priced in the outlook, so by the time that people actually want to trade that knowledge, it is already too late and not actionable.</p>

<p>Using the fundamentals of a company to buy or sell a stock is very dangerous, because it creates a bias which may cause traders to hold on to losers longer than they probably should. In the end, people invest in stocks in order to make money. If a company were to go bankrupt, it makes sense that they won’t continue to hold the stock and watch the net liquidity in their stock position go to 0.</p>

<p>However, you would be surprised to find that many continue to hold on to their losers, because they don’t want to be wrong. It’s human nature to feed our egos; we all have a “need to be right” mentality somewhere deep inside us, so we start looking at fundamentals to find reasons why we’re still holding on to a losing stock. We look for news that substantiates our bias, and ignore those that don&rsquo;t support our position.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, even when the company is cashflow positive, P/E ratios are reasonable, and dividends are high, a stock can still continue to sell off, and novice traders are left holding the bag for the next X years, praying that all else goes well and that they get their money back.</p>

<p>With all due respect to many of fundamentalists out there, we believe that looking towards fundamentals ultimately ends up creating unnecessary noise for traders, causing them to use the news as excuses to explain why they either buy, hold, or sell a stock.</p>

<p>It doesn&rsquo;t need to be that complicated. Just tune out the noise, ignore the fundamentals, and focus on price.</p>

<p>What is the price telling you? Is the stock trending up? Down? Sideways? If so, trade in the direction of the trend. It&rsquo;s that simple! Looking at price and trading with the trend, with proper risk management through position sizing (an arena often glossed over by many beginning investors), is what ultimately yields big profits in the long run.</p>

<p><em>Stay tuned for our next post, where we discuss in detail how to look at price to determine the trend and trade with it.</em></p>

<p><em>If you haven&rsquo;t yet, subscribe to our email list below to receive notifications on new posts and special offers.</em></p>

<div class="subscribe-button">
    <button>Subscribe to Our Updates</button>
</div>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Type of Trader Should I Be?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/02/27/what-type-of-trader-should-i-be/"/>
    <updated>2017-02-27T21:36:15-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/02/27/what-type-of-trader-should-i-be</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Have you ever asked yourself the question - what type of trader should I be?</p>

<p>If you’re just starting to trade, you’ve probably heard of many different styles of trading. Some may even sound scary, but don&rsquo;t worry! We’ll go over them in a little bit of detail here, and with a bit of self-assessment, you&rsquo;ll be able to figure out what trading style best suits you. Here is a table of the main different styles of trading, with their time frames listed:</p>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th> Trading Style    </th>
<th> Time Frame </th>
<th> Holding Period                              </th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td> Day Trading      </td>
<td> Short term </td>
<td> Seconds to minutes - no overnight positions </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td> Swing Trading    </td>
<td> Short term </td>
<td> Days to weeks                               </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td> Position Trading </td>
<td> Long Term  </td>
<td> Months to years                             </td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


<p>Let’s go over these styles one by one. As you read, please refer to this table above.</p>

<h3>Day Trading</h3>

<p>This is the typical picture that pops up in your head when you think about day trading - a trader sitting behind 8 different monitors, usually constantly monitoring the charts throughout the day. Day traders typically execute anywhere from 1 trade a day to 50+ trades a day. They do not hold any positions overnight, meaning they balance their account and close any open positions before the market closes at the end of the day. Day trading requires an intense amount of focus. If trading is indeed your one and only job, this can be an area for you to explore.</p>

<h3>Swing Trading</h3>

<p>In swing trading, traders typically capture market moves from days to weeks. This type of trading does not necessarily require constant monitoring because traders are more focused on where prices open at the beginning of the day and where they close at the end of the day, not anytime in between. Because trades last over the course of at least multiple days, swing traders hold positions overnight. Generally speaking, swing trading captures larger directional moves than those of day trading, but less than those of position trading.</p>

<h3>Position Trading</h3>

<p>This is essentially the Warren Buffet types of investing. Investors looking for long term buy and hold or long term shorts are position traders. They generally look at their accounts even less than swing traders, typically once or twice a week, and their trades can last from months to years. Generally speaking, position trading captures larger directional moves than those of swing trading and day trading.</p>

<hr />

<p><br/>
<strong>What time frame does ThetaTrades employ?</strong></p>

<p>At ThetaTrades, our trades operate on the daily time frame, and we maintain our position as long as the overall trend of the underlying holds. Usually, our trades last from days to weeks; however, some trends can last a long time, so they can also extend to months and possibly (though rarely) years, so <strong>we’re actually in both the swing and position trading camps</strong>.</p>

<p>With these trading time frames in mind, it&rsquo;s time to ask yourself, which time frame best suits your lifestyle? Do you have a full time job where you can only look at the market once a day or once a week? If you do, If not, styles that require less attention such as swing trading or position trading may be the better option. However, if you do not have a full-time job and are capable of being in front of the markets all day, then day-trading becomes a possibility in your arena. Whatever you decide, make sure that it absolutely fits your personality and lifestyle.</p>

<p>If you have any questions and are still confused as to what type of time frame best suits you, feel free to leave a comment at the bottom of the page, and we&rsquo;ll get back to you!</p>

<p>Cheers!</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re interested in more ideas like this, <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow us on Twitter</a> or <a href="https://facebook.com/thetatrades" title="Follow @thetatrades on Facebook">Facebook</a> to receive our tweets and posts in real time! And if you haven&rsquo;t yet, subscribe to our email listing below to receive special email alerts as well.</p>

<div class="subscribe-button">
    <button>Subscribe to Our Updates</button>
</div>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Long TDC]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/02/27/long-tdc/"/>
    <updated>2017-02-27T14:23:11-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/02/27/long-tdc</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey traders!</p>

<p>We love stocks that have reclaimed the 200MA that are above the 50MA and 20MA as well. What&rsquo;s even better is when they pull back to one of these moving averages. One candidate is $TDC, which has pulled back to the 20MA and held. Please observe the chart below:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.thetatrades.com/images/blog/20170227/tdc.png"><img src="http://www.thetatrades.com/images/blog/20170227/tdc.png" alt="$TDC - 2017-02-27 - Daily" /></a></p>

<p>With a pullback to the 20MA, $TDC offers a good location to get long. Because it is currently a bit far from the 200MA, and with our stop around 27.36, it means that our position size would need to be smaller. But that&rsquo;s fine - the important thing to remember when trying to ride trends is that you want to do it without getting stopped out, and you want your stop to be placed at a point where you&rsquo;re proven wrong, with some buffer added to account for potential noise. Based on this stop distance, you would then calculate your position size to fit your risk tolerance. Again, as with many of our other trades, we&rsquo;re in this trade to ride the trend for as long as possible. As $TDC moves up, we&rsquo;ll also trail our stop below the 200MA.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re interested in more ideas like this, <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow us on Twitter</a> or <a href="https://facebook.com/thetatrades" title="Follow @thetatrades on Facebook">Facebook</a> to receive our tweets and posts in real time! And if you haven&rsquo;t yet, subscribe to our email listing below to receive special email alerts as well.</p>

<div class="subscribe-button">
    <button>Subscribe to Our Updates</button>
</div>




<!-- <script src="//z-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/onejs?MarketPlace=US&adInstanceId=3c36f001-e4b7-4c98-bffa-716b4f4878ab"></script>
 -->

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[FCX - Another Opportunity]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/02/26/fcx-another-opportunity/"/>
    <updated>2017-02-26T22:22:29-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/02/26/fcx-another-opportunity</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey traders!</p>

<p>One of the things that we love most about stocks is trading them in the direction of the trend, at an area of value. By area of value, we mean at places like retracements. One particular stock that shows this is $FCX. Check out the chart below:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.thetatrades.com/images/blog/20170226/fcx.png"><img src="http://www.thetatrades.com/images/blog/20170226/fcx.png" alt="$FCX - 2017-02-26 - Daily" /></a></p>

<p>With a pullback to the 200MA, FCX provides a good long entry at 13.25. As this stock tends to overshoot past the 200MA, one can consider entering a bit beneath it as well. However, the stop placement should take that into consideration as well and be placed well below it. Though a further stop reduces the size of the position one can place, it also allows us to ride the trend longer. If anything, we can always add to the position on another pullback if $FCX does continue higher.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re interested in more ideas like this, <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow us on Twitter</a> or <a href="https://facebook.com/thetatrades" title="Follow @thetatrades on Facebook">Facebook</a> to receive our tweets and posts in real time! And if you haven&rsquo;t yet, subscribe to our email listing below to receive special email alerts as well.</p>

<div class="subscribe-button">
    <button>Subscribe to Our Updates</button>
</div>




<!-- <script src="//z-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/onejs?MarketPlace=US&adInstanceId=3c36f001-e4b7-4c98-bffa-716b4f4878ab"></script>
 -->

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Long RIG]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/02/23/long-rig/"/>
    <updated>2017-02-23T21:55:17-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/02/23/long-rig</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey traders,</p>

<p>One stock that makes a good long candidate is $RIG, as it just reclaimed the 50MA and is above the 200MA. Please observe the chart below:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.thetatrades.com/images/blog/20170223/rig.png"><img src="http://www.thetatrades.com/images/blog/20170223/rig.png" alt="$RIG - 2017-02-23 - Daily" /></a></p>

<p>Entry would be around 14.23, and stop would be placed outside the average noise, below the 200MA at around 12.01. As always, remember to always trade with the trend, and ride it for as long as possible.</p>

<div class="subscribe-button">
    <button>Subscribe to Our Updates</button>
</div>




<!-- <script src="//z-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/onejs?MarketPlace=US&adInstanceId=3c36f001-e4b7-4c98-bffa-716b4f4878ab"></script>
 -->

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chipotle - Another Run (Not for the Bathroom)]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/02/22/chipotle-another-run-not-for-the-bathroom/"/>
    <updated>2017-02-22T16:54:05-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/02/22/chipotle-another-run-not-for-the-bathroom</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Chipotle has had a pretty bad run over the past year. Even if you didn&rsquo;t own the stock and just ate there, well, you were probably given a bad run as well. At ThetaTrades, we like to trade potential trend reversals, meaning that a close above the 200MA would signal an entry. $CMG is one of these candidates and could be making another run higher, hopefully for the better this time. Please observe the chart below:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.thetatrades.com/images/blog/20170222/cmg.png"><img src="http://www.thetatrades.com/images/blog/20170222/cmg.png" alt="$CMG - 2017-02-22 - Daily" /></a></p>

<p>Over the past four trading days, $CMG has held above the 200MA. Still close to the moving average, one can look to initiate a long position, with entry at around 430, and a stop loss below the 200MA, far enough to avoid the average noise the stock makes. As such, the stop could be placed around 403.67. Once set, if $CMG does take off, we simply enjoy the ride, and continue trading the trend, while moving our stops up with the 200MA.</p>

<div class="subscribe-button">
    <button>Subscribe to Our Updates</button>
</div>




<!-- <script src="//z-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/onejs?MarketPlace=US&adInstanceId=3c36f001-e4b7-4c98-bffa-716b4f4878ab"></script>
 -->

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Charts of the Week]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/02/20/charts-of-the-week/"/>
    <updated>2017-02-20T14:25:41-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/02/20/charts-of-the-week</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There&rsquo;s no doubt that the overall trend of the equities market is up. As such, many stocks are simply following the trend, and so should we. We&rsquo;ve been looking at a few charts over the weekend; here are some that stood out as good tickers to get long:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.thetatrades.com/images/blog/20170220/tap.png"><img src="http://www.thetatrades.com/images/blog/20170220/tap.png" alt="$TAP - 2017-02-20 - Daily" /></a>
Here&rsquo;s $TAP: over the 200MA post earnings. Stop would be beneath the 200MA.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.thetatrades.com/images/blog/20170220/ppg.png"><img src="http://www.thetatrades.com/images/blog/20170220/ppg.png" alt="$PPG - 2017-02-20 - Daily" /></a>
$PPG: Reclaimed the 200MA, quite a lot of room to the upside. Stop below 200MA.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.thetatrades.com/images/blog/20170220/alk.png"><img src="http://www.thetatrades.com/images/blog/20170220/alk.png" alt="$ALK - 2017-02-20 - Daily" /></a>
$ALK: Super bullish, holding snugly above the 20MA.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.thetatrades.com/images/blog/20170220/mdt.png"><img src="http://www.thetatrades.com/images/blog/20170220/mdt.png" alt="$MDT - 2017-02-20 - Daily" /></a>
$MDT: recapturing the 200MA.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.thetatrades.com/images/blog/20170220/dg.png"><img src="http://www.thetatrades.com/images/blog/20170220/dg.png" alt="$DG - 2017-02-20 - Daily" /></a>
$DG: recaptured 200MA and holding. Stop below 200MA.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.thetatrades.com/images/blog/20170220/myl.png"><img src="http://www.thetatrades.com/images/blog/20170220/myl.png" alt="$MYL - 2017-02-20 - Daily" /></a>
$MYL: recaptured 200MA and holding. Stop below 200MA.</p>

<p>As always, if entering these positions, place stops away from the average noise the stock makes. Think about risk first, and size up your position according to how much you are comfortable with losing if your stop were to get hit. Once set, enjoy the ride with the trend.</p>

<div class="subscribe-button">
    <button>Subscribe to Our Updates</button>
</div>




<!-- <script src="//z-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/onejs?MarketPlace=US&adInstanceId=3c36f001-e4b7-4c98-bffa-716b4f4878ab"></script>
 -->

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Best Stock Trading Books Every Trader Should Read]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/02/18/the-best-stock-trading-books-every-trader-should-read/"/>
    <updated>2017-02-18T13:41:22-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/02/18/the-best-stock-trading-books-every-trader-should-read</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Whether or not you’re a professional trader, or just an average trader looking to become a professional, we believe that there are important books that discuss in depths the foundation of trading success. From psychology and discipline to execution, the concepts covered by the following books are a must-have in order to be successful in the trading business. Here is a list of the top four trading books we recommend, our detailed review of each, and why every trader should have them in their arsenal to create long-lasting wealth.<br/></p>

<p class="title">
<a href="http://amzn.to/2luN8En">Van Tharp - Trade Your Way to Financial Freedom</a> | (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/book/trade-your-way-to-financial/id502276916?mt=11">iBooks</a>)<br/>
<a class="book-image" target="_blank"  href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/007147871X/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&camp=1789&creative=9325&creativeASIN=007147871X&linkCode=as2&tag=thetatrades-20&linkId=c4b8fb5a73301abe6d1c790a889ba14f"><img border="0" src="//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?_encoding=UTF8&MarketPlace=US&ASIN=007147871X&ServiceVersion=20070822&ID=AsinImage&WS=1&Format=_SL250_&tag=thetatrades-20" ></a><img src="//ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=thetatrades-20&l=am2&o=1&a=007147871X" width="1" height="1" border="0" alt="" style="border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" />
</p>


<p>This is by far the best book that we believe every consistently profitable trader should read. Many average traders blindly believe that having a high probability of profit brings trading success, only to find out that in the long run, they still do not make money. Why is is that they have a track record of having more wins than losses, but still end up being net negative in their liquidity? In his book <em>Trade Your Way to Financial Freedom,</em> Van Tharp discusses the fundamental concepts from position sizing and risk management, to the more crucial concepts of R-multiples and proper backtesting. If you’re still looking for the “holy grail” chart setup or strategy that will make you rich an in instant, you need to stop where you are and pick up this book. Because the truth is, the only “holy grail” that you need to be looking for already exists within you - once you’ve read this book, you’ll figure out what is holding you back from scoring those big winners and being consistently profitable in the long run.<br/> <br/> <br/></p>

<p class="title">
<a href="http://amzn.to/2luFnyq">Mike Bellafiore - The Playbook</a> |
(<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/author/mike-bellafiore/id383955358?mt=11">iBooks</a>)<br/>
<a class="book-image" target="_blank"  href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0132937646/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&camp=1789&creative=9325&creativeASIN=0132937646&linkCode=as2&tag=thetatrades-20&linkId=f041a15427dae7c8762c15abd8af30f1"><img border="0" src="//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?_encoding=UTF8&MarketPlace=US&ASIN=0132937646&ServiceVersion=20070822&ID=AsinImage&WS=1&Format=_SL250_&tag=thetatrades-20" ></a><img src="//ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=thetatrades-20&l=am2&o=1&a=0132937646" width="1" height="1" border="0" alt="" style="border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" />
</p>


<p>In terms of trading discipline, <em>The Playbook</em> offers numerous accounts of day traders in Mike’s firm who went from just the average Joe to flat out professional. Through rigorous journaling and documentation of their trades and emotions, these traders eventually became consistent in following their methodology, and as a result, became consistently profitable. As you read through this book, pay attention to the journey of each of the traders - how they started, what their thought process was like, and how, eventually, the lightbulb went off in their head. But don’t expect to find the one chart setup that’ll make you rich quickly in this book either, unless you’re absolutely willing, like the mentioned traders, to put in the effort of creating your own Playbook and having the discipline to constantly review and refine your process.<br/> <br/> <br/></p>

<p class="title">
<a href="http://amzn.to/2luzykF">Michael Covel - Trend Following: Learn to Make Millions in Up or Down Markets</a> |
(<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/book/trend-following-updated-edition/id401494235?mt=11">iBooks</a>)<br/>
<a class="book-image" target="_blank"  href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/013702018X/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&camp=1789&creative=9325&creativeASIN=013702018X&linkCode=as2&tag=thetatrades-20&linkId=d4f3a693f1b481eed7b2da3cda3c0f67"><img border="0" src="//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?_encoding=UTF8&MarketPlace=US&ASIN=013702018X&ServiceVersion=20070822&ID=AsinImage&WS=1&Format=_SL250_&tag=thetatrades-20" ></a><img src="//ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=thetatrades-20&l=am2&o=1&a=013702018X" width="1" height="1" border="0" alt="" style="border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" />
</p>


<p>One of the biggest mistakes that average traders make is that they try to predict where the market goes, whether it is through fundamental analysis, or technical analysis via chart patterns like Head and Shoulders, Cup and Handle, Fibonacci Extensions, etc… The truth is, it doesn’t need to be that hard - there’s only one constant in trading that traders can trade off of, and that is price. And to make money off of price, one should follow the direction of price. In <em>Trend Following</em>, Michael Covel discusses the simple strategy of eliminating discretionary trading and implementing the systematic process of trading in the direction of the trend, in all types of markets To those that believe that this sounds boring because it may not seem like a “get rich quick” type of strategy, you’ll want to think about this next point: good trading isn’t fun - it’s mechanical, methodical, and should be outright boring, because that’s the kind of trading that makes money. If you’re still holding on to your losers and quickly taking profits when you see winners, but are having a hard time cutting your losses short and letting your winners run, then we highly recommend this book.<br/> <br/> <br/></p>

<p class="title">
<a href="http://amzn.to/2li6gU1">Edwin Lefevre - Reminiscences of a Stock Operator</a> |
(<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/audiobook/reminiscences-stock-operator/id371680538">iBooks</a>)<br/>
<a class="book-image" target="_blank"  href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0471770884/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&camp=1789&creative=9325&creativeASIN=0471770884&linkCode=as2&tag=thetatrades-20&linkId=d5dfe694031baee69506c078319044df"><img border="0" src="//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?_encoding=UTF8&MarketPlace=US&ASIN=0471770884&ServiceVersion=20070822&ID=AsinImage&WS=1&Format=_SL250_&tag=thetatrades-20" ></a><img src="//ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=thetatrades-20&l=am2&o=1&a=0471770884" width="1" height="1" border="0" alt="" style="border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" />
</p>


<p>This is a book which walks through the life of Jesse Livermore, a securities trader. Throughout his trading career, Livermore learned many lessons, now shared in this book, from making a lot of money, to losing a lot more. Like some of the other books, this too does not offer the perfect “chart setup” that will make you get rich quickly - instead, it provides the fundamental strategies of maintaining proper trading psychology, the ultimate aspect of consistently profitable traders. To quote from an excerpt in the book:</p>

<blockquote><p>The reason is that a man may see straight and clearly and yet become impatient or doubtful when the market takes its time about doing as he figured it must do. That is why so many men in Wall Street, who are not at all in the sucker class, not even in the third grade, nevertheless lose money. The market does not beat them. They beat themselves, because though they have brains they cannot sit tight.</p></blockquote>

<p>If you want to know what you should and should not do when it comes to trading psychology, then start reading this entertaining, yet inspiring novel, and be prepared to change your trading psychology and approach to the markets.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fireworks for SWKS]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/02/16/fireworks-for-swks/"/>
    <updated>2017-02-16T22:07:45-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/02/16/fireworks-for-swks</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey traders,</p>

<p>We particularly like to look for stocks that are currently consolidating with a potential of moving higher with the trend of the market. One particular candidate to put on our watchlist is $SWKS. Please observe the chart below</p>

<p><a href="http://www.thetatrades.com/images/blog/20170216/swks.png"><img src="http://www.thetatrades.com/images/blog/20170216/swks.png" alt="$SWKS - 2017-02-16 - Daily" /></a></p>

<p>$SWKS has exploded like a firework after earnings and has recently consolidated around the 92 level. As the 20MA catches up, we&rsquo;re looking for buyers to step in and hold price above that curve. We&rsquo;re looking for another set of fireworks - a breakout above 94. It wouldn&rsquo;t be a bad idea to start accumulating some long deltas. For stock, we&rsquo;ll be going long at 91.80 with a stop below the 20MA at 87.46.</p>

<div class="subscribe-button">
    <button>Subscribe to Our Updates</button>
</div>




<!-- <script src="//z-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/onejs?MarketPlace=US&adInstanceId=3c36f001-e4b7-4c98-bffa-716b4f4878ab"></script>
 -->

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[DUK Reclaims 200MA]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/02/16/duk-reclaims-200ma/"/>
    <updated>2017-02-16T17:37:16-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/02/16/duk-reclaims-200ma</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey traders,</p>

<p>The utility sector in general has been hanging out in an area of value for one to get long. One stock in this sector in particular which just reported earnings is DUK. Please observe the chart below:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.thetatrades.com/images/blog/20170216/duk.png"><img src="http://www.thetatrades.com/images/blog/20170216/duk.png" alt="$DUK - 2017-02-16 - Daily" /></a></p>

<p>With earnings out of the way, and with it reclaiming the 20, 50, and 200MA via a strong close, $DUK looks like it&rsquo;s positioned for another run up. We&rsquo;ll look to buy if price crosses above 78.90, with a stop at 75.79 to give us some leeway to account for recent noise. As long as price holds and trends upward, we&rsquo;ll continue to hold.</p>

<div class="subscribe-button">
    <button>Subscribe to Our Updates</button>
</div>




<!-- <script src="//z-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/onejs?MarketPlace=US&adInstanceId=3c36f001-e4b7-4c98-bffa-716b4f4878ab"></script>
 -->

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[PCLN Revisited]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/02/15/pcln-revisited/"/>
    <updated>2017-02-15T19:07:36-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/02/15/pcln-revisited</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey traders,</p>

<p>We&rsquo;re currently looking at two potential bullish plays.</p>

<p>First is $PCLN:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.thetatrades.com/images/blog/20170215/pcln.png"><img src="http://www.thetatrades.com/images/blog/20170215/pcln.png" alt="$PCLN - 2017-02-15 - Daily" /></a></p>

<p>We had mentioned to get long <a href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/01/23/long-pcln/" title="Long PCLN">back on Jan 23</a>, and $PCLN has trended nicely since then. However, with the recent three day consolidation, and the bullishness of the market, $PCLN looks ready to break out higher for more upside gains. One can look to add more on a break above 1652.</p>

<p>Second is $TXN:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.thetatrades.com/images/blog/20170215/txn.png"><img src="http://www.thetatrades.com/images/blog/20170215/txn.png" alt="$TXN - 2017-02-15 - Daily" /></a></p>

<p>$TXN has also trended nicely over the past year, holding above the 50MA. We&rsquo;ve pulled back to it recently, making it a great location to get long. We&rsquo;re looking to get long above 75.76, with a stop at 72.20. We&rsquo;ll continue staying long as long as trend holds.</p>

<div class="subscribe-button">
    <button>Subscribe to Our Updates</button>
</div>




<!-- <script src="//z-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/onejs?MarketPlace=US&adInstanceId=3c36f001-e4b7-4c98-bffa-716b4f4878ab"></script>
 -->

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How I Improved My Trading]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/02/15/how-i-improved-my-trading/"/>
    <updated>2017-02-15T08:55:30-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/02/15/how-i-improved-my-trading</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>[Written by a member of ThetaTrades]</em></p>

<p>When I first started trading, I lost a huge amount of money. During this time, I had a full time job, and I would wonder what was the point of working if I’m just going to re-invest it back into my trading account and potentially lose it all again. I felt like I was at a constant loss. I felt like a victim. For days, I beat up myself - sulked around, stopped going to the gym, underperformed at work, and just felt like settling for a lackluster life. Needless to say, this was a pretty big obstacle for me.</p>

<p>Then I came across a book called <a href="http://amzn.to/2kypWkt" title="Fred Kofman - Conscious Business">Conscious Business</a> by Fred Kofman. Fred mentions in one chapter the concept of the &ldquo;victim&rdquo; vs the &ldquo;player&rdquo;:</p>

<blockquote><blockquote><blockquote><p>“You must take unconditional responsibility; you need to see yourself as a ‘player,’ as a central character who has contributed to shape the current situation—and who can thus affect its future.<br/><br/>
This is the opposite of seeing yourself as a ‘victim,’ subject to forces beyond your control. The player is the in the game and can affect the result. The victim is out of the game and can only suffer the consequences of others’ actions."</p></blockquote></blockquote></blockquote>

<p>As cliche as it sounds, the lightbulb went off in my head. We only have one life to live, and we better take advantage of it to the utmost of our ability. This means taking action and taking responsibility for the things that we do in our life. More importantly, it means that no matter what external factors that affect us, even the things that are seemingly out of our control (ie. weather, traffic, accidents), we STILL have a choice in how we approach the way we view these circumstances. We still can choose to how we respond to it.</p>

<p>In my particular situation, I came to realize that I can choose to feel the pain, beat up myself, sulk in my losses, etc (be the victim), or I can choose to learn from this experience, work hard, dedicate time and energy to become a disciplined and consistently profitable trader, and conquer all aspects of life (be the player).</p>

<p>To this day, this passage from Fred&rsquo;s book continues to resonate with me; every day, I&rsquo;m motivated to take responsibility for everything that happens to me. And I mean literally everything. I stopped trying to apologize in ways that felt like I was not in control. I went from saying &ldquo;Sorry, I was late because there was traffic&rdquo; and replacing them with &ldquo;Sorry, I was late. I did not account for traffic. Next time, I&rsquo;ll use Waze, and if my ETA will be such that I&rsquo;ll be late to my destination, I will make sure to give you a call.&rdquo;</p>

<p>I hope that each one of you, trader or not, will take advantage of the principles that this book has to offer. It&rsquo;s truly a rare gem, and I continuously refer back to the book every now and then and apply the concepts to all aspects of my life. Don&rsquo;t forget that the most powerful investment that you can make in yourself is knowledge through education.</p>

<p>Cheers!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
