<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[ThetaTrades]]></title>
  <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-04-25T20:37:05-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[theta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Watch for an Upside Move]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/25/watch-for-an-upside-move/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-25T20:11:37-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/25/watch-for-an-upside-move</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Value continues to build lower:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04242016/es.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04252016/es.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-04-25 - 15m Chart - Volume Profile" /></a></p>

<p>That&rsquo;s definitely not a bullish sign; however, just to stay alert, I wanted to point out one thing that I noticed over the past two trading sessions that has me prepared for a move back to the upside, and this is the way in which the Bears have attempted to push prices lower. You may have noticed the slow and steady grind lower during Friday&rsquo;s action and today&rsquo;s action. This has me thinking that the Bears aren&rsquo;t really confident, and they&rsquo;re struggling to push prices lower, but ultimately unable to. You can see this clearly during the past two trading sessions, where much of the grind lower gets wiped out by a big rip to the upside towards the end of each session.</p>

<p>Also, notice that today, we managed to close above the intermediate balance area high. I would not be surprised tomorrow if we hold above that level and trade near the POC from last Monday, Thursday, or Friday, which is around 2085. If so, I would consider that bullish, and would be looking to put on some type of a credit trade that captures a move into the 2100 level going forward.</p>

<p>For me to switch my bias to bearish, I would need to see the 2067 level fail. If we close below there with signs of stronger selling, I&rsquo;ll be looking to target the other side of balance, which is down at 2012. More intermediate targets would occur along the way, but they&rsquo;ll be noted when we do break 2067.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today. For now, I&rsquo;m still keeping my bias neutral, but watching for any bullish/bearish signals.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mixed Signals from Indices]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/24/mixed-signals-from-indices/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-24T14:38:16-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/24/mixed-signals-from-indices</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We ended last week on diverging signals. It&rsquo;s important to look at all broad market indices, so let&rsquo;s do that.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the SPX:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04242016/spx.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04242016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-04-24 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>We have a very clear look above and fail, topping tail pattern, which is generally a bearish signal. However, although we closed below trendline resistance, the week did end up positive, so keep that in mind.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the DJX:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04242016/djx.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04242016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-04-24 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>This one is a little bit more bullish than the SPX, as we closed just a bit above that 100% retracement level. I do think we start consolidating around this area for a while before we break any higher.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the NDX:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04242016/ndx.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04242016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-04-24 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>The weakest of the bunch again due to weak earnings from GOOG. It has been unable to close above that trendline resistance, but do keep a close eye on this.</p>

<p>Finally the RUT:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04242016/rut.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04242016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-04-24 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>The most bullish of all indices. This one clearly closed the week above the trendline resistance and has a lot of clearance to continue running to 1200.</p>

<p>Going forward, keep a close eye on all of these indices. They&rsquo;re currently divergent, so it&rsquo;s hard to say whether we should remain bullish or bearish going forward. For now, bias remains neutral.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for the recap - make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a>, because that&rsquo;s where I post all my trades in real-time. Make sure you turn on notifications specifically from me. Just visit my Twitter profile on mobile, select the Settings gear, and then select the option to turn on notifications.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets tomorrow!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Will the Bears Continue the Selling Pressure?]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/21/will-the-bears-continue-the-selling-pressure/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-21T18:49:01-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/21/will-the-bears-continue-the-selling-pressure</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We saw a nice liquidation break today, and actually saw the first sign of sellers being able to keep that pressure on throughout the entire RTH session. Let&rsquo;s take a look at the overall volume profile over the past 20 days:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04212016/es.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04212016/es.png" alt="/ES - 2016-04-21 - Volume Profile - 20 days" /></a></p>

<p>We can see that today, not only did we clearly create value lower, but also look where the point of control migrated to: basically back to where it was on Monday. We&rsquo;re now exploring this area to see if this is the fairest price to do business.</p>

<p>And if we zoom in and take a closer look at the past couple of weeks:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04212016/es_zoomed.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04212016/es_zoomed.png" alt="/ES - 2016-04-21 - Volume Profile - Zoomed In - Value Area Gapping Lower" /></a></p>

<p>Notice today, our value area not only migrated lower, but also it did not overlap yesterday&rsquo;s value area. When value areas gap like this, it <em>generally</em> signifies the start of a new trend (although a larger gap would&rsquo;ve been better to signify stronger selling pressure). Will the selling continue tomorrow? We can only wait to find out, but until then, bias is neutral.</p>

<p>Going forward, here are important reference points to keep in mind: I&rsquo;ll be watching how the <strong>2081.75</strong> level holds tomorrow. <strong>The area between 2067 and 2081.75 can be considered a balance area</strong>, which was formed last week for a few days before we broke higher out of it this Monday. If we fall back into this area tomorrow and we start seeing some really strong selling pressure (watch the internals), look to target the other side of that balance area, which is <strong>2067</strong>.</p>

<p>Before wrapping up, I&rsquo;d like to propose a trade idea, which I haven&rsquo;t in a while. Here&rsquo;s <strong>HAL</strong> on the daily:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04212016/hal.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04212016/hal.png" alt="HAL - 2016-04-21 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m looking to position a trade around <strong>HAL</strong> that assumes the analog of what happened last year would happen again this year. If so, a trade that captures a slow retracement to the bottom of the right orange rectangle over the next month or so would probably be ideal.</p>

<p>I couldn&rsquo;t find any butterflies/put backratios that were great, so I was thinking a small calendar play may work here, specifically, the JUN/MAY 36 PUT calendar:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04212016/hal_calendar.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04212016/hal_calendar.png" alt="HAL - 2016-04-21 - Put Calendar" /></a></p>

<p>This is a much longer-term play, and we&rsquo;ll need to wait probably around a month or so for the premium to really start coming in. If you have a slight bearish bias on the energy sector, this could be the play for you.</p>

<p>One thing to note is that this company does have earnings coming up, but I&rsquo;m not really expecting the stock to move much to the downside, and we have quite some time for the trade to work out for us. I&rsquo;ll be looking to put this trade on tomorrow, so be on the lookout for that.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today - as always, make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a>. That is where I post all of my trades in real-time. Make sure you turn on notifications specifically from me. Just go to my Twitter profile on your mobile device, select the Settings gear, and then select the option to turn on notifications.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets tomorrow, and remember to keep those reference points in mind on the /ES.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Value Building Higher]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/20/value-building-higher/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-20T21:40:42-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/20/value-building-higher</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Value builds higher:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04202016/es.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04202016/es.png" alt="/ES - 2016-04-20 - Volume Profile" /></a></p>

<p>Towards the end of the trading session, we had a nice liquidation break, and we bounced right off yesterday&rsquo;s value area high. So still, very short term reference points in play here. Regardless, this is still bullish, as value continues to build higher, and volume POCs continue to move higher. This liquidation break only strengthened the market.</p>

<p><em>Bias is still bullish until sellers step up.</em></p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today. If you haven&rsquo;t already, make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a>. That is where I post all of my trades in real-time. Don&rsquo;t forget to turn on notifications specifically from me. Just go to my Twitter profile on mobile, select the Settings gear, and then select the option to turn on notifications.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Still Bullish...]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/19/still-bullish-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-19T21:29:48-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/19/still-bullish-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Markets still remain bullish.</p>

<p>We&rsquo;ve had mini-liquidation breaks throughout the trading day - all that does is strengthen the market, as it eliminates the shorter-term, weaker hands, allowing buyers to continue doing what they do - buying.</p>

<p>Taking a look at the SPX:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04192016/spx.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04192016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-04-19 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>We had a nice strong close by the end of the trading session.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the DJX:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04192016/djx.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04192016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-04-19 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>Also a nice follow through here.</p>

<p>However, the NDX:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04192016/ndx.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04192016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-04-19 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>Still the weakest of the bunch. This is one that casts a shadow of doubt on the rally - eventually, this, or one or more of the other indices will catch up to the other.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the RUT:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04192016/rut.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04192016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-04-19 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>Consolidating after a move higher from yesterday. Watch for a continuation tomorrow. Our <a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/trades#RUT" title="RUT Call Calendar">RUT calendar</a> is still looking good, and we&rsquo;re holding on to it - no need to panic out.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today. As always, make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a>. That is where I post all of my trades in real-time. Make sure you turn on notifications specifically from me. Just go to my Twitter profile on mobile, select the Settings gear, and then select the option to turn on notifications.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets tomorrow!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bias Still to the Upside]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/18/bias-still-to-the-upside/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-18T19:01:23-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/18/bias-still-to-the-upside</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Market trucks relentlessly to the upside, and bias remains to the upside until market starts to show signs of sellers.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the SPX:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04182016/spx.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04182016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-04-18 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>We closed just above that trendline, which can now be considered broken. The next target here is 2100, followed by 2115.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the DJX:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04182016/djx.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04182016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-04-18 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>Bullish here as well. We closed above the highs of November from last year. The next target would be around 181.9.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the NDX:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04182016/ndx.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04182016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-04-18 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>The weakest of the bunch, but it closed at the trendline resistance and has room to run to the upside. First target is the gap fill of 2016, which is just about 20 points away.</p>

<p>Finally the RUT:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04182016/rut.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04182016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-04-18 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>This broke the trendline resistance very cleanly. The next major resistance is around 1200.</p>

<p>Today, we put on the trade discussed yesterday for the RUT - you can see that post <a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/17/remaining-cautiously-bullish/" title="RUT Call Calendar Spread">here</a>. If you missed the entry, it&rsquo;s not too late to get in the trade. More importantly, make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a>, because that&rsquo;s where I post all my trades in real-time. Make sure you turn on notifications specifically from me. Just visit my Twitter profile on mobile, select the Settings gear, and then select the option to turn on notifications.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today. Good luck in the markets tomorrow!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Remaining Cautiously Bullish]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/17/remaining-cautiously-bullish/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-17T12:37:47-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/17/remaining-cautiously-bullish</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m continuing to remain cautiously bullish going into next week, given the massive overhead resistance we still have.</p>

<p>Looking at the broad market indices on the weekly, here&rsquo;s the SPX:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04172016/spx.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04172016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-04-17 - Weekly Chart" /></a></p>

<p>We finished last week with a wide body candle after <em>consolidating</em> for a couple of weeks prior. This leads me to believe that, if we do continue moving up, the trendline resistance up ahead is less likely to hold, given how close we consolidated just under that.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the DJX:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04172016/djx.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04172016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-04-17 - Weekly Chart" /></a></p>

<p>The previous trendline resistance (now support) is holding up nicely. The same thing can be seen here - consolidation right underneath the 100% Fib level from back in November. This makes me think it&rsquo;s not hard to pierce that resistance level.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the NDX:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04172016/ndx.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04172016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-04-17 - Weekly Chart" /></a></p>

<p>Again, same thing.</p>

<p>The RUT probably paints the clearest picture:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04172016/rut.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04172016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-04-17 - Weekly Chart" /></a></p>

<p>We&rsquo;ve consolidated over the past two weeks below the trendline and closed the week right up against it. That trendline can easily be invalidated, in which case we&rsquo;d have clearance to run up to the 1200 levels again.</p>

<p>Given what we just saw in the RUT, come Monday I&rsquo;m looking to put on a Call Calendar (again?!) in the RUT (unfortunately, the market has been extremely boring recently, and this is one of the bread and butter strategies during times of low volatility):</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04172016/rut_call_calendar.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04172016/rut_call_calendar.png" alt="RUT - 2016-04-17 - Call Calendar" /></a></p>

<p>We&rsquo;ll manage this over the next month. The debit here is quite small for the potential gains we can achieve. If you have a bearish portfolio, this could be quite beneficial if the market does continue running higher.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for this weekend. I&rsquo;ll be posting that trade, along with all other entries/adjustments, live on Twitter, so be sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> to get all of my updates in real time.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets this week!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Value Building Higher]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/14/value-building-higher/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-14T21:38:50-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/14/value-building-higher</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Market remains strong as value builds higher:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04142016/esm6.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04142016/esm6.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-04-14 - Market Profile - 20d Zoomed In" /></a></p>

<p>We were able to hold above the balance area for the second trading session after the breakout. Stay with the trend, and that is up. Any kind of a pullback on not-so-bearish internals can be considered buy points, as short term traders are still the most dominant traders out there in terms of price action. 2067 would be that point.</p>

<p>We are at some very interesting points in the broad market indices, so just wanted to briefly present them.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the SPX:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04142016/spx.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04142016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-04-14 - Daily" /></a></p>

<p>We&rsquo;re just about 10 points away from 2092 on the SPX, which would be the trendline resistance point by tomorrow. As mentioned yesterday, we expected a consolidation day today, and that is exactly what we got today, that Doji. Watch for either a continuation or a reversal tomorrow.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the DJX:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04142016/djx.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04142016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-04-14 - Daily" /></a></p>

<p>We just barely tagged the high from back in November, closing on a spinning top. Again, watch for a continuation or a reversal tomorrow.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the NDX:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04142016/ndx.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04142016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-04-14 - Daily" /></a></p>

<p>Very similar here as it&rsquo;s also closing today on a Doji like the SPX after tagging that trendline resistance.</p>

<p>And the RUT:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04142016/rut.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04142016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-04-14 - Daily" /></a></p>

<p>Touching that trendline resistance today and closing on a spinning top.</p>

<p>These are all very similar patterns across all the indices, so we shall see how this all plays out tomorrow.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today. I&rsquo;ll keep posting new entries/adjustments on Twitter, so be sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> to get all of my updates in real time.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets and good trading!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Breaking out of Balance]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/13/breaking-out-of-balance/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-13T18:18:12-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/13/breaking-out-of-balance</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The market broke out of balance very clearly today to the upside as we mentioned yesterday:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04132016/esm6.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04132016/esm6.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-04-13 - Market Profile - 15d Zoomed In" /></a></p>

<p>We attempted to trade back below balance, but failed as buyers kept the market up.</p>

<p>On the SPX, we now have clearance to tag the uppermost trendline resistance this Friday at around 2090.</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04132016/spx.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04132016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-04-13 - Trendline Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>Also, from now on for the SPX chart, the pink rectangles will be removed - the target here has been reached.</p>

<p>Watch for the top of the balance area to hold as support, because we can just as easily fail tomorrow and fall back into the balance area, which is not a strong Bullish signal. If that&rsquo;s the case, I&rsquo;ll be looking for a rotation all the way back down to the bottom of the balance area (2012) as a weekly play. However, tomorrow, I&rsquo;m looking for some consolidation before any moves higher.</p>

<p>One of the plays that I&rsquo;m looking at currently is the SPY MAY2/APR5 211/210 Diagonal Call spread, currently going for about .26 debit:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04132016/spy_call_diagonal.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04132016/spy_call_diagonal.png" alt="SPY Diagonal Call Spread - 2016-04-13 - Risk Graph" /></a></p>

<p>This has breakevens at around 206 and 212 over the next few weeks. Given the low volatility that we&rsquo;ve been having and the low confidence in any downmove, as long as we stay in this range, we should be good to milk some premium. I&rsquo;ll be looking to put this on tomorrow.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today. I&rsquo;ll keep posting new entries/adjustments on Twitter, so be sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> to get all of my updates in real time.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets and good trading!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Exploring Upper Side of Balance Area]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/12/exploring-upper-side-of-balance-area/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-12T23:19:17-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/12/exploring-upper-side-of-balance-area</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ll keep the post today short, as nothing much as changed.</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04122016/esm6.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04122016/esm6.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-04-12 - Market Profile - 15d Zoomed In" /></a></p>

<p>We&rsquo;re still inside the large balance area between 2012.25 and 2067. From the movement today, it appears we&rsquo;ll reach the upper side of the balance area tomorrow, and we&rsquo;ll need to pay close attention to the strength of the breakout to the upside from there. Keep in mind 2067 was the overnight high that was had not revisited yet. Intraday tomorrow, we may see multiple touches of this level, and multiple backing-offs. If we do see this kind of action, be prepared for an even stronger breakout.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today - will keep posting new entries/adjustments on Twitter, so be sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> to get all of my updates in real time.</p>

<p>Good luck tomorrow!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Still in Balance]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/11/still-in-balance/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-11T20:31:30-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/11/still-in-balance</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We had another late-day selloff. Don&rsquo;t be surprised if we gap up tomorrow morning as we have been doing so much these past couple of weeks.</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04112016/esm6_15d.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04112016/esm6_15d.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-04-11 - Market Profile - 15d" /></a></p>

<p>We&rsquo;re still trading within the balance area between 2012.25 and 2067, so things still look neutral to me. The next, intermediate downside reference point is 2026. If we can build value near that area (remember 2025 is the POC from the Janet Yellen day - this is the day with the three blue distributions), then I&rsquo;d give the edge to the Bears. Until then, bias remains neutral, but be ready because those reference points below us are weak, as can be seen in the 20-day chart:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04112016/esm6_20d.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04112016/esm6_20d.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-04-11 - Market Profile - 20d - Weak Reference Points" /></a></p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today - I&rsquo;ll be posting/adjusting more trades tomorrow, so be sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> to get all of my updates in real time.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets tomorrow!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Preparing for a Breakout]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/09/preparing-for-a-breakout/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-09T13:26:26-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/09/preparing-for-a-breakout</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This market has been consolidating in a big balance area for a while now, with the volume POC for the past 15 days at around the 2040.75 level in the /ES:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04092016/esm6.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04092016/esm6.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-04-09 - Market Profile" /></a></p>

<p>The composite doesn&rsquo;t look quite skewed in any direction, so I would say we&rsquo;re right in the middle of this entire balance area between 2012 and 2067.</p>

<p>Keep in mind 2012 goes back to a spike high from March 16 (refer to <a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/18/the-most-dangerous-aspect-of-the-recent-rally/" title="Weak Reference Points">this post for more info</a> ), as well as a <em>close</em> touch of that point back in March 24. Keep this weak reference point in mind going forward.</p>

<p>Short term traders continue to be the dominant players here, getting themselves overly long or overly short. Until we see some bigger players come into play and break us out of balance, assume that we trade within the denoted range.</p>

<p>Overall, momentum in the board market indices does look like it is slowing and rounding off. My bias here is still neutral, and with such low IV, it doesn&rsquo;t make sense to be selling premium. If you have a directional bias and you&rsquo;re bearish, selling calls might not be a bad idea. Personally, I&rsquo;d want to be buying cheap OOM calendar spreads.</p>

<p>We haven&rsquo;t really traded options on the indices in a while, but here&rsquo;s a trade idea on the SPY utilizing an OOM put calendar:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04092016/spy_put_calendar.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04092016/spy_put_calendar.png" alt="SPY - 2016-04-09 - Put Calendar Risk Graph" /></a></p>

<p>We&rsquo;d like SPY to trade between 190 and 202 by expiration. Adjust strikes as necessary. If you want to collect a credit, you can think about moving the nearer term strike higher.</p>

<p>A simple call credit spread on the SPY is also not a bad idea. I may be looking to put some on this coming week, depending on conditions.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m also thinking about a Bullish play on AMZN:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04092016/amzn.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04092016/amzn.png" alt="AMZN - 2016-04-09 - Daily - Sitting at Horizontal Support" /></a></p>

<p>AMZN is holding up at the horizontal support level and the upward trendline support level. One of the things I&rsquo;m looking to do is put on a call condor on AMZN that includes the earnings cycle, obviously as an earnings play. I&rsquo;ll also be looking to finance this condor by selling put spreads beneath trendline support for the weeks prior to earnings, as long as the market continues to stay in balance. The reason I&rsquo;m thinking about putting on this trade is that if the market does continue to stay in balance or climb higher, AMZN usually won&rsquo;t sell off and may even climb higher as well into earnings.</p>

<p>Currently the APR5 660/670/690/700 call condor is being priced in for about .89 debit:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04092016/amzn_call_condor.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04092016/amzn_call_condor.png" alt="AMZN - 2016-04-09 - Call Condor Risk Graph" /></a></p>

<p>I might buy a few of these. These and the put spreads will need to be managed if AMZN starts to lose the support levels.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ll be looking to put on these trades come Monday, so <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> to get my updates. And to make the most out of Twitter, make sure you turn on notifications specifically from me. Just visit my Twitter profile on mobile, select the Settings gear, and then select the option to turn on notifications.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for the weekend update - enjoy the weekend, and good trading on Monday!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shifting Bias to Neutral]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/07/shifting-bias-to-neutral/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-07T22:19:22-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/07/shifting-bias-to-neutral</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Short term traders still remain in control.</p>

<p>The price action has been volatile and we&rsquo;ve been having 100% retracements within very short periods of time - i.e. swings from one side of the lows to the highs the very next day. Just two days ago, shorts who tried to push the market lower by the end of the trading session got punished the very next day by the Bulls who took the market all the way up to the highs yesterday. Now, today we&rsquo;ve just reversed all of that and traded even lower today. There&rsquo;s no doubt that shorter term traders are in control here.</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04072016/esm6_vp.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04072016/esm6_vp.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-04-07 - Market Profile" /></a></p>

<p>Today&rsquo;s action touched yesterday&rsquo;s point of control early in the session before failing there, and for the rest of the day, traders built value lower to almost not overlapping. We even took out the weak reference point of 2033.5 and tagged the point of control going back to the Fed day shown by the 3 blue distribution areas on the left side. By the end of today&rsquo;s session, the POC migrated lower to near Apr 5th&rsquo;s POC.</p>

<p>Today was a very interesting day and it appears that the sellers are finally getting some control. Instead of being bought up after gapping down this morning, we actually continued selling and sentiment remained bearish all day.</p>

<p>Zooming out over the past 20 days, here is the volume profile:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04072016/esm6.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04072016/esm6.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-04-07 - Market Profile Zoomed Out" /></a></p>

<p>Here are the reference points to watch out for tomorrow (and this is important due to the short term traders dominating):</p>

<p><strong>Settlement</strong>: 2034.75<br/>
<strong>POC</strong>: 2040<br/>
<strong>Value area high</strong>: 2043<br/>
<strong>Value area low</strong>: 2029.75<br/></p>

<p>Tomorrow, if we gap up, here&rsquo;s what I&rsquo;ll be watching for:</p>

<ol>
<li>How far of a gap are we gapping up by? Anything around double digits is going to be a hard gap to fade unless internals are very bearish. If internals do show strong bearishness, I would look to target the POC and then after that, the settlement, then the value area low, then today&rsquo;s low (2026), then low of the Fed day (2019), then 2012 (the unvisited high of the March 16 spike). Watch for a bounce at any of these levels and look at internals for confirmation.</li>
<li>Are we opening up inside of value area? If so, observe how traders behave - do they want to take it outside of value area and explore higher, lower, or just keep it near the POC? Again, if internals aren&rsquo;t confirming a strong move up or down, then the value area high is most likely a short, and the value area low is most likely a buy. This is just responsive trading. If internals are strong enough for us to break out of value area, then a break below value area is a short, and a break above would be a buy.</li>
<li>How far of a gap down are we gapping down by? Anything around double digits is going to be a hard gap to fade unless internals are very bullish. If internals do show strong bullishness, and we try to go lower but fail and instead we take out the overnight low, I would look to target the yesterday&rsquo;s low and then after that, the value area low, the settlement, then the POC and then value area high, and then from there, yesterday&rsquo;s POC at around 2050. Watch any of these levels for a potential short as well, and watch the internals for confirmation.</li>
</ol>


<p>That&rsquo;s it for today. I don&rsquo;t have trade setups for tonight, but if you <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a>, you will be able to see every trade that I enter, adjust, and exit, and my live market commentary.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets tomorrow!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[More Low Confidence]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/06/more-consolidation/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-06T19:08:41-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/06/more-consolidation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Market continues to consolidate here. As I mentioned yesterday, I just didn&rsquo;t see enough sellers, and that spells low confidence.</p>

<p>Looking at the SPX:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04062016/spx.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04062016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-04-06 - Daily - Look-Above-And-Fail" /></a></p>

<p>Yesterday&rsquo;s look-above-and-fail pattern failed, and now we&rsquo;re back up above the trendline support. All of this just spells low confidence.</p>

<p>DJX:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04062016/djx.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04062016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-04-06 - Daily - Bounced off Trendline Support" /></a></p>

<p>Couldn&rsquo;t continue lower after testing the support. Once again, consolidating just above the trendline support.</p>

<p>NDX:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04062016/ndx.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04062016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-04-06 - Daily - Seller Shutoff" /></a></p>

<p>We&rsquo;re still consolidating here, though we have a wide body candle.</p>

<p>RUT:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04062016/rut.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04062016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-04-06 - Daily - Bullish Engulfing" /></a></p>

<p>We&rsquo;re now back up above the 61.8% Fib level - again, this spells low confidence. When a price level is traded through many times, it&rsquo;s not a sign of trend confidence, but rather a sign of consolidation, or low confidence.</p>

<p>Today, we put on a couple of new trades, specifically calendar spreads in CMG and EEM. We also made some adjustments to our TSLA position (currently our worst trade so far) and closed out our AAPL calendar (at a profit). Check them out in the <a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/trades" title="Ongoing Trades">Trades</a> page. If you want to be notified when I enter, adjust, or exit trades, make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> so you can receive my updates in real-time. Again, to make the most out of Twitter, make sure you turn on notifications specifically from me. Just visit my Twitter profile on the mobile app, select the Settings gear, and select the <em>Turn on Notifications</em> option.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today. Good luck in the markets tomorrow!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Market Still Pausing]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/05/market-still-pausing/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-05T21:23:05-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/05/market-still-pausing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There isn&rsquo;t a lot pointing to the Bears being in full control, yet. For now, it still appears to just be consolidation. I am still watching for a break below 2033.5 on the /ES with strong follow-through before I turn bearish.</p>

<p>Looking at the SPX:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04052016/spx.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04052016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-04-05 - Daily - Look-Above-And-Fail" /></a></p>

<p>Today it appears we formed a look-above-and-fail pattern - I&rsquo;d like to see follow-through to the downside for confirmation.</p>

<p>DJX:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04052016/djx.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04052016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-04-05 - Daily - Sitting at Trendline Support" /></a></p>

<p>We closed just at trendline support. Let&rsquo;s see if it holds.</p>

<p>NDX:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04052016/ndx.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04052016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-04-05 - Daily - Consolidation" /></a></p>

<p>This appears to just be consolidating over the past 5 trading days.</p>

<p>RUT:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04052016/rut.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04052016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-04-05 - Daily - Consolidation" /></a></p>

<p>We&rsquo;re now below the 61.8% Fib level. We&rsquo;ve now traded near and around the 61.8% Fib level many times - consolidation is still happening here.</p>

<p>Ok - we haven&rsquo;t been putting on many trades this week. This is largely due to my reluctance to sell premium in a cycle that contains earnings, but I&rsquo;ve managed to find some that avoid it with good weeklies.</p>

<p>I wanted to go back to GS which I mentioned the other day:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04032016/gs_batman.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04032016/gs_batman.png" alt="GS - 2016-04-05 - Put Backratio With Call Backratio" /></a></p>

<p>Though this play contains an earnings cycle, I&rsquo;ve noticed that it doesn&rsquo;t quite move much from earnings reports. I wouldn&rsquo;t mind putting this on tomorrow - with pretty wide breakevens, we can aim for a move towards both ends of the spectrum, regardless of which way the market moves. Just as long as it doesn&rsquo;t crash, of course. This is currently being priced in at a .67 cr.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve also got a couple of calendars/diagonals for play here.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s DIS:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04052016/dis.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04052016/dis.png" alt="DIS - 2016-04-05 - Daily" /></a></p>

<p>Aiming for 90 by the 4th week of April:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04052016/dis_diagonal.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04052016/dis_diagonal.png" alt="DIS - 2016-04-05 - Diagonal Put" /></a></p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s EEM:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04052016/eem.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04052016/eem.png" alt="EEM - 2016-04-05 - Daily" /></a></p>

<p>Aiming for 30 by the 5th week of April:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04052016/eem_calendar.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04052016/eem_calendar.png" alt="EEM - 2016-04-05 - Put Calendar" /></a></p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s CMG:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04052016/cmg.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04052016/cmg.png" alt="CMG - 2016-04-05 - Daily - Slow Grind to 420" /></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m looking for a slow grind down to 420:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04052016/cmg_calendar.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04052016/cmg_calendar.png" alt="CMG - 2016-04-05 - Put Calendar" /></a></p>

<p>All of these require a debit, but when volatility is low, these are good deals. If we get the directional move we want and volatility expands and time decays the nearer-term option, the spread can really expand nicely.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for now. I&rsquo;ll most likely be putting these trades on, so <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> to get my updates. Also, to make the most out of Twitter, make sure you turn on notifications specifically from me. Just visit my Twitter profile on mobile, select the Settings gear, and turn on notifications.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets tomorrow!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monitoring for Continuation]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/04/monitoring-for-continuation/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-04T20:26:18-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/04/monitoring-for-continuation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today&rsquo;s action is just balancing after a trending move. For me to consider this bearish, I&rsquo;d want to see 2033.5 on the /ES get taken out. I&rsquo;d like to see value move lower as well. Also, the highs from the overnight session usually don&rsquo;t mark the end of up-moves, so expect 2071.5 to be revisited sometime soon, and if it doesn&rsquo;t, carry that information forward.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the SPX:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04042016/spx.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04042016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-04-04 - Daily - Consolidation Above Trendline Support" /></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m looking for this to hold up at the trendline support. A failure to remain above it is an edge to the Bears.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the DJX:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04042016/djx.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04042016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-04-04 - Daily - Consolidation" /></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m also looking for this to hold up at the trendline support.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the NDX:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04042016/ndx.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04042016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-04-04 - Daily - Consolidation" /></a></p>

<p>Looks like a pause before a continuation higher.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the RUT:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04042016/rut.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04042016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-04-04 - Daily - 61.8% Fib Level" /></a></p>

<p>This is a bit more interesting. Still holding above the 61.8 Fib level and may just slowly grind around here until it touches the trendline resistance.</p>

<p>For those looking for a bearish play, I&rsquo;ve been looking at CMG. We have a trendline support coming up on the weekly:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04042016/cmg_weekly.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04042016/cmg_weekly.png" alt="CMG - 2016-04-04 - Weekly" /></a></p>

<p>As well as a revisit of the prior lows at 400 on the daily:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04042016/cmg.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04042016/cmg.png" alt="CMG - 2016-04-04 - Daily" /></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m looking to place a small butterfly to capture a move down into the 400 area:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04042016/cmg_risk_graph.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04042016/cmg_risk_graph.png" alt="CMG - 2016-04-04 - Risk Graph" /></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;ll be tweeting out my entry on this trade depending on how it&rsquo;s priced, so make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> <em>and</em> turn on notifications from my profile (on mobile - hit the settings gear on my profile and then select &ldquo;Turn On Notifications&rdquo;). You&rsquo;ll receive push notifications for all of my tweets.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets tomorrow!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Potential Upside Plays]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/03/potential-upside-plays/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-03T21:34:10-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/03/potential-upside-plays</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been looking at a couple of trade setups given the bullish follow-through I&rsquo;m expecting this coming week and the lack of bearishness out there.</p>

<p>First is GS:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04032016/gs.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04032016/gs.png" alt="GS - 2016-04-03 - Daily - Trendline Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>We&rsquo;ve currently put in a rounded-bottom / inverted head-and-shoulders pattern, and on Friday it appears that we&rsquo;re just breaking out of that right shoulder. If we continue to see bullishness, GS has room to run up to the trendline resistance. This should bring us to about 177 by the time of their earnings. As I&rsquo;m expecting a short term run up, this could make for a (slightly aggressive) potential options play:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04032016/gs_risk_reversal.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04032016/gs_risk_reversal.png" alt="GS - 2016-04-03 - Bull Call Spread Financed by Put Backratio" /></a></p>

<p>We&rsquo;ll buy a slightly OOM call vertical and finance it by selling a put backratio with 11 days to go. We&rsquo;re currently getting a credit for this, but of course this will have to be priced again on Monday.</p>

<p>For those that are a bit more conservative and would like more room for error in case we do have a downside move, consider a longer term play that <em>includes</em> the earnings cycle:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04032016/gs_batman.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04032016/gs_batman.png" alt="GS - 2016-04-03 - Put Backratio With Call Backratio" /></a></p>

<p>Your range of profit potential is wide, with the peaks denoting the max profits (about $500 per spread). With pretty wide breakevens, and the fact that GS doesn&rsquo;t usually move much from earnings, this is a safer approach that could help you profit from either a move up to the 175 area which is near the trendline resistance, or down to the 140 area which is near prior support levels. I personally like this trade more, as we have duration to help us out, too, in case we&rsquo;re wrong on direction.</p>

<p>Another idea is the SPY:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04032016/spy_diagonal.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04032016/spy_diagonal.png" alt="SPY - 2016-04-03 - Diagonal Call Spread" /></a></p>

<p>This is not a short term trade, but one that has a wide breakeven as well by expiration. If you don&rsquo;t expect the SPY to move past 211 by the next few weeks, or if you expect it to slowly grind higher, a cheap diagonal here could be the play.</p>

<p>These are just a couple of ideas that I&rsquo;m looking to put on for Monday - they may be adjusted slightly depending on how the market opens on Monday and where things are priced. I will tweet out the exact trade that I put on in real time, though. Make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> and turn on notifications from me to get my posts in real time (no I don&rsquo;t post pictures of cats or food - no spam, just trades only).</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for now - good luck, and let&rsquo;s have another week of good trading.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bullish into Next Week]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/02/bullish-into-next-week/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-02T11:29:57-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/02/bullish-into-next-week</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m certain the markets will continue to climb higher next week.</p>

<p>There are just not enough sellers out there. On Friday, we were able to enter into the second distribution area from the Janet Yellen day:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04022016/es.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04022016/es.png" alt="/ES - 2016-04-02 - Weak Sellers Failing to Take Market Lower Regardless of Poor Structure" /></a></p>

<p>But before spending enough time there, we couldn&rsquo;t find more sellers to come in. What I was expecting to happen when we broke into the second distribution area was that we at least test the 2033.5 level (and it should be relatively easy to get there due to the extremely poor structure). Obviously that didn&rsquo;t happen, and instead, on Friday during RTH, we ended up moving back up over the overnight low and through the open (which was a strong buy signal). Overnight shorts did not get paid, got nervous, and we saw the market run higher for the rest of the day.</p>

<p>Is that bearish? No. Sellers are extremely nervous out there still, and looking at the tape, every time they tried to take this market lower, they completely failed, even when structurally it was easy for them to do so. So regardless of how overbought this market is right now, we should be thinking bullish into next week. We&rsquo;ll have some trade ideas presented later this weekend based around this bullish bias, but first:</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the SPX on the daily:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04022016/spx_daily.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04022016/spx_daily.png" alt="SPX - 2016-04-02 - Daily - Bullish - Trendline Resistance Becomes Trendline Support" /></a></p>

<p>Notice how we tried to break down, but ended up finding support at what was previously the trendline resistance. A classic look below and fail pattern - <strong>pretty bullish</strong>. First target here is the top of the range extension denoted by the top right pink box, which is around 2084, followed by the next trendline resistance at around 2090, and then the even 2100.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the SPX on the weekly:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04022016/spx_weekly.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04022016/spx_weekly.png" alt="SPX - 2016-04-02 - Weekly" /></a></p>

<p>Strong momentum.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the DJX on the weekly:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04022016/djx.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04022016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-04-02 - Weekly - Breaking Trendline Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>Again, strong momentum. It actually broke through the trendline resistance. Target here would be 180.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the NDX on the weekly:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04022016/ndx.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04022016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-04-02 - Weekly - 61.8% Fib Level Acts as Support" /></a></p>

<p>It found support off that 61.8% Fib level. Next target is that trendline resistance.</p>

<p>Finally the RUT:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04022016/rut.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/04022016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-04-02 - Weekly" /></a></p>

<p>Which looks like it may just plow through that trendline resistance, and if so, the next target would be back up to 1200.</p>

<p>Given the doubt that many have on how much higher this market can really run, but keeping in mind the bullish targets explained just above, I have a few options trade ideas that may work well just for this scenario. This will be done in a separate post which I will tweet out later this weekend, so stay tuned, and <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me</a> if you haven&rsquo;t already so that you&rsquo;ll know about it right when I tweet it out.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Important Weak Reference Points]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/31/important-weak-reference-points/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-31T21:36:53-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/31/important-weak-reference-points</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Not a lot of updates for today. For tomorrow, keep in mind the reference points pointed out a couple of days ago (those that separate the distributions):</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/03312016/es.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/03312016/es.png" alt="/ES - 2016-03-31 - Three Separate Distributions - Weak Reference Points" /></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve denoted them by the dashed blue horizontal price levels. Also keep in mind the unemployment rate and non-farm employment change data coming out tomorrow at 8:30 am EST. Those could potentially be market movers and may entice more buyers/sellers to come in.</p>

<p>I think this market has been waiting for a move lower, so if we break lower, watch for volume. That will be an indicator of if sellers are still weak out there, or if they&rsquo;re coming in strong.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s all the updates for today.</p>

<p>Also, no trade ideas planned, but I may be posting new trades live on Twitter tomorrow as I do every day, so you should be <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">following me</a> to get my updates in real-time.</p>

<p>In case you missed them, check out the <a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/trades" title="Ongoing Trades">Trades</a> page to see all ongoing trades. The <a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/history" title="Closed Trades">History</a> page shows all of our closed trades.</p>

<p>I wish you all happy trading!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What's New? Nothing. Bias Still to the Upside]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/30/whats-new-nothing-bias-still-to-the-upside/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-30T13:59:59-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/30/whats-new-nothing-bias-still-to-the-upside</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We continue to float higher:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/03302016/es.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/03302016/es.png" alt="/ES - 2016-03-30 15m Time Frame - Multiple Distributions - Gap Higher" /></a></p>

<p>Towards the beginning of today&rsquo;s session we saw a liquidation break which looked like it was going to fill the overnight gap on the /ES - that is what should&rsquo;ve happened if the Bears were really here. Unfortunately for them, all we had was a slow grind lower, which wasn&rsquo;t a convincing move (I <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive/status/715222086789111808" title="Slow Grind Lower Tweet">tweeted this out</a> as we were gradually trading lower). Not only did we snap higher, but by the end of the day, we weren&rsquo;t able to even fill the gap on the /ES.</p>

<p>What the Bears needed today was a gap down to the lowest distribution (denoted by the bottom-most blue rectangle) and build value there - that would&rsquo;ve signified a more bearish signal. Instead, not only did we <strong>not</strong> trade in the middle or top-most distribution, but price actually gapped above and traders accepted prices up at where we currently are. That&rsquo;s quite a bullish signal. On weak structure, of course. But again, don&rsquo;t fight price.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the SPX:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/03302016/spx.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/03302016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-30 Daily Time Frame - Trendline Resistance Breached" /></a></p>

<p>Our 2060 target was reached. That trendline resistance has been broken, and is now meaningless. The next target would now be around 2095.</p>

<p>DJX:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/03302016/djx.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/03302016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-03-30 Daily Time Frame - Trendline Resistance Breached" /></a></p>

<p>This closed above the trendline resistance, also rendering it useless.</p>

<p>NDX:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/03302016/ndx.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/03302016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-03-30 Daily Time Frame - Trendline Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>This is still on track to touching the trendline resistance.</p>

<p>RUT:</p>

<p><a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/03302016/rut.png"><img src="http://kenniyu.github.io/images/blog/03302016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-03-30 Daily Time Frame - Doji Consolidation" /></a></p>

<p>Closing above the 61.8% Fib level on a Doji (consolidation). This was actually quite weak today. The trendline resistance could be tagged, so look to see if we continue or reverse tomorrow.</p>

<p>By the way, that put backratio that we put on for LNKD yesterday turned out great today. For those of you who are in this trade, if you want to turn this into a 100% winner, 0% risk trade, buy the 98 put to turn the backratio into a balanced butterfly (this put option costs less than the credit we received when we put this trade on). Your max profit is reduced by the cost of this additional put that you buy, and regardless of where LNKD moves, this trade is an absolute winner. More details on LNKD on the <a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/trades" title="Ongoing Trades">Trades</a> page.</p>

<p>Once again, new trades and trade adjustments can be found daily on the <a href="http://kenniyu.github.io/trades" title="Ongoing Trades">Trades</a> page. Be sure to stay updated and <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> to follow along and see my trades in real-time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
