<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[theta trades]]></title>
  <link href="https://rocky-inlet-68994.herokuapp.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://rocky-inlet-68994.herokuapp.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-03-07T19:24:20-08:00</updated>
  <id>https://rocky-inlet-68994.herokuapp.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[theta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Keeping an Eye Out on Indices and Crude Oil]]></title>
    <link href="https://rocky-inlet-68994.herokuapp.com/blog/2016/03/07/indices/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-07T13:42:40-08:00</updated>
    <id>https://rocky-inlet-68994.herokuapp.com/blog/2016/03/07/indices</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The markets continue to grind higher, with the SPX closing today above the 61.8% fib level. The likely target is the descending trendline resistance, which should be around 2020:</p>

<p><a href="https://rocky-inlet-68994.herokuapp.com/images/blog/03072016/spx.png"><img src="https://rocky-inlet-68994.herokuapp.com/images/blog/03072016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-07 Daily Time Frame - Descending Trendline Resistance &amp; Fibonacci Retracement" /></a></p>

<p>Looking at the DJX, it has also closed above the 61.8% fib level:
<a href="https://rocky-inlet-68994.herokuapp.com/images/blog/03072016/djx.png"><img src="https://rocky-inlet-68994.herokuapp.com/images/blog/03072016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-03-07 Daily Time Frame - Descending Trendline Resistance and Fibonacci Retracement" /></a></p>

<p>Of course, the strongest of them all, RUT, grinds higher:
<a href="https://rocky-inlet-68994.herokuapp.com/images/blog/03072016/rut.png"><img src="https://rocky-inlet-68994.herokuapp.com/images/blog/03072016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-03-07 Daily Time Frame - Ascending Trendline Support as Resistance and Fibonacci Retracement" /></a></p>

<p>And then, interestingly enough the NDX, which has been having a hard time getting some love:
<a href="https://rocky-inlet-68994.herokuapp.com/images/blog/03072016/ndx.png"><img src="https://rocky-inlet-68994.herokuapp.com/images/blog/03072016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-03-07 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement" /></a></p>

<p>Whatever the case, it looks like the markets are mostly pointing to being neutral or moving higher. Unless the Bears have more confidence, this market will most likely continue to meander up here, dominated by many short term traders. Look for yesterday&rsquo;s trade idea on the market for ideas on trade location.</p>

<p>Moving over to /CL.</p>

<p><a href="https://rocky-inlet-68994.herokuapp.com/images/blog/03072016/cl_f.png"><img src="https://rocky-inlet-68994.herokuapp.com/images/blog/03072016/cl_f.png" alt="/CL - 2016-03-07 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement and Harmonic Pattern" /></a></p>

<p>/CL is approaching its previous resistance levels, as well as the 50% fib level (Oct - Feb). Furthermore, a <a href="http://www.harmonictrader.com/price_patternsabcd.htm" title="harmonic pattern">harmonic pattern AB=CD</a> could be forming again (we saw one form from last May to last August, and a completion of the pattern from last October to last month). If we do see crude oil begin to roll over, we can initiate a short position, giving us a good trade location. However, for confirmation, I&rsquo;d like to see it trade below 35 again before shorting. For now, do keep an eye out on /CL.</p>

<p>For those that are a bit more aggressive, you may consider selling a call vertical here on /CL. The MAY 42/42.5 call spread (39 DTE) is trading for .15 cr currently, or the 42/43 call spread, currently trading for .28 cr.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today, happy trading out there, and enjoy the markets tomorrow.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Bullish Play Gold]]></title>
    <link href="https://rocky-inlet-68994.herokuapp.com/blog/2016/03/06/a-bullish-play-gold/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-06T17:05:56-08:00</updated>
    <id>https://rocky-inlet-68994.herokuapp.com/blog/2016/03/06/a-bullish-play-gold</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Probably everyone and their mothers have already gotten the memo to buy Gold. I don&rsquo;t want to be jumping on the bandwagon because everyone else is, but because technical analysis points to further upside potential. Observe the chart of /GC below:</p>

<p><a href="https://rocky-inlet-68994.herokuapp.com/images/blog/03062016/gc_f_zoomed_out.png"><img src="https://rocky-inlet-68994.herokuapp.com/images/blog/03062016/gc_f_zoomed_out.png" alt="/GC" /></a></p>

<p>Gold has had a massive rally ever since the rounded bottom formed during the end of last year. On Feb 10-11 when the market double bottomed, we saw /GC put in a high, but even as the broad market rallied, /GC hasn&rsquo;t fallen much; instead, it consolidated and formed a wedge, and then towards the end of last week, it broke up and out of that wedge:</p>

<p><a href="https://rocky-inlet-68994.herokuapp.com/images/blog/03062016/gc_f_zoomed_in.png"><img src="https://rocky-inlet-68994.herokuapp.com/images/blog/03062016/gc_f_zoomed_in.png" alt="/GC" /></a></p>

<p>As such, we can expect this break out to continue to trend upwards. Any failure to maintain this new uptrend should be considered bearish, since that would be a classic &ldquo;look above and fail&rdquo; pattern.</p>

<p>For those that would like to take a theta-positive trade on this instrument, consider selling naked puts (perhaps at the 0.05 delta).</p>

<p>Another strategy that collects more premium but has upside risk is selling a strangle to finance a vertical debit call spread. One idea is to buy the 1300/1325 call spread, and finance it by selling the 1175/1375 strangle. This is currently trading for about 0.20 cr, so even after commissions, this trade can be put on for &ldquo;free.&rdquo; Here&rsquo;s the risk graph:</p>

<p><a href="https://rocky-inlet-68994.herokuapp.com/images/blog/03062016/gc_f_risk_graph.png"><img src="https://rocky-inlet-68994.herokuapp.com/images/blog/03062016/gc_f_risk_graph.png" alt="/GC" /></a></p>

<p>This trade has about a 71% probability of success, with the breakeven at 1400 to the upside (which lines up nicely with a previous horizontal resistance) and a bit below 1175 to the downside. Management is key here, as risk is unlimited - make sure to roll up/down and out in duration if the strikes are being threatened.</p>

<p>You can also consider legging into this position, if you believe that /GC will make a quick run up first. In that case, consider selling the naked put and buying the call spread, but leaving the naked call to be placed at a later time. Finding the right credit for these setups may be harder, but if you have the edge of technical analysis, you may not always need to place trades for a credit initially.</p>

<p>As always, stay small, and trade safely.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Market Outlook - Will the Short Squeeze Continue]]></title>
    <link href="https://rocky-inlet-68994.herokuapp.com/blog/2016/03/06/market-outlook-will-the-short-squeeze-continue/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-06T09:16:35-08:00</updated>
    <id>https://rocky-inlet-68994.herokuapp.com/blog/2016/03/06/market-outlook-will-the-short-squeeze-continue</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For the past 6 weeks, the SPX has been rallying almost non-stop from the double-bottom lows. Last week, I wasn&rsquo;t convinced that we would see a follow through in the Bulls, but after the Bears failed to take this market lower on Monday, we only got more short squeeze action, and the Bulls remained in charge.</p>

<p><a href="https://rocky-inlet-68994.herokuapp.com/images/blog/03062016/spx.png"><img src="https://rocky-inlet-68994.herokuapp.com/images/blog/03062016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-06 Daily Timeframe Fibonaccis" /></a></p>

<p>Last Friday, SPX closed at the 61.8% fib retracement level. Will we continue to see a rally, or will we turn here? There are many factors leading me to think that the market will turn lower at this point - I&rsquo;ll first argue the Bear case:
1. The market has been extremely overextended to the upside, and almost every rally has been built on poor structure
2. The recent rallying has been closely tied to crude, and crude is coming up to major resistance levels
3. Friday&rsquo;s late day selloff was a bit unusual (usually on a short-squeezing day, we see the action continue all the way to the closing bell) and lends support to the fact that:
5. There is major overhead supply above us; path of least resistance is to the downside
6. Overall fundamentals have not changed</p>

<p>But, I&rsquo;ll also argue the other Bull case - we can continue to see higher prices:
1. Looking at the SPX chart above, a full extension of the W pattern goes as high as 2080 (though we may not see that target to be fully reached due to multiple trendline resistances along the way)
2. Though Friday&rsquo;s late day selloff was unusual, the longer term players usually don&rsquo;t wait until near the closing bell to sell a market
3. Liquidation breaks strengthen the market, and we had one on Friday morning
4. The RUT is the strongest out of all the indices and has not reached the 61.8% fib level (Dec - Feb). The NDX also closed above the 50% fib level (Dec - Feb), but has not reached the 61.8%</p>

<p>Although the edge is to the Bears here, any upside continuation may only cause more shorts to be nervous.</p>

<p>Looking at all the other major indices, the RUT is the strongest and doesn&rsquo;t look like it&rsquo;ll be pulling back, as the 61.8% fib level hasn&rsquo;t been reached, yet:
<a href="https://rocky-inlet-68994.herokuapp.com/images/blog/03062016/rut.png"><img src="https://rocky-inlet-68994.herokuapp.com/images/blog/03062016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-03-06 Daily Timeframe Fibonaccis" /></a></p>

<p>The NDX had balancing action over the past 3 trading days (2 hammers, 1 doji). It&rsquo;s currently sitting just a bit above the 50% fib level (Dec - Feb). A break out of balance to either side would most likely result in violent moves in that direction.
<a href="https://rocky-inlet-68994.herokuapp.com/images/blog/03062016/ndx.png"><img src="https://rocky-inlet-68994.herokuapp.com/images/blog/03062016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-03-06 Daily Timeframe Fibonaccis" /></a></p>

<p>The DJX peaked above the 61.8% fib level, but closed underneath it:
<a href="https://rocky-inlet-68994.herokuapp.com/images/blog/03062016/djx.png"><img src="https://rocky-inlet-68994.herokuapp.com/images/blog/03062016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-03-06 Daily Timeframe Fibonaccis" /></a></p>

<p>With that, I&rsquo;ll leave you with a couple of trade ideas. These are mostly bearish plays, as is my current bias.</p>

<p>For a bearish play on the SPX: knowing that the peak of the extension from the W pattern is around 2080, we can place the APR 2080/2100 bear call spread (currently priced for about 3.00 cr). This trade has a 92% probability of success, and should be managed to avoid taking the max loss (consider rolling out in time for duration once the short strike is threatened). If the margin requirement on SPX is too much, consider the 208/210 bear call on the SPY - adjust the lot size as you see fit.</p>

<p>Another trade idea that is bearish, but also allows room for bullishness: we can sell the APR 206/208 call ratio spread on the SPY for about a 0.12 credit. If the market does in fact roll over, we win. But if not, and if it grinds higher and hovers around our 208 resistance area by expiration, even better. Our breakeven to the upside is 210.12, with a 93% win rate, and a max profit of 2.12 per spread. Adjust lot size as you see fit.</p>

<p>More direct, bullish plays here with credits are a bit hard to put on right now. IV is low, and any downmove will inflate our premium, which will most likely hurt us, so I caution against putting those on.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for this week&rsquo;s outlook. I&rsquo;ll be posting updates as the week progresses. Good luck, and happy trading.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Beginning Steps]]></title>
    <link href="https://rocky-inlet-68994.herokuapp.com/blog/2016/03/06/beginning-steps/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-06T00:49:05-08:00</updated>
    <id>https://rocky-inlet-68994.herokuapp.com/blog/2016/03/06/beginning-steps</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is the beginning of my personal investing blog.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ll be tracking my journey in trading as closely as I can, reviewing my progress and always bettering myself. I&rsquo;ll also be posting trade ideas and monitoring ongoing positions that I have in the market.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
