<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: ung | theta trades]]></title>
  <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/categories/ung/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-03-30T14:21:40-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[theta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Expecting a Turnaround Very Soon]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/21/expecting-a-turnaround-very-soon/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-21T19:05:51-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/21/expecting-a-turnaround-very-soon</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We continue to grind higher.</p>

<p>SPX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03212016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03212016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-21 Daily Time Frame - Target 2060 - Gap Fill" /></a></p>

<p>The 2060 target mentioned for a while now is just within reach. Due to the slowing momentum, I&rsquo;m looking to enter into a 2100/2110 short call vertical spread on the SPX, currently going for 1.70 cr once that trendline is reached and we exhibit signs of a turnaround.</p>

<p>DJX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03212016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03212016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-03-21 Daily Time Frame - Trendline Resistance Tag" /></a></p>

<p>We tagged the trendline resistance today. I am expecting this to stall around here, while the SPX climbs higher to tag its trendline.</p>

<p>NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03212016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03212016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-03-21 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement" /></a></p>

<p>We crossed the 61.8% fib level today, so the next level of resistance is the trendline resistance. However, given the slowing momentum we have in all of the other indices, I don&rsquo;t expect NDX to actually reach that trendline resistance on this run.</p>

<p>RUT:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03212016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/03212016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-03-21 Daily Time Frame - Trendline Support" /></a></p>

<p>The RUT was the weakest of the bunch today, closing down, but still above the trendline support. We&rsquo;ll need to see more follow-through to the upside if the market were truly bullish, but that may be a bit hard given how much we&rsquo;ve come off from the lows, and also the fact that there is a 61.8% fib level there as well. I do expect some stalling to occur here, but keep an eye out on this, as we could easily fall below that support, making for a classic look-above-and-fail pattern.</p>

<p>The upcoming week is key and will most likely determine whether or not we get the retracement in the market that many, including me, have been looking for. Keep your eyes peeled.</p>

<p>In the meantime, for those that followed me on Twitter, here is the trade we got filled on today:</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">It&#39;s breaking support. BOT BUTTERFLY <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24AMZN&amp;src=ctag">$AMZN</a> 100 APR 16 480/475/465 PUT @-.17</p>&mdash; theta (@theta_positive) <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive/status/711923212490121216">March 21, 2016</a></blockquote>


<script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>


<p>And the risk profile per spread:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03212016/amzn_risk_profile.png"><img src="/images/blog/03212016/amzn_risk_profile.png" alt="AMZN - 2016-03-21 Daily Time Frame - Unbalanced Butterfly Risk Profile" /></a></p>

<p>Looking at the chart of AMZN on the daily:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03212016/amzn.png"><img src="/images/blog/03212016/amzn.png" alt="AMZN - 2016-03-21 Daily Time Frame - Approximate Support" /></a></p>

<p>I expect us to find some support around the prior lows in the area of about 475 to 500. Because I didn&rsquo;t have a specific target in mind, only an approximate area, plus the fact that I think we&rsquo;ll stall around there, a theta-positive, risk-defined trade here may not be such a bad idea. If we aren&rsquo;t able to clearly break support (which we couldn&rsquo;t by the end of today, we actually had a look-below-and-fail) and we end up moving higher, we still make money. As for trade management, since we don&rsquo;t want to take on the max loss here, we&rsquo;ll be looking to manage if AMZN does indeed fall down hard.</p>

<p>Also, given how UNG closed today, I think we are in for another leg lower, and the measured target would be 5.61:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03212016/ung.png"><img src="/images/blog/03212016/ung.png" alt="UNG - 2016-03-21 Daily Time Frame - Trendline Resistance, Fibonacci Extension" /></a></p>

<p>I would like to see us break the lows of 5.78 first, though. As for the entry point, looking at the chart on an intraday basis, a break below 6.4 should trigger us into the short:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03212016/ung_short_entry.png"><img src="/images/blog/03212016/ung_short_entry.png" alt="UNG - 2016-03-21 Hourly Time Frame - Short Entry Point" /></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m looking to sell the APR5 6.5 call and buy the APR5 6 put for about .17 cr. Look out for my tweet on this.</p>

<p>Last, but not least, HD:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03212016/hd.png"><img src="/images/blog/03212016/hd.png" alt="HD - 2016-03-21 Daily Time Frame - Channel Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>I completely got sidetracked by work while an entry was available here today - unfortunately it seems like we&rsquo;re no longer able to get a credit for putting on the 133/135 call backratio right now (currently going for .09 debit). I&rsquo;ll continue monitoring this for a good entry, and I&rsquo;ll post it live on Twitter as well.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets tomorrow, and <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive/">follow me on Twitter</a> to get my updates in real-time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Grandma Yellen Stepping to the Mic]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/15/grandma-yellen-stepping-to-the-mic/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-15T23:49:16-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/15/grandma-yellen-stepping-to-the-mic</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We&rsquo;re in a holding pattern, as Janet Yellen is stepping up to the mic tomorrow, so watch out for movements afterwards, and stay on the sidelines in the meantime.</p>

<p>Trade idea that triggered last night was the AUD/JPY. I&rsquo;m still waiting on UNG to go a bit higher before shorting. <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive/">Follow me on Twitter</a> to get my real-time updates on my entries and positions.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[More Trade Ideas]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/14/more-trade-ideas/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-14T17:49:12-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/14/more-trade-ideas</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday I mentioned a possible long/short trade on AUD/JPY depending on how we close today. Unfortunately for the Bull case, we weren&rsquo;t able to close above that lower price level. Still for the Bear case, I&rsquo;d like to see us breach the 85 level before initiating a short, so this is still a wait-and-see.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03142016/aud_jpy.png"><img src="/images/blog/03142016/aud_jpy.png" alt="AUD/JPY - 2016-03-14 Daily Time Frame " /></a></p>

<p>I also mentioned shorting natural gas if UNG floats up to the price level shown here:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03142016/ung.png"><img src="/images/blog/03142016/ung.png" alt="UNG - 2016-03-14 Daily Time Frame" /></a></p>

<p>We did not get that today, so this is also still a wait-and-see.</p>

<p>Looking at /GC, we&rsquo;ve stalled since ECB, and we&rsquo;re currently testing some trendline support levels:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03142016/gc_f.png"><img src="/images/blog/03142016/gc_f.png" alt="/GC - 2016-03-14 Daily Time Frame - Target 1200 Support" /></a></p>

<p>If we do break lower, I&rsquo;d imagine the next level of support is around 1200, and if so, we could easily reach that target within the next 2 weeks. One trade idea here is the 1210/1200/1185 unbalanced butterfly:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03142016/gc_f_risk_graph.png"><img src="/images/blog/03142016/gc_f_risk_graph.png" alt="/GC Risk Graph - 1210/1200/1185 Put Unbalanced Butterfly - Max Profit at 1200" /></a></p>

<p>This trade can basically be put on for free or even for a credit, but will need to be managed in case gold does plunge back down hard. I will be monitoring /GC and will be tweeting out my entry.</p>

<p>Another one is BIDU:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03142016/bidu.png"><img src="/images/blog/03142016/bidu.png" alt="BIDU - 2016-03-14 Daily Time Frame - Topping-Tail Hammer" /></a></p>

<p>Below 178.92 is a short, but I&rsquo;ll be watching FXI for follow through as well:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03142016/fxi.png"><img src="/images/blog/03142016/fxi.png" alt="FXI - 2016-03-14 Daily Time Frame - Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>If FXI stalls at that resistance, I&rsquo;ll be looking to sell some call spreads on BIDU. One trade idea is the 200/205 call spread, currently going for 1.03 cr.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today. <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive/">Follow me on Twitter</a> to get my real-time updates on my entries and positions.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Commodity and Volatility Play]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/13/commodity-and-volatility-play/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-13T12:18:23-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/13/commodity-and-volatility-play</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Natural gas has been one of the commodities that just can&rsquo;t seem to get it up. Observe the chart below:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03132016/ung.png"><img src="/images/blog/03132016/ung.png" alt="UNG - Natural Gas - 2016-03-13 Daily Time Frame - Trendline Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>A good place to short this commodity would be at the horizontal price level, so wait for a bit more of a retracement higher before entering. If we do turn lower before getting up there, then we&rsquo;ll have missed out, but our risk/reward would have been better as well.</p>

<p>My favorite currency pair to look at for market volatility opportunities is the AUD/JPY:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03132016/aud_jpy.png"><img src="/images/blog/03132016/aud_jpy.png" alt="AUD/JPY - Australian Dollar / Japanese Yen - 2016-03-13 Daily Time Frame - Trendline Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>When volatility starts picking up, look for the AUD to weaken and the JPY to strengthen. This pair should head lower if we do start to see volatility increase. If AUD/JPY starts to roll over, then the first target would be 85, then 83.3, and then 82. But if we continue to see strength in the markets, this pair can break into the region bounded by the two horizontal price levels. Look for the strength of the breakout and the tempo in the equities market as well as confirmation to enter, with a tight stop just below the lower price level - the 85.61 from the highs of Thursday&rsquo;s session would be a good place.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ll be looking to enter these trades. If you&rsquo;d like to keep up with my trades in real time, <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive/">follow me on Twitter</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
