<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: cognitive dissonance | theta trades]]></title>
  <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/categories/cognitive-dissonance/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-03-12T20:48:19-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[theta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Further Upside Expected]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/11/further-upside-expected/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-11T18:45:36-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/11/further-upside-expected</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m expecting further upside in the market.</p>

<p>Yesterday after the ECB announcement, traders attempted to push the market lower but were unable to do so. We looked below balance, failed, made a poor low, and then came back into balance. Then this morning, we gapped up, but with the internals so strong, no chance of a gap fade play was available, and we continued to ratchet higher.</p>

<p>This is a very bullish signal, regardless of how overbought the conditions are. Here&rsquo;s the current SPX chart:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03112016/spx_daily.png"><img src="/images/blog/03112016/spx_daily.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-11 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement, Trendline Resistance, Range Extension" /></a></p>

<p>For those that took a bullish stance on the market during that time, congratulations. In the first SPX chart that I posted a couple of weeks back, I outlined the potential range extension we could see as possible target areas (via the pink rectangles). This week, not only did we break the 61.8% fib level, but we&rsquo;ve also broken the trendline resistance connected by the tops of November and December 2015. I believe we&rsquo;re headed to 2060. So if you&rsquo;re long, continue to hold that position.</p>

<p>Zooming out and taking a look at the market on the weekly:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03112016/spx_weekly.png"><img src="/images/blog/03112016/spx_weekly.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-11 Weekly Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement, Trendline Resistance, Range Extension, Bottoming-Tail Hammer" /></a></p>

<p>Notice the bottoming tail hammer that formed. I count many weekly bars from before that ended with a higher close the following week.</p>

<p>The same bullishness can be seen in the Dow:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03112016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03112016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-03-11 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement, Trendline Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>We&rsquo;re approaching the trendline resistance here as well. Look for a short there. As a side note, DJX has also put in a bottoming-tail hammer on the weekly chart.</p>

<p>For the NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03112016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03112016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-03-11 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement" /></a></p>

<p>A little bit weaker here, as we have not tagged the 61.8% fib level, yet. Still, this has also put in a bottoming-tail hammer on the weekly chart.</p>

<p>Finally the RUT:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03112016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/03112016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-03-11 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement, Trendline Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>Though it exhibited a lot of weakness a couple of days ago, keep in mind it has come off really high from the lows. It looks like it&rsquo;ll break that trendline resistance, and if it does, that&rsquo;ll suggest more short-covering to come.</p>

<p>That about wraps it up for the week going on to next week. I&rsquo;d just like to finish with another note:</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m not bullish on the market - I think the fundamentals are complete garbage, and I think we&rsquo;ll see a crash like we&rsquo;ve never seen before. However, I can&rsquo;t let my biases blind me from seeing the opportunities out there. Instead of falling prey to cognitive dissonance, we can separate our bias and take advantage of these opportunities as they come.</p>

<p>Enjoy the weekend, and good luck to everyone, bull or bear.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
