<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: market recap | ThetaTrades]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/categories/market-recap/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-02-16T22:14:03-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[theta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Value Building Higher]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/14/value-building-higher/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-14T21:38:50-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/14/value-building-higher</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Market remains strong as value builds higher:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04142016/esm6.png"><img src="/images/blog/04142016/esm6.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-04-14 - Market Profile - 20d Zoomed In" /></a></p>

<p>We were able to hold above the balance area for the second trading session after the breakout. Stay with the trend, and that is up. Any kind of a pullback on not-so-bearish internals can be considered buy points, as short term traders are still the most dominant traders out there in terms of price action. 2067 would be that point.</p>

<p>We are at some very interesting points in the broad market indices, so just wanted to briefly present them.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the SPX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04142016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04142016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-04-14 - Daily" /></a></p>

<p>We&rsquo;re just about 10 points away from 2092 on the SPX, which would be the trendline resistance point by tomorrow. As mentioned yesterday, we expected a consolidation day today, and that is exactly what we got today, that Doji. Watch for either a continuation or a reversal tomorrow.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the DJX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04142016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04142016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-04-14 - Daily" /></a></p>

<p>We just barely tagged the high from back in November, closing on a spinning top. Again, watch for a continuation or a reversal tomorrow.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04142016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04142016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-04-14 - Daily" /></a></p>

<p>Very similar here as it&rsquo;s also closing today on a Doji like the SPX after tagging that trendline resistance.</p>

<p>And the RUT:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04142016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/04142016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-04-14 - Daily" /></a></p>

<p>Touching that trendline resistance today and closing on a spinning top.</p>

<p>These are all very similar patterns across all the indices, so we shall see how this all plays out tomorrow.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today. I&rsquo;ll keep posting new entries/adjustments on Twitter, so be sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> to get all of my updates in real time.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets and good trading!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Breaking out of Balance]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/13/breaking-out-of-balance/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-13T18:18:12-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/13/breaking-out-of-balance</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The market broke out of balance very clearly today to the upside as we mentioned yesterday:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04132016/esm6.png"><img src="/images/blog/04132016/esm6.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-04-13 - Market Profile - 15d Zoomed In" /></a></p>

<p>We attempted to trade back below balance, but failed as buyers kept the market up.</p>

<p>On the SPX, we now have clearance to tag the uppermost trendline resistance this Friday at around 2090.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04132016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04132016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-04-13 - Trendline Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>Also, from now on for the SPX chart, the pink rectangles will be removed - the target here has been reached.</p>

<p>Watch for the top of the balance area to hold as support, because we can just as easily fail tomorrow and fall back into the balance area, which is not a strong Bullish signal. If that&rsquo;s the case, I&rsquo;ll be looking for a rotation all the way back down to the bottom of the balance area (2012) as a weekly play. However, tomorrow, I&rsquo;m looking for some consolidation before any moves higher.</p>

<p>One of the plays that I&rsquo;m looking at currently is the SPY MAY2/APR5 211/210 Diagonal Call spread, currently going for about .26 debit:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04132016/spy_call_diagonal.png"><img src="/images/blog/04132016/spy_call_diagonal.png" alt="SPY Diagonal Call Spread - 2016-04-13 - Risk Graph" /></a></p>

<p>This has breakevens at around 206 and 212 over the next few weeks. Given the low volatility that we&rsquo;ve been having and the low confidence in any downmove, as long as we stay in this range, we should be good to milk some premium. I&rsquo;ll be looking to put this on tomorrow.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today. I&rsquo;ll keep posting new entries/adjustments on Twitter, so be sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> to get all of my updates in real time.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets and good trading!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Preparing for a Breakout]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/09/preparing-for-a-breakout/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-09T13:26:26-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/09/preparing-for-a-breakout</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This market has been consolidating in a big balance area for a while now, with the volume POC for the past 15 days at around the 2040.75 level in the /ES:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04092016/esm6.png"><img src="/images/blog/04092016/esm6.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-04-09 - Market Profile" /></a></p>

<p>The composite doesn&rsquo;t look quite skewed in any direction, so I would say we&rsquo;re right in the middle of this entire balance area between 2012 and 2067.</p>

<p>Keep in mind 2012 goes back to a spike high from March 16 (refer to <a href="/blog/2016/03/18/the-most-dangerous-aspect-of-the-recent-rally/" title="Weak Reference Points">this post for more info</a> ), as well as a <em>close</em> touch of that point back in March 24. Keep this weak reference point in mind going forward.</p>

<p>Short term traders continue to be the dominant players here, getting themselves overly long or overly short. Until we see some bigger players come into play and break us out of balance, assume that we trade within the denoted range.</p>

<p>Overall, momentum in the board market indices does look like it is slowing and rounding off. My bias here is still neutral, and with such low IV, it doesn&rsquo;t make sense to be selling premium. If you have a directional bias and you&rsquo;re bearish, selling calls might not be a bad idea. Personally, I&rsquo;d want to be buying cheap OOM calendar spreads.</p>

<p>We haven&rsquo;t really traded options on the indices in a while, but here&rsquo;s a trade idea on the SPY utilizing an OOM put calendar:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04092016/spy_put_calendar.png"><img src="/images/blog/04092016/spy_put_calendar.png" alt="SPY - 2016-04-09 - Put Calendar Risk Graph" /></a></p>

<p>We&rsquo;d like SPY to trade between 190 and 202 by expiration. Adjust strikes as necessary. If you want to collect a credit, you can think about moving the nearer term strike higher.</p>

<p>A simple call credit spread on the SPY is also not a bad idea. I may be looking to put some on this coming week, depending on conditions.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m also thinking about a Bullish play on AMZN:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04092016/amzn.png"><img src="/images/blog/04092016/amzn.png" alt="AMZN - 2016-04-09 - Daily - Sitting at Horizontal Support" /></a></p>

<p>AMZN is holding up at the horizontal support level and the upward trendline support level. One of the things I&rsquo;m looking to do is put on a call condor on AMZN that includes the earnings cycle, obviously as an earnings play. I&rsquo;ll also be looking to finance this condor by selling put spreads beneath trendline support for the weeks prior to earnings, as long as the market continues to stay in balance. The reason I&rsquo;m thinking about putting on this trade is that if the market does continue to stay in balance or climb higher, AMZN usually won&rsquo;t sell off and may even climb higher as well into earnings.</p>

<p>Currently the APR5 660/670/690/700 call condor is being priced in for about .89 debit:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04092016/amzn_call_condor.png"><img src="/images/blog/04092016/amzn_call_condor.png" alt="AMZN - 2016-04-09 - Call Condor Risk Graph" /></a></p>

<p>I might buy a few of these. These and the put spreads will need to be managed if AMZN starts to lose the support levels.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ll be looking to put on these trades come Monday, so <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> to get my updates. And to make the most out of Twitter, make sure you turn on notifications specifically from me. Just visit my Twitter profile on mobile, select the Settings gear, and then select the option to turn on notifications.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for the weekend update - enjoy the weekend, and good trading on Monday!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[More Low Confidence]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/06/more-consolidation/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-06T19:08:41-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/06/more-consolidation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Market continues to consolidate here. As I mentioned yesterday, I just didn&rsquo;t see enough sellers, and that spells low confidence.</p>

<p>Looking at the SPX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04062016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04062016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-04-06 - Daily - Look-Above-And-Fail" /></a></p>

<p>Yesterday&rsquo;s look-above-and-fail pattern failed, and now we&rsquo;re back up above the trendline support. All of this just spells low confidence.</p>

<p>DJX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04062016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04062016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-04-06 - Daily - Bounced off Trendline Support" /></a></p>

<p>Couldn&rsquo;t continue lower after testing the support. Once again, consolidating just above the trendline support.</p>

<p>NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04062016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04062016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-04-06 - Daily - Seller Shutoff" /></a></p>

<p>We&rsquo;re still consolidating here, though we have a wide body candle.</p>

<p>RUT:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04062016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/04062016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-04-06 - Daily - Bullish Engulfing" /></a></p>

<p>We&rsquo;re now back up above the 61.8% Fib level - again, this spells low confidence. When a price level is traded through many times, it&rsquo;s not a sign of trend confidence, but rather a sign of consolidation, or low confidence.</p>

<p>Today, we put on a couple of new trades, specifically calendar spreads in CMG and EEM. We also made some adjustments to our TSLA position (currently our worst trade so far) and closed out our AAPL calendar (at a profit). Check them out in the <a href="/trades" title="Ongoing Trades">Trades</a> page. If you want to be notified when I enter, adjust, or exit trades, make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> so you can receive my updates in real-time. Again, to make the most out of Twitter, make sure you turn on notifications specifically from me. Just visit my Twitter profile on the mobile app, select the Settings gear, and select the <em>Turn on Notifications</em> option.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today. Good luck in the markets tomorrow!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Choppy Market with Low Volume]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/03/28/choppy-market-with-low-volume/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-28T18:36:41-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/03/28/choppy-market-with-low-volume</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We continue to chop and grind here on low volume. Nothing interesting happening here that I haven&rsquo;t mentioned before. All of the charts pretty much look the same as Friday, but I&rsquo;ll post them here again.</p>

<p>SPX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03282016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03282016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-28 Daily Time Frame - Target 2060" /></a></p>

<p>DJX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03282016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03282016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-03-28 Daily Time Frame - Trendline Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03282016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03282016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-03-28 Daily Time Frame" /></a></p>

<p>RUT:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03282016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/03282016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-03-28 Daily Time Frame" /></a></p>

<p>If you&rsquo;ve been following me on Twitter, you&rsquo;ll know that we got filled on these trades today:</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">SOLD 1/-1/2 CUSTOM <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24EWZ&amp;src=ctag">$EWZ</a> 100 MAY 16/MAY 16/MAY 16 30/25/22.5 CALL/PUT/PUT @.59</p>&mdash; theta (@theta_positive) <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive/status/714445062352949248">March 28, 2016</a></blockquote>


<script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>




<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">BOT BUTTERFLY <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24PCLN&amp;src=ctag">$PCLN</a> 100 (Weeklys) APR1 16 1230/1220/1205 PUT @.15 (Opening)</p>&mdash; theta (@theta_positive) <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive/status/714540072947744768">March 28, 2016</a></blockquote>


<script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>


<p>Also, we got filled on a closing order today on PCLN:</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Booking another winner: #1617415600, BOT VERTICAL <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24PCLN&amp;src=ctag">$PCLN</a> 100 APR 16 1375/1380 CALL @.48</p>&mdash; theta (@theta_positive) <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive/status/714470002909315072">March 28, 2016</a></blockquote>


<script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>


<p>Congratulations if you took that trade with me!</p>

<p>The other trades currently look good still. To see the most recent risk graphs on our open positions, check out the <a href="/trades" title="Trades">Trades page</a>. If you&rsquo;re interested in the trades we&rsquo;ve closed, check out the <a href="/history" title="History">History page</a>.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ll leave you with one trade idea for tomorrow. We&rsquo;ve been putting on quite some trades, so its wise we have time each day to manage each as necessary (though not a lot of management has been necessary so far for many of our trades).</p>

<p>Anyway, here&rsquo;s a trade idea on LNKD:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03282016/lnkd.png"><img src="/images/blog/03282016/lnkd.png" alt="LNKD - 2016-03-28 Range-Bound" /></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m expecting for the stock to slowly grind lower or meander in between the 100 to 125 price range. If it does manage to get down to 100, I&rsquo;m expecting a bounce to occur, as it has been a while since we&rsquo;ve tested that prior support level. Because of these reasons, I think a put backratio would allow us to capture profits on a slow move down, as well as any moves up. Here is the 105/102 put backratio in APR:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03282016/lnkd_risk_graph.png"><img src="/images/blog/03282016/lnkd_risk_graph.png" alt="LNKD Risk Graph - 2016-03-28 Put Backratio" /></a></p>

<p>We have big downside risk, so management is key here. We may be able to turn this into a cheap butterfly later as well, so stay tuned.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s all for today. If you haven&rsquo;t yet, make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> to receive my trade entries and adjustments in real time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
