<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: trade ideas | ThetaTrades]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/categories/trade-ideas/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-02-27T22:29:44-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[theta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Potential Upside Plays]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/03/potential-upside-plays/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-03T21:34:10-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/03/potential-upside-plays</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been looking at a couple of trade setups given the bullish follow-through I&rsquo;m expecting this coming week and the lack of bearishness out there.</p>

<p>First is GS:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04032016/gs.png"><img src="/images/blog/04032016/gs.png" alt="GS - 2016-04-03 - Daily - Trendline Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>We&rsquo;ve currently put in a rounded-bottom / inverted head-and-shoulders pattern, and on Friday it appears that we&rsquo;re just breaking out of that right shoulder. If we continue to see bullishness, GS has room to run up to the trendline resistance. This should bring us to about 177 by the time of their earnings. As I&rsquo;m expecting a short term run up, this could make for a (slightly aggressive) potential options play:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04032016/gs_risk_reversal.png"><img src="/images/blog/04032016/gs_risk_reversal.png" alt="GS - 2016-04-03 - Bull Call Spread Financed by Put Backratio" /></a></p>

<p>We&rsquo;ll buy a slightly OOM call vertical and finance it by selling a put backratio with 11 days to go. We&rsquo;re currently getting a credit for this, but of course this will have to be priced again on Monday.</p>

<p>For those that are a bit more conservative and would like more room for error in case we do have a downside move, consider a longer term play that <em>includes</em> the earnings cycle:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04032016/gs_batman.png"><img src="/images/blog/04032016/gs_batman.png" alt="GS - 2016-04-03 - Put Backratio With Call Backratio" /></a></p>

<p>Your range of profit potential is wide, with the peaks denoting the max profits (about $500 per spread). With pretty wide breakevens, and the fact that GS doesn&rsquo;t usually move much from earnings, this is a safer approach that could help you profit from either a move up to the 175 area which is near the trendline resistance, or down to the 140 area which is near prior support levels. I personally like this trade more, as we have duration to help us out, too, in case we&rsquo;re wrong on direction.</p>

<p>Another idea is the SPY:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04032016/spy_diagonal.png"><img src="/images/blog/04032016/spy_diagonal.png" alt="SPY - 2016-04-03 - Diagonal Call Spread" /></a></p>

<p>This is not a short term trade, but one that has a wide breakeven as well by expiration. If you don&rsquo;t expect the SPY to move past 211 by the next few weeks, or if you expect it to slowly grind higher, a cheap diagonal here could be the play.</p>

<p>These are just a couple of ideas that I&rsquo;m looking to put on for Monday - they may be adjusted slightly depending on how the market opens on Monday and where things are priced. I will tweet out the exact trade that I put on in real time, though. Make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> and turn on notifications from me to get my posts in real time (no I don&rsquo;t post pictures of cats or food - no spam, just trades only).</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for now - good luck, and let&rsquo;s have another week of good trading.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Choppy Market with Low Volume]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/03/28/choppy-market-with-low-volume/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-28T18:36:41-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/03/28/choppy-market-with-low-volume</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We continue to chop and grind here on low volume. Nothing interesting happening here that I haven&rsquo;t mentioned before. All of the charts pretty much look the same as Friday, but I&rsquo;ll post them here again.</p>

<p>SPX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03282016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03282016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-28 Daily Time Frame - Target 2060" /></a></p>

<p>DJX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03282016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03282016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-03-28 Daily Time Frame - Trendline Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03282016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03282016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-03-28 Daily Time Frame" /></a></p>

<p>RUT:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03282016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/03282016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-03-28 Daily Time Frame" /></a></p>

<p>If you&rsquo;ve been following me on Twitter, you&rsquo;ll know that we got filled on these trades today:</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">SOLD 1/-1/2 CUSTOM <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24EWZ&amp;src=ctag">$EWZ</a> 100 MAY 16/MAY 16/MAY 16 30/25/22.5 CALL/PUT/PUT @.59</p>&mdash; theta (@theta_positive) <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive/status/714445062352949248">March 28, 2016</a></blockquote>


<script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>




<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">BOT BUTTERFLY <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24PCLN&amp;src=ctag">$PCLN</a> 100 (Weeklys) APR1 16 1230/1220/1205 PUT @.15 (Opening)</p>&mdash; theta (@theta_positive) <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive/status/714540072947744768">March 28, 2016</a></blockquote>


<script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>


<p>Also, we got filled on a closing order today on PCLN:</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Booking another winner: #1617415600, BOT VERTICAL <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24PCLN&amp;src=ctag">$PCLN</a> 100 APR 16 1375/1380 CALL @.48</p>&mdash; theta (@theta_positive) <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive/status/714470002909315072">March 28, 2016</a></blockquote>


<script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>


<p>Congratulations if you took that trade with me!</p>

<p>The other trades currently look good still. To see the most recent risk graphs on our open positions, check out the <a href="/trades" title="Trades">Trades page</a>. If you&rsquo;re interested in the trades we&rsquo;ve closed, check out the <a href="/history" title="History">History page</a>.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ll leave you with one trade idea for tomorrow. We&rsquo;ve been putting on quite some trades, so its wise we have time each day to manage each as necessary (though not a lot of management has been necessary so far for many of our trades).</p>

<p>Anyway, here&rsquo;s a trade idea on LNKD:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03282016/lnkd.png"><img src="/images/blog/03282016/lnkd.png" alt="LNKD - 2016-03-28 Range-Bound" /></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m expecting for the stock to slowly grind lower or meander in between the 100 to 125 price range. If it does manage to get down to 100, I&rsquo;m expecting a bounce to occur, as it has been a while since we&rsquo;ve tested that prior support level. Because of these reasons, I think a put backratio would allow us to capture profits on a slow move down, as well as any moves up. Here is the 105/102 put backratio in APR:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03282016/lnkd_risk_graph.png"><img src="/images/blog/03282016/lnkd_risk_graph.png" alt="LNKD Risk Graph - 2016-03-28 Put Backratio" /></a></p>

<p>We have big downside risk, so management is key here. We may be able to turn this into a cheap butterfly later as well, so stay tuned.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s all for today. If you haven&rsquo;t yet, make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> to receive my trade entries and adjustments in real time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bias Remains to the Upside Currently]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/03/26/bias-remains-to-the-upside-currently/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-26T17:38:12-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/03/26/bias-remains-to-the-upside-currently</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Remember this chart from last Friday?</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03182016/esm6_thurs_fri.png"><img src="/images/blog/03182016/esm6_thurs_fri.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-03-18 Hourly Time Frame - Single Prints Separating Distributions as Weak Reference Points" /></a></p>

<p>If you missed the explanation of what these reference points mean, <a href="/blog/2016/03/18/the-most-dangerous-aspect-of-the-recent-rally/" title="/ES Weak Reference Points">please take a look</a>.</p>

<p>Prior to Thursday&rsquo;s action, I was thinking that perhaps this could be the turning point for the Bears to step in and take the market back lower. However, from Thursday&rsquo;s action:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03262016/es_f.png"><img src="/images/blog/03262016/es_f.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-03-18 Hourly Time Frame - Bias Continues to Upside" /></a></p>

<p>We came close to the 2012 level, and instead of taking out that weak reference point, we bounced off hard and the Bulls took the market back up to fill the gap between Wednesday and Thursday. So the way we edge lower has me thinking that we will test 2060 soon on the SPX and possibly take that out and move higher to about 2090.</p>

<p>At the same time, value built lower on Thursday because most of the time was spent trading around 2016 on the /ES. And while we did finish the day filling the gap, late day rallies (and selloffs) are usually suspect and unsustainable. So Bulls, don&rsquo;t get too excited here. Keep value in mind, and don&rsquo;t be fooled by price (don&rsquo;t fight it, either).</p>

<p>Shorter term time frame traders are still dominating here, and structure remains weak. The only way the edge will shift to the Bears is if we take out that 2012 level (basically Thursday&rsquo;s low). After that, look for the next weak low at 1995 to be taken out.</p>

<p>Until then, bias still remains to the upside.</p>

<p>Taking a look at the SPX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03262016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03262016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-26 Daily Time Frame - Target 2060" /></a></p>

<p>As mentioned earlier, I believe the 2060 target is not out of play and may be reached soon. Looking at the other indices, I think we may consolidate there more before moving higher, which makes for a possible trade here which I&rsquo;ll show below.</p>

<p>DJX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03262016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03262016/djx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-26 Daily Time Frame - Target 2060" /></a></p>

<p>Same comment as the SPX.</p>

<p>NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03262016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03262016/ndx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-26 Daily Time Frame - Target 2060" /></a></p>

<p>Still under the 61.8% fib level, which doesn&rsquo;t mean much as a resistance level given how much we&rsquo;ve traded back and forth between this level.</p>

<p>RUT:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03262016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/03262016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-03-26 Daily Time Frame - Target 2060" /></a></p>

<p>The 61.8 fib level is still in play here as resistance.</p>

<p>Ok, trade ideas:</p>

<p>Because I&rsquo;m looking for the SPX to head to 2060 and stall there a bit, here&rsquo;s the play:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03262016/spx_diagonal.png"><img src="/images/blog/03262016/spx_diagonal.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-26 - Diagonal Call Spread" /></a></p>

<p>We front some debit here, and will incur losses if SPX blows through the 2060 very quickly, so this will need to be managed if that happens (keep a close eye on this and my Twitter). We want SPX to expire near our short strike by its expiration. Now this will have to be priced in again on Monday and will depend on how the futures trade Sunday night. I&rsquo;ll tweet this trade out if I end up putting it on.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m also looking at AMZN:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03262016/amzn.png"><img src="/images/blog/03262016/amzn.png" alt="AMZN - 2016-03-26 Daily Time Frame - Range Extension - 61.8% Fibonnaci Retracement" /></a></p>

<p>Last week we put a trade on for AMZN that would take advantage of a slow grind down to prior support levels at around 475. After doing so, we got faked out when the 547 support broke, and for the rest of the week, AMZN grinded higher. This is great for our position, as we had put it on for a credit, so the further it&rsquo;s away from our unbalanced butterfly, the higher the probability that we win on this trade (of course, we would like AMZN to trade near our short strikes for max profit, but a winner is a winner).</p>

<p>This week, I&rsquo;m looking for upside follow-through in this stock. Notice how the 50% fib level acts as the resistance level. If we pierce through this, and if the market does indeed turn around and move higher, I think we at least head to the 61.8 fib level and possibly double the range of the consolidation area that we&rsquo;ve had since February (between 547 and 585, ~ 35 points) and head to 620. Of course, because we&rsquo;ve retraced a long way from the 547 lows, the best way to hit 620 would be for AMZN to make a slight pullback before breaking the 50% fib level. Keep that point in mind, because we&rsquo;ll use that information to manage our trade. So here&rsquo;s the trade I&rsquo;m thinking:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03262016/amzn_condor.png"><img src="/images/blog/03262016/amzn_condor.png" alt="AMZN - 2016-03-26 Risk Graph - Condor" /></a></p>

<p>We can place a condor with a slight debit (.92 currently) with 1 week to go. If AMZN is able to reach the 61.8% fib level and close around there, we&rsquo;ll collect the max profit of 9.05. We should be looking to manage this trade by looking at the market action, in case we get a look above and fail. I&rsquo;ll also tweet out this trade when I end up putting it on, so keep watch.</p>

<p>Another one is EWZ:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03262016/ewz.png"><img src="/images/blog/03262016/ewz.png" alt="EWZ - 2016-03-26 Support and Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m looking to sell a strangle here in May - not sure why the implied volatility here is pretty rich. But I also have a bearish bias on this, so I&rsquo;m looking to buy a put spread as well. Here is the trade:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03262016/ewz_strangle_put_vertical.png"><img src="/images/blog/03262016/ewz_strangle_put_vertical.png" alt="EWZ - 2016-03-26 Strangle and Put Vertical" /></a></p>

<p>Breakevens are at around 19.1 and 30.9. We can put this on for about a .84 cr.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today. Good luck in the markets. Remember to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> as that is where I&rsquo;ll be posting my trades up in real-time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monitor for Continuation]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/03/08/monitor-for-continuation/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-08T18:24:59-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/03/08/monitor-for-continuation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>All broad market indices traded lower today.</p>

<p>SPX erases the past 3 days of trading:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03082016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03082016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-08 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement" /></a></p>

<p>NDX continues to form lower Dojis:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03082016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03082016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-03-08 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement" /></a></p>

<p>DJX forms a swing high:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03082016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03082016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-03-08 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement" /></a></p>

<p>RUT forms a swing high and had the biggest drop in % today.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03082016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/03082016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-03-08 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement" /></a></p>

<p>This could be the start of a new (down) trend, but given how nervous traders are out there, I would not be surprised if we gap up tomorrow; thus, monitor the markets for a continued move down.</p>

<p>Let&rsquo;s take a look at a couple of bearish trades that may pan out if the market continues to roll over:</p>

<p>/CL erased all of its gains from yesterday - this is quite bearish. Look for a break below 36. If sellers start coming in hard, then we&rsquo;ve got a &ldquo;look above and fail&rdquo; pattern, which would be a short signal. Keep a close eye on this.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03082016/cl_f.png"><img src="/images/blog/03082016/cl_f.png" alt="/CL - 2016-03-08 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement and Harmonic Pattern" /></a></p>

<p>CMG exhibited a dark cloud cover pattern today, with a double top on the daily, and a small topping tail. The APR 600/610 call spread is currently trading for 0.97 cr.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03082016/cmg.png"><img src="/images/blog/03082016/cmg.png" alt="CMG - 2016-03-08 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement, Dark Cloud Cover, Double Top" /></a></p>

<p>TRIP has been a bit confused about where it wanted to go for the previous 4 days before today. Today&rsquo;s price action broke us out of a rising wedge. If bearishness continues, we can easily head to the lower 50s.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03082016/cmg.png"><img src="/images/blog/03082016/cmg.png" alt="TRIP - 2016-03-08 Daily Time Frame - Rising Wedge" /></a></p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today. Good luck in the markets tomorrow. Stay small, and stay safe.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Market Outlook - Will the Short Squeeze Continue]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/03/06/market-outlook-will-the-short-squeeze-continue/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-06T09:16:35-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/03/06/market-outlook-will-the-short-squeeze-continue</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For the past 6 weeks, the SPX has been rallying almost non-stop from the double-bottom lows. Last week, I wasn&rsquo;t convinced that we would see a follow through in the Bulls, but after the Bears failed to take this market lower on Monday, we only got more short squeeze action, and the Bulls remained in charge.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03062016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03062016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-06 Daily Timeframe Fibonaccis" /></a></p>

<p>Last Friday, SPX closed at the 61.8% fib retracement level. Will we continue to see a rally, or will we turn here? There are many factors leading me to think that the market will turn lower at this point - I&rsquo;ll first argue the Bear case:
1. The market has been extremely overextended to the upside, and almost every rally has been built on poor structure
2. The recent rallying has been closely tied to crude, and crude is coming up to major resistance levels
3. Friday&rsquo;s late day selloff was a bit unusual (usually on a short-squeezing day, we see the action continue all the way to the closing bell) and lends support to the fact that:
5. There is major overhead supply above us; path of least resistance is to the downside
6. Overall fundamentals have not changed</p>

<p>But, I&rsquo;ll also argue the other Bull case - we can continue to see higher prices:
1. Looking at the SPX chart above, a full extension of the W pattern goes as high as 2080 (though we may not see that target to be fully reached due to multiple trendline resistances along the way)
2. Though Friday&rsquo;s late day selloff was unusual, the longer term players usually don&rsquo;t wait until near the closing bell to sell a market
3. Liquidation breaks strengthen the market, and we had one on Friday morning
4. The RUT is the strongest out of all the indices and has not reached the 61.8% fib level (Dec - Feb). The NDX also closed above the 50% fib level (Dec - Feb), but has not reached the 61.8%</p>

<p>Although the edge is to the Bears here, any upside continuation may only cause more shorts to be nervous.</p>

<p>Looking at all the other major indices, the RUT is the strongest and doesn&rsquo;t look like it&rsquo;ll be pulling back, as the 61.8% fib level hasn&rsquo;t been reached, yet:
<a href="/images/blog/03062016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/03062016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-03-06 Daily Timeframe Fibonaccis" /></a></p>

<p>The NDX had balancing action over the past 3 trading days (2 hammers, 1 doji). It&rsquo;s currently sitting just a bit above the 50% fib level (Dec - Feb). A break out of balance to either side would most likely result in violent moves in that direction.
<a href="/images/blog/03062016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03062016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-03-06 Daily Timeframe Fibonaccis" /></a></p>

<p>The DJX peaked above the 61.8% fib level, but closed underneath it:
<a href="/images/blog/03062016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03062016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-03-06 Daily Timeframe Fibonaccis" /></a></p>

<p>With that, I&rsquo;ll leave you with a couple of trade ideas. These are mostly bearish plays, as is my current bias.</p>

<p>For a bearish play on the SPX: knowing that the peak of the extension from the W pattern is around 2080, we can place the APR 2080/2100 bear call spread (currently priced for about 3.00 cr). This trade has a 92% probability of success, and should be managed to avoid taking the max loss (consider rolling out in time for duration once the short strike is threatened). If the margin requirement on SPX is too much, consider the 208/210 bear call on the SPY - adjust the lot size as you see fit.</p>

<p>Another trade idea that is bearish, but also allows room for bullishness: we can sell the APR 206/208 call ratio spread on the SPY for about a 0.12 credit. If the market does in fact roll over, we win. But if not, and if it grinds higher and hovers around our 208 resistance area by expiration, even better. Our breakeven to the upside is 210.12, with a 93% win rate, and a max profit of 2.12 per spread. Adjust lot size as you see fit.</p>

<p>More direct, bullish plays here with credits are a bit hard to put on right now. IV is low, and any downmove will inflate our premium, which will most likely hurt us, so I caution against putting those on.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for this week&rsquo;s outlook. I&rsquo;ll be posting updates as the week progresses. Good luck, and happy trading.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
