<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: djx | ThetaTrades]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/categories/djx/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-02-28T08:32:51-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[theta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Preparing for an Upside Breakout]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/06/04/preparing-for-an-upside-breakout/"/>
    <updated>2016-06-04T10:08:28-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/06/04/preparing-for-an-upside-breakout</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Why next week should be bullish</p>

<p>Much of the trade this past week contributed to developing the big balance area between 2082.50 and 2106:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/06042016/es.png"><img src="/images/blog/06042016/es.png" alt="/ES - 2016-06-04 - 1h Chart - Balance Area" /></a></p>

<p>Notice where most of the volume took place over the past 5 days:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/06042016/es_15m.png"><img src="/images/blog/06042016/es_15m.png" alt="/ES - 2016-06-04 - 15m Chart Volume Composite" /></a></p>

<p>The fairest price to do business appears to be right in the middle of this balance area. This is neutral so far.</p>

<p>However, as a point in the Bulls camp, note how we&rsquo;ve had multiple liquidation breaks with no significant follow-through to the downside, and in multiple sessions, we ended with the Bulls taking it right back up to near 2100. On the daily:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/06042016/es_tails.png"><img src="/images/blog/06042016/es_tails.png" alt="/ES - 2016-06-04 - Daily Bottoming-Tails" /></a></p>

<p>Note the bottoming-tail hammers. There are 5 of them all within the balance area. An edge to the Bulls.</p>

<p>Taking a look at the indices on the weekly, here&rsquo;s the SPX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/06042016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/06042016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-06-04 - Weekly Chart" /></a></p>

<p>Doji forming above trendline support.</p>

<p>DJX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/06042016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/06042016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-06-04 - Weekly Chart" /></a></p>

<p>Bottoming tail above trendline support.</p>

<p>NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/06042016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/06042016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-06-04 - Weekly Chart" /></a></p>

<p>Doji right at trendline resistance. This could make for a big breakout.</p>

<p>RUT:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/06042016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/06042016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-06-04 - Weekly Chart" /></a></p>

<p>The strongest of them all, Maintaining the breakout above multiple trendline supports.</p>

<p>Keep these points in mind going into next week. Though we&rsquo;re currently neutral and in balance, the shorts seem extremely nervous and are unable to push prices lower given every opportunity they&rsquo;ve had.</p>

<p>Could we continue to remain in balance next week? Absolutely, and if so, the resulting breakout would be more violent. But be prepared for a breakout this coming week to the upside.</p>

<p>This past week, we made many trade adjustments. Keep an eye on <a href="/trades#KORS" title="KORS">KORS</a>, <a href="/trades#NFLX" title="NFLX">NFLX</a>, <a href="/trades#CL_F" title="/CL">/CL</a>, <a href="/trades#SQ" title="SQ">SQ</a>, and <a href="/trades#SLV" title="SLV">SLV</a> as potential winners to manage. As always, I will be tweeting out entries/adjustments/exits on Twitter, so if you haven&rsquo;t already, make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> to get these updates in real-time.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for this week&rsquo;s market recap and outlook. Enjoy the weekend everyone!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Edge to the Bears]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/30/an-edge-to-the-bears/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-30T09:58:05-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/30/an-edge-to-the-bears</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On Friday, we got an expansion of range yesterday, with value area gapping to the downside:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04302016/es_5m.png"><img src="/images/blog/04302016/es_5m.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-04-30 - 5m Chart - Value Area Gapping to the Downside" /></a></p>

<p><a href="/blog/2016/04/29/yesterdays-liquidation-break-going-forward/" title="Liquidation Break Going Forward - Bulls and Bears Have Work to Do">In my premarket post on Friday morning</a>, I mentioned that it would be beneficial for the Bulls to hold value at or above the upper distribution of Thursday&rsquo;s profile, and for the Bears to maintain the continuation of selling and migrate the POC and value area lower.</p>

<p>Well, congratulations to the Bears, because they did exactly that and were able to keep trade <em>well below</em> both of Thursday&rsquo;s distributions. When the market opened, we saw the Bulls try to push price back into Thursday&rsquo;s value area, but could not even reach it before falling back down. We then tagged the POC from 4/12, and for the rest of the day, we built value in the large balance area developed from mid-March to mid-April. By the end of the day, it was clear that Friday&rsquo;s value area is a gap below Thursday&rsquo;s. That&rsquo;s an expansion of range to the downside, and this generally signifies the start of a new trend (in this case, a down-trend):</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04302016/es_15m.png"><img src="/images/blog/04302016/es_15m.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-04-30 - 15m Chart - Expansion of Range Signifying Beginning of a New Trend" /></a></p>

<p>The only argument that I have against the Bears is that all of this trading seems to be of low confidence. The big rip that we saw at the end of the session tells me that shorts are nervous into the close. Still, Bulls have no confidence, either. I am, however, switching my bias from neutral to slightly bearish.</p>

<p>Taking a look at the volume composite over the past 20 days:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04302016/es_volume_comp.png"><img src="/images/blog/04302016/es_volume_comp.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-04-30 - Volume Composite" /></a></p>

<p>Prices have a predisposition to trade near high volume nodes. They also have a tendency to reject trading around low volume nodes. In accordance with that behavior, we can see that the next target to the downside is around 2040.50. This makes sense - looking back to early April, that was where a lot of the volume traded. So again, as a downside target reference, <strong>I&rsquo;m expecting traders to explore the 2040.50 area next.</strong></p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve also been talking about how falling into this big balance area, <strong>we should expect to target the other side of balance at 2012</strong> if we start to see some sellers step up. Keep this target in mind going forward.</p>

<p>Below that, there are many more weak downside reference points, but I will bring them up as we get closer to them. For now, <strong>focus on the large volume node at 2040.50, and then the balance area low at 2012.</strong></p>

<p>Take this bearish move with a grain of salt, because as I mentioned earlier, all of this trading seems to be done with very low confidence.</p>

<p>Let&rsquo;s take a look at the weeklies for the broad market indices. Here&rsquo;s the SPX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04302016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04302016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-04-30 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>Prior to this past week, we had a green candle that failed to close the week above the trendline resistance. This past week, we confirmed that failure by taking prices lower.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the DJX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04302016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04302016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-04-30 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>Very similar to the SPX. Let&rsquo;s see if we get a continuation to the downside this coming week.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04302016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04302016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-04-30 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>This one, as continuously mentioned, is the weakest of the bunch and exhibits the bearishness more clearly than the other indices. Watch for a break of the 4300 level, and see how the 38% fib level holds.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the RUT:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04302016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/04302016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-04-30 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>Currently testing that trendline support. If that support fails, I&rsquo;ll be looking to target the upward-sloping trendline support first at around 1100.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for this weekend&rsquo;s market recap and outlook. With more volatility coming back into the markets, watch out for more trades from me, which I will tweet out. Make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a>, because that&rsquo;s where I post all of my trades in real-time. Make sure you turn on notifications specifically from me. Just visit my Twitter profile on mobile, select the Settings gear, and then select the option to turn on notifications.</p>

<p>Enjoy the weekend guys, and stay safe out there.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Yesterday's Liquidation Break Going Forward]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/29/yesterdays-liquidation-break-going-forward/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-29T05:03:36-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/29/yesterdays-liquidation-break-going-forward</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday&rsquo;s liquidation was one which I haven&rsquo;t seen in a while and showed some signs of life from the sellers.</p>

<p>Whether or not Icahn contributed to the scare doesn&rsquo;t matter. Here&rsquo;s the current volume profile over the past 15 days:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04292016/es.png"><img src="/images/blog/04292016/es.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-04-29 - 15d Chart - Volume Profile" /></a></p>

<p>By the end of the session, we managed to trade back inside the intermediate balance area. Though traders got themselves stretched too short to the downside, notice that they did so with volume and were able to form two distributions (highlighted by the pink boxes):</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04292016/es_zoomed.png"><img src="/images/blog/04292016/es_zoomed.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-04-29 - 5d Chart - Volume Profile" /></a></p>

<p>The profile shows that the trades that occurred at the bottom distribution happened with decent volume, almost as much as there was in the upper distribution. This is definitely an edge to the Bears. However, notice that the volume POC did not migrate lower - it remained at 2087.5 - and most of the time was spent trading up there as well.</p>

<p>Today, I want to see if the POC and value area can migrate lower. I&rsquo;d like to see some continuation of selling from the Bears before switching my bias. For now, however, the Bulls have some work to do as well, and that is to get trading back above the intermediate balance area to at least in the upper distribution. Until then, my bias is neutral.</p>

<p>Also, let&rsquo;s quickly take a look at the major market indices.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the SPX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04292016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04292016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-04-29 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>We&rsquo;ve now fallen back below that trendline which we&rsquo;ve meandered back and forth between. Let&rsquo;s see if the Bears can hold it below here and show some continuation to the downside.</p>

<p>The DJX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04292016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04292016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-04-29 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>We&rsquo;re now below the highs of Nov 2015. Looks like the Bulls failed to keep it above there for now.</p>

<p>The NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04292016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04292016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-04-29 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>That trendline resistance has played out well, and this is still the weakest of the bunch. We&rsquo;re now below that 61.8% Fib retracement, closing yesterday&rsquo;s trade below it on a wide body candle.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the RUT:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04292016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/04292016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-04-29 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>Still holding above the trendline support quite well. We&rsquo;ll need to see if this one will start rolling over.</p>

<p>Keep a close eye on all of these indices, and let&rsquo;s see who wins the struggle up here.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today&rsquo;s morning market outlook. Make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a>, because that&rsquo;s where I post all my trades in real-time. Make sure you turn on notifications specifically from me. Just visit my Twitter profile on mobile, select the Settings gear, and then select the option to turn on notifications.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mixed Signals from Indices]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/24/mixed-signals-from-indices/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-24T14:38:16-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/24/mixed-signals-from-indices</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We ended last week on diverging signals. It&rsquo;s important to look at all broad market indices, so let&rsquo;s do that.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the SPX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04242016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04242016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-04-24 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>We have a very clear look above and fail, topping tail pattern, which is generally a bearish signal. However, although we closed below trendline resistance, the week did end up positive, so keep that in mind.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the DJX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04242016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04242016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-04-24 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>This one is a little bit more bullish than the SPX, as we closed just a bit above that 100% retracement level. I do think we start consolidating around this area for a while before we break any higher.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04242016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04242016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-04-24 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>The weakest of the bunch again due to weak earnings from GOOG. It has been unable to close above that trendline resistance, but do keep a close eye on this.</p>

<p>Finally the RUT:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04242016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/04242016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-04-24 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>The most bullish of all indices. This one clearly closed the week above the trendline resistance and has a lot of clearance to continue running to 1200.</p>

<p>Going forward, keep a close eye on all of these indices. They&rsquo;re currently divergent, so it&rsquo;s hard to say whether we should remain bullish or bearish going forward. For now, bias remains neutral.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for the recap - make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a>, because that&rsquo;s where I post all my trades in real-time. Make sure you turn on notifications specifically from me. Just visit my Twitter profile on mobile, select the Settings gear, and then select the option to turn on notifications.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets tomorrow!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Still Bullish...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/19/still-bullish-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-19T21:29:48-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/19/still-bullish-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Markets still remain bullish.</p>

<p>We&rsquo;ve had mini-liquidation breaks throughout the trading day - all that does is strengthen the market, as it eliminates the shorter-term, weaker hands, allowing buyers to continue doing what they do - buying.</p>

<p>Taking a look at the SPX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04192016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04192016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-04-19 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>We had a nice strong close by the end of the trading session.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the DJX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04192016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04192016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-04-19 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>Also a nice follow through here.</p>

<p>However, the NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04192016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04192016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-04-19 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>Still the weakest of the bunch. This is one that casts a shadow of doubt on the rally - eventually, this, or one or more of the other indices will catch up to the other.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the RUT:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04192016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/04192016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-04-19 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>Consolidating after a move higher from yesterday. Watch for a continuation tomorrow. Our <a href="/trades#RUT" title="RUT Call Calendar">RUT calendar</a> is still looking good, and we&rsquo;re holding on to it - no need to panic out.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today. As always, make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a>. That is where I post all of my trades in real-time. Make sure you turn on notifications specifically from me. Just go to my Twitter profile on mobile, select the Settings gear, and then select the option to turn on notifications.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets tomorrow!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
