<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: djx | theta trades]]></title>
  <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/categories/djx/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-03-12T15:34:28-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[theta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Further Upside Expected]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/11/further-upside-expected/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-11T18:45:36-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/11/further-upside-expected</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m expecting further upside in the market.</p>

<p>Yesterday after the ECB announcement, traders attempted to push the market lower but were unable to do so. We looked below balance, failed, made a poor low, and then came back into balance. Then this morning, we gapped up, but with the internals so strong, no chance of a gap fade play was available, and we continued to ratchet higher.</p>

<p>This is a very bullish signal, regardless of how overbought the conditions are. Here&rsquo;s the current SPX chart:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03112016/spx_daily.png"><img src="/images/blog/03112016/spx_daily.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-11 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement, Trendline Resistance, Range Extension" /></a></p>

<p>For those that took a bullish stance on the market during that time, congratulations. In the first SPX chart that I posted a couple of weeks back, I outlined the potential range extension we could see as possible target areas (via the pink rectangles). This week, not only did we break the 61.8% fib level, but we&rsquo;ve also broken the trendline resistance connected by the tops of November and December 2015. I believe we&rsquo;re headed to 2060. So if you&rsquo;re long, continue to hold that position.</p>

<p>Zooming out and taking a look at the market on the weekly:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03112016/spx_weekly.png"><img src="/images/blog/03112016/spx_weekly.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-11 Weekly Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement, Trendline Resistance, Range Extension, Bottoming-Tail Hammer" /></a></p>

<p>Notice the bottoming tail hammer that formed. I count many weekly bars from before that ended with a higher close the following week.</p>

<p>The same bullishness can be seen in the Dow:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03112016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03112016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-03-11 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement, Trendline Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>We&rsquo;re approaching the trendline resistance here as well. Look for a short there. As a side note, DJX has also put in a bottoming-tail hammer on the weekly chart.</p>

<p>For the NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03112016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03112016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-03-11 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement" /></a></p>

<p>A little bit weaker here, as we have not tagged the 61.8% fib level, yet. Still, this has also put in a bottoming-tail hammer on the weekly chart.</p>

<p>Finally the RUT:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03112016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/03112016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-03-11 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement, Trendline Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>Though it exhibited a lot of weakness a couple of days ago, keep in mind it has come off really high from the lows. It looks like it&rsquo;ll break that trendline resistance, and if it does, that&rsquo;ll suggest more short-covering to come.</p>

<p>That about wraps it up for the week going on to next week. I&rsquo;d just like to finish with another note:</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m not bullish on the market - I think the fundamentals are complete garbage, and I think we&rsquo;ll see a crash like we&rsquo;ve never seen before. However, I can&rsquo;t let my biases blind me from seeing the opportunities out there. Instead of falling prey to cognitive dissonance, we can separate our bias and take advantage of these opportunities as they come.</p>

<p>Enjoy the weekend, and good luck to everyone, bull or bear.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monitor for Continuation]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/08/monitor-for-continuation/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-08T18:24:59-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/08/monitor-for-continuation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>All broad market indices traded lower today.</p>

<p>SPX erases the past 3 days of trading:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03082016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03082016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-08 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement" /></a></p>

<p>NDX continues to form lower Dojis:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03082016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03082016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-03-08 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement" /></a></p>

<p>DJX forms a swing high:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03082016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03082016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-03-08 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement" /></a></p>

<p>RUT forms a swing high and had the biggest drop in % today.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03082016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/03082016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-03-08 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement" /></a></p>

<p>This could be the start of a new (down) trend, but given how nervous traders are out there, I would not be surprised if we gap up tomorrow; thus, monitor the markets for a continued move down.</p>

<p>Let&rsquo;s take a look at a couple of bearish trades that may pan out if the market continues to roll over:</p>

<p>/CL erased all of its gains from yesterday - this is quite bearish. Look for a break below 36. If sellers start coming in hard, then we&rsquo;ve got a &ldquo;look above and fail&rdquo; pattern, which would be a short signal. Keep a close eye on this.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03082016/cl_f.png"><img src="/images/blog/03082016/cl_f.png" alt="/CL - 2016-03-08 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement and Harmonic Pattern" /></a></p>

<p>CMG exhibited a dark cloud cover pattern today, with a double top on the daily, and a small topping tail. The APR 600/610 call spread is currently trading for 0.97 cr.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03082016/cmg.png"><img src="/images/blog/03082016/cmg.png" alt="CMG - 2016-03-08 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement, Dark Cloud Cover, Double Top" /></a></p>

<p>TRIP has been a bit confused about where it wanted to go for the previous 4 days before today. Today&rsquo;s price action broke us out of a rising wedge. If bearishness continues, we can easily head to the lower 50s.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03082016/cmg.png"><img src="/images/blog/03082016/cmg.png" alt="TRIP - 2016-03-08 Daily Time Frame - Rising Wedge" /></a></p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today. Good luck in the markets tomorrow. Stay small, and stay safe.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Keeping an Eye Out on Indices and Crude Oil]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/07/indices/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-07T13:42:40-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/07/indices</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The markets continue to grind higher, with the SPX closing today above the 61.8% fib level. The likely target is the descending trendline resistance, which should be around 2020:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03072016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03072016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-07 Daily Time Frame - Descending Trendline Resistance &amp; Fibonacci Retracement" /></a></p>

<p>Looking at the DJX, it has also closed above the 61.8% fib level:
<a href="/images/blog/03072016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03072016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-03-07 Daily Time Frame - Descending Trendline Resistance and Fibonacci Retracement" /></a></p>

<p>Of course, the strongest of them all, RUT, grinds higher:
<a href="/images/blog/03072016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/03072016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-03-07 Daily Time Frame - Ascending Trendline Support as Resistance and Fibonacci Retracement" /></a></p>

<p>And then, interestingly enough the NDX, which has been having a hard time getting some love:
<a href="/images/blog/03072016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03072016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-03-07 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement" /></a></p>

<p>Whatever the case, it looks like the markets are mostly pointing to being neutral or moving higher. Unless the Bears have more confidence, this market will most likely continue to meander up here, dominated by many short term traders. Look for yesterday&rsquo;s trade idea on the market for ideas on trade location.</p>

<p>Moving over to /CL.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03072016/cl_f.png"><img src="/images/blog/03072016/cl_f.png" alt="/CL - 2016-03-07 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement and Harmonic Pattern" /></a></p>

<p>/CL is approaching its previous resistance levels, as well as the 50% fib level (Oct - Feb). Furthermore, a <a href="http://www.harmonictrader.com/price_patternsabcd.htm" title="harmonic pattern">harmonic pattern AB=CD</a> could be forming again (we saw one form from last May to last August, and a completion of the pattern from last October to last month). If we do see crude oil begin to roll over, we can initiate a short position, giving us a good trade location. However, for confirmation, I&rsquo;d like to see it trade below 35 again before shorting. For now, do keep an eye out on /CL.</p>

<p>For those that are a bit more aggressive, you may consider selling a call vertical here on /CL. The MAY 42/42.5 call spread (39 DTE) is trading for .15 cr currently, or the 42/43 call spread, currently trading for .28 cr.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today, happy trading out there, and enjoy the markets tomorrow.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Market Outlook - Will the Short Squeeze Continue]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/06/market-outlook-will-the-short-squeeze-continue/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-06T09:16:35-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/06/market-outlook-will-the-short-squeeze-continue</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For the past 6 weeks, the SPX has been rallying almost non-stop from the double-bottom lows. Last week, I wasn&rsquo;t convinced that we would see a follow through in the Bulls, but after the Bears failed to take this market lower on Monday, we only got more short squeeze action, and the Bulls remained in charge.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03062016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03062016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-06 Daily Timeframe Fibonaccis" /></a></p>

<p>Last Friday, SPX closed at the 61.8% fib retracement level. Will we continue to see a rally, or will we turn here? There are many factors leading me to think that the market will turn lower at this point - I&rsquo;ll first argue the Bear case:
1. The market has been extremely overextended to the upside, and almost every rally has been built on poor structure
2. The recent rallying has been closely tied to crude, and crude is coming up to major resistance levels
3. Friday&rsquo;s late day selloff was a bit unusual (usually on a short-squeezing day, we see the action continue all the way to the closing bell) and lends support to the fact that:
5. There is major overhead supply above us; path of least resistance is to the downside
6. Overall fundamentals have not changed</p>

<p>But, I&rsquo;ll also argue the other Bull case - we can continue to see higher prices:
1. Looking at the SPX chart above, a full extension of the W pattern goes as high as 2080 (though we may not see that target to be fully reached due to multiple trendline resistances along the way)
2. Though Friday&rsquo;s late day selloff was unusual, the longer term players usually don&rsquo;t wait until near the closing bell to sell a market
3. Liquidation breaks strengthen the market, and we had one on Friday morning
4. The RUT is the strongest out of all the indices and has not reached the 61.8% fib level (Dec - Feb). The NDX also closed above the 50% fib level (Dec - Feb), but has not reached the 61.8%</p>

<p>Although the edge is to the Bears here, any upside continuation may only cause more shorts to be nervous.</p>

<p>Looking at all the other major indices, the RUT is the strongest and doesn&rsquo;t look like it&rsquo;ll be pulling back, as the 61.8% fib level hasn&rsquo;t been reached, yet:
<a href="/images/blog/03062016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/03062016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-03-06 Daily Timeframe Fibonaccis" /></a></p>

<p>The NDX had balancing action over the past 3 trading days (2 hammers, 1 doji). It&rsquo;s currently sitting just a bit above the 50% fib level (Dec - Feb). A break out of balance to either side would most likely result in violent moves in that direction.
<a href="/images/blog/03062016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03062016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-03-06 Daily Timeframe Fibonaccis" /></a></p>

<p>The DJX peaked above the 61.8% fib level, but closed underneath it:
<a href="/images/blog/03062016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03062016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-03-06 Daily Timeframe Fibonaccis" /></a></p>

<p>With that, I&rsquo;ll leave you with a couple of trade ideas. These are mostly bearish plays, as is my current bias.</p>

<p>For a bearish play on the SPX: knowing that the peak of the extension from the W pattern is around 2080, we can place the APR 2080/2100 bear call spread (currently priced for about 3.00 cr). This trade has a 92% probability of success, and should be managed to avoid taking the max loss (consider rolling out in time for duration once the short strike is threatened). If the margin requirement on SPX is too much, consider the 208/210 bear call on the SPY - adjust the lot size as you see fit.</p>

<p>Another trade idea that is bearish, but also allows room for bullishness: we can sell the APR 206/208 call ratio spread on the SPY for about a 0.12 credit. If the market does in fact roll over, we win. But if not, and if it grinds higher and hovers around our 208 resistance area by expiration, even better. Our breakeven to the upside is 210.12, with a 93% win rate, and a max profit of 2.12 per spread. Adjust lot size as you see fit.</p>

<p>More direct, bullish plays here with credits are a bit hard to put on right now. IV is low, and any downmove will inflate our premium, which will most likely hurt us, so I caution against putting those on.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for this week&rsquo;s outlook. I&rsquo;ll be posting updates as the week progresses. Good luck, and happy trading.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
