<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: djx | ThetaTrades]]></title>
  <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/categories/djx/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-04-13T18:42:31-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[theta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[More Low Confidence]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/06/more-consolidation/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-06T19:08:41-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/06/more-consolidation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Market continues to consolidate here. As I mentioned yesterday, I just didn&rsquo;t see enough sellers, and that spells low confidence.</p>

<p>Looking at the SPX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04062016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04062016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-04-06 - Daily - Look-Above-And-Fail" /></a></p>

<p>Yesterday&rsquo;s look-above-and-fail pattern failed, and now we&rsquo;re back up above the trendline support. All of this just spells low confidence.</p>

<p>DJX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04062016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04062016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-04-06 - Daily - Bounced off Trendline Support" /></a></p>

<p>Couldn&rsquo;t continue lower after testing the support. Once again, consolidating just above the trendline support.</p>

<p>NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04062016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04062016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-04-06 - Daily - Seller Shutoff" /></a></p>

<p>We&rsquo;re still consolidating here, though we have a wide body candle.</p>

<p>RUT:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04062016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/04062016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-04-06 - Daily - Bullish Engulfing" /></a></p>

<p>We&rsquo;re now back up above the 61.8% Fib level - again, this spells low confidence. When a price level is traded through many times, it&rsquo;s not a sign of trend confidence, but rather a sign of consolidation, or low confidence.</p>

<p>Today, we put on a couple of new trades, specifically calendar spreads in CMG and EEM. We also made some adjustments to our TSLA position (currently our worst trade so far) and closed out our AAPL calendar (at a profit). Check them out in the <a href="/trades" title="Ongoing Trades">Trades</a> page. If you want to be notified when I enter, adjust, or exit trades, make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> so you can receive my updates in real-time. Again, to make the most out of Twitter, make sure you turn on notifications specifically from me. Just visit my Twitter profile on the mobile app, select the Settings gear, and select the <em>Turn on Notifications</em> option.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today. Good luck in the markets tomorrow!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Market Still Pausing]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/05/market-still-pausing/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-05T21:23:05-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/05/market-still-pausing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There isn&rsquo;t a lot pointing to the Bears being in full control, yet. For now, it still appears to just be consolidation. I am still watching for a break below 2033.5 on the /ES with strong follow-through before I turn bearish.</p>

<p>Looking at the SPX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04052016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04052016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-04-05 - Daily - Look-Above-And-Fail" /></a></p>

<p>Today it appears we formed a look-above-and-fail pattern - I&rsquo;d like to see follow-through to the downside for confirmation.</p>

<p>DJX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04052016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04052016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-04-05 - Daily - Sitting at Trendline Support" /></a></p>

<p>We closed just at trendline support. Let&rsquo;s see if it holds.</p>

<p>NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04052016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04052016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-04-05 - Daily - Consolidation" /></a></p>

<p>This appears to just be consolidating over the past 5 trading days.</p>

<p>RUT:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04052016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/04052016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-04-05 - Daily - Consolidation" /></a></p>

<p>We&rsquo;re now below the 61.8% Fib level. We&rsquo;ve now traded near and around the 61.8% Fib level many times - consolidation is still happening here.</p>

<p>Ok - we haven&rsquo;t been putting on many trades this week. This is largely due to my reluctance to sell premium in a cycle that contains earnings, but I&rsquo;ve managed to find some that avoid it with good weeklies.</p>

<p>I wanted to go back to GS which I mentioned the other day:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04032016/gs_batman.png"><img src="/images/blog/04032016/gs_batman.png" alt="GS - 2016-04-05 - Put Backratio With Call Backratio" /></a></p>

<p>Though this play contains an earnings cycle, I&rsquo;ve noticed that it doesn&rsquo;t quite move much from earnings reports. I wouldn&rsquo;t mind putting this on tomorrow - with pretty wide breakevens, we can aim for a move towards both ends of the spectrum, regardless of which way the market moves. Just as long as it doesn&rsquo;t crash, of course. This is currently being priced in at a .67 cr.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve also got a couple of calendars/diagonals for play here.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s DIS:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04052016/dis.png"><img src="/images/blog/04052016/dis.png" alt="DIS - 2016-04-05 - Daily" /></a></p>

<p>Aiming for 90 by the 4th week of April:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04052016/dis_diagonal.png"><img src="/images/blog/04052016/dis_diagonal.png" alt="DIS - 2016-04-05 - Diagonal Put" /></a></p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s EEM:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04052016/eem.png"><img src="/images/blog/04052016/eem.png" alt="EEM - 2016-04-05 - Daily" /></a></p>

<p>Aiming for 30 by the 5th week of April:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04052016/eem_calendar.png"><img src="/images/blog/04052016/eem_calendar.png" alt="EEM - 2016-04-05 - Put Calendar" /></a></p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s CMG:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04052016/cmg.png"><img src="/images/blog/04052016/cmg.png" alt="CMG - 2016-04-05 - Daily - Slow Grind to 420" /></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m looking for a slow grind down to 420:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04052016/cmg_calendar.png"><img src="/images/blog/04052016/cmg_calendar.png" alt="CMG - 2016-04-05 - Put Calendar" /></a></p>

<p>All of these require a debit, but when volatility is low, these are good deals. If we get the directional move we want and volatility expands and time decays the nearer-term option, the spread can really expand nicely.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for now. I&rsquo;ll most likely be putting these trades on, so <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> to get my updates. Also, to make the most out of Twitter, make sure you turn on notifications specifically from me. Just visit my Twitter profile on mobile, select the Settings gear, and turn on notifications.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets tomorrow!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monitoring for Continuation]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/04/monitoring-for-continuation/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-04T20:26:18-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/04/monitoring-for-continuation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today&rsquo;s action is just balancing after a trending move. For me to consider this bearish, I&rsquo;d want to see 2033.5 on the /ES get taken out. I&rsquo;d like to see value move lower as well. Also, the highs from the overnight session usually don&rsquo;t mark the end of up-moves, so expect 2071.5 to be revisited sometime soon, and if it doesn&rsquo;t, carry that information forward.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the SPX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04042016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04042016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-04-04 - Daily - Consolidation Above Trendline Support" /></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m looking for this to hold up at the trendline support. A failure to remain above it is an edge to the Bears.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the DJX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04042016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04042016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-04-04 - Daily - Consolidation" /></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m also looking for this to hold up at the trendline support.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04042016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04042016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-04-04 - Daily - Consolidation" /></a></p>

<p>Looks like a pause before a continuation higher.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the RUT:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04042016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/04042016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-04-04 - Daily - 61.8% Fib Level" /></a></p>

<p>This is a bit more interesting. Still holding above the 61.8 Fib level and may just slowly grind around here until it touches the trendline resistance.</p>

<p>For those looking for a bearish play, I&rsquo;ve been looking at CMG. We have a trendline support coming up on the weekly:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04042016/cmg_weekly.png"><img src="/images/blog/04042016/cmg_weekly.png" alt="CMG - 2016-04-04 - Weekly" /></a></p>

<p>As well as a revisit of the prior lows at 400 on the daily:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04042016/cmg.png"><img src="/images/blog/04042016/cmg.png" alt="CMG - 2016-04-04 - Daily" /></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m looking to place a small butterfly to capture a move down into the 400 area:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04042016/cmg_risk_graph.png"><img src="/images/blog/04042016/cmg_risk_graph.png" alt="CMG - 2016-04-04 - Risk Graph" /></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;ll be tweeting out my entry on this trade depending on how it&rsquo;s priced, so make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> <em>and</em> turn on notifications from my profile (on mobile - hit the settings gear on my profile and then select &ldquo;Turn On Notifications&rdquo;). You&rsquo;ll receive push notifications for all of my tweets.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets tomorrow!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bullish into Next Week]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/02/bullish-into-next-week/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-02T11:29:57-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/02/bullish-into-next-week</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m certain the markets will continue to climb higher next week.</p>

<p>There are just not enough sellers out there. On Friday, we were able to enter into the second distribution area from the Janet Yellen day:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04022016/es.png"><img src="/images/blog/04022016/es.png" alt="/ES - 2016-04-02 - Weak Sellers Failing to Take Market Lower Regardless of Poor Structure" /></a></p>

<p>But before spending enough time there, we couldn&rsquo;t find more sellers to come in. What I was expecting to happen when we broke into the second distribution area was that we at least test the 2033.5 level (and it should be relatively easy to get there due to the extremely poor structure). Obviously that didn&rsquo;t happen, and instead, on Friday during RTH, we ended up moving back up over the overnight low and through the open (which was a strong buy signal). Overnight shorts did not get paid, got nervous, and we saw the market run higher for the rest of the day.</p>

<p>Is that bearish? No. Sellers are extremely nervous out there still, and looking at the tape, every time they tried to take this market lower, they completely failed, even when structurally it was easy for them to do so. So regardless of how overbought this market is right now, we should be thinking bullish into next week. We&rsquo;ll have some trade ideas presented later this weekend based around this bullish bias, but first:</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the SPX on the daily:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04022016/spx_daily.png"><img src="/images/blog/04022016/spx_daily.png" alt="SPX - 2016-04-02 - Daily - Bullish - Trendline Resistance Becomes Trendline Support" /></a></p>

<p>Notice how we tried to break down, but ended up finding support at what was previously the trendline resistance. A classic look below and fail pattern - <strong>pretty bullish</strong>. First target here is the top of the range extension denoted by the top right pink box, which is around 2084, followed by the next trendline resistance at around 2090, and then the even 2100.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the SPX on the weekly:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04022016/spx_weekly.png"><img src="/images/blog/04022016/spx_weekly.png" alt="SPX - 2016-04-02 - Weekly" /></a></p>

<p>Strong momentum.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the DJX on the weekly:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04022016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04022016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-04-02 - Weekly - Breaking Trendline Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>Again, strong momentum. It actually broke through the trendline resistance. Target here would be 180.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the NDX on the weekly:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04022016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04022016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-04-02 - Weekly - 61.8% Fib Level Acts as Support" /></a></p>

<p>It found support off that 61.8% Fib level. Next target is that trendline resistance.</p>

<p>Finally the RUT:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04022016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/04022016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-04-02 - Weekly" /></a></p>

<p>Which looks like it may just plow through that trendline resistance, and if so, the next target would be back up to 1200.</p>

<p>Given the doubt that many have on how much higher this market can really run, but keeping in mind the bullish targets explained just above, I have a few options trade ideas that may work well just for this scenario. This will be done in a separate post which I will tweet out later this weekend, so stay tuned, and <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me</a> if you haven&rsquo;t already so that you&rsquo;ll know about it right when I tweet it out.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What's New? Nothing. Bias Still to the Upside]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/30/whats-new-nothing-bias-still-to-the-upside/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-30T13:59:59-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/30/whats-new-nothing-bias-still-to-the-upside</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We continue to float higher:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03302016/es.png"><img src="/images/blog/03302016/es.png" alt="/ES - 2016-03-30 15m Time Frame - Multiple Distributions - Gap Higher" /></a></p>

<p>Towards the beginning of today&rsquo;s session we saw a liquidation break which looked like it was going to fill the overnight gap on the /ES - that is what should&rsquo;ve happened if the Bears were really here. Unfortunately for them, all we had was a slow grind lower, which wasn&rsquo;t a convincing move (I <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive/status/715222086789111808" title="Slow Grind Lower Tweet">tweeted this out</a> as we were gradually trading lower). Not only did we snap higher, but by the end of the day, we weren&rsquo;t able to even fill the gap on the /ES.</p>

<p>What the Bears needed today was a gap down to the lowest distribution (denoted by the bottom-most blue rectangle) and build value there - that would&rsquo;ve signified a more bearish signal. Instead, not only did we <strong>not</strong> trade in the middle or top-most distribution, but price actually gapped above and traders accepted prices up at where we currently are. That&rsquo;s quite a bullish signal. On weak structure, of course. But again, don&rsquo;t fight price.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the SPX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03302016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03302016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-30 Daily Time Frame - Trendline Resistance Breached" /></a></p>

<p>Our 2060 target was reached. That trendline resistance has been broken, and is now meaningless. The next target would now be around 2095.</p>

<p>DJX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03302016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03302016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-03-30 Daily Time Frame - Trendline Resistance Breached" /></a></p>

<p>This closed above the trendline resistance, also rendering it useless.</p>

<p>NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03302016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03302016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-03-30 Daily Time Frame - Trendline Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>This is still on track to touching the trendline resistance.</p>

<p>RUT:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03302016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/03302016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-03-30 Daily Time Frame - Doji Consolidation" /></a></p>

<p>Closing above the 61.8% Fib level on a Doji (consolidation). This was actually quite weak today. The trendline resistance could be tagged, so look to see if we continue or reverse tomorrow.</p>

<p>By the way, that put backratio that we put on for LNKD yesterday turned out great today. For those of you who are in this trade, if you want to turn this into a 100% winner, 0% risk trade, buy the 98 put to turn the backratio into a balanced butterfly (this put option costs less than the credit we received when we put this trade on). Your max profit is reduced by the cost of this additional put that you buy, and regardless of where LNKD moves, this trade is an absolute winner. More details on LNKD on the <a href="/trades" title="Ongoing Trades">Trades</a> page.</p>

<p>Once again, new trades and trade adjustments can be found daily on the <a href="/trades" title="Ongoing Trades">Trades</a> page. Be sure to stay updated and <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> to follow along and see my trades in real-time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
