<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: composite | ThetaTrades]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/categories/composite/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-03-05T11:24:31-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[theta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Preparing for an Upside Breakout]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/06/04/preparing-for-an-upside-breakout/"/>
    <updated>2016-06-04T10:08:28-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/06/04/preparing-for-an-upside-breakout</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Why next week should be bullish</p>

<p>Much of the trade this past week contributed to developing the big balance area between 2082.50 and 2106:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/06042016/es.png"><img src="/images/blog/06042016/es.png" alt="/ES - 2016-06-04 - 1h Chart - Balance Area" /></a></p>

<p>Notice where most of the volume took place over the past 5 days:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/06042016/es_15m.png"><img src="/images/blog/06042016/es_15m.png" alt="/ES - 2016-06-04 - 15m Chart Volume Composite" /></a></p>

<p>The fairest price to do business appears to be right in the middle of this balance area. This is neutral so far.</p>

<p>However, as a point in the Bulls camp, note how we&rsquo;ve had multiple liquidation breaks with no significant follow-through to the downside, and in multiple sessions, we ended with the Bulls taking it right back up to near 2100. On the daily:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/06042016/es_tails.png"><img src="/images/blog/06042016/es_tails.png" alt="/ES - 2016-06-04 - Daily Bottoming-Tails" /></a></p>

<p>Note the bottoming-tail hammers. There are 5 of them all within the balance area. An edge to the Bulls.</p>

<p>Taking a look at the indices on the weekly, here&rsquo;s the SPX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/06042016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/06042016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-06-04 - Weekly Chart" /></a></p>

<p>Doji forming above trendline support.</p>

<p>DJX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/06042016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/06042016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-06-04 - Weekly Chart" /></a></p>

<p>Bottoming tail above trendline support.</p>

<p>NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/06042016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/06042016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-06-04 - Weekly Chart" /></a></p>

<p>Doji right at trendline resistance. This could make for a big breakout.</p>

<p>RUT:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/06042016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/06042016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-06-04 - Weekly Chart" /></a></p>

<p>The strongest of them all, Maintaining the breakout above multiple trendline supports.</p>

<p>Keep these points in mind going into next week. Though we&rsquo;re currently neutral and in balance, the shorts seem extremely nervous and are unable to push prices lower given every opportunity they&rsquo;ve had.</p>

<p>Could we continue to remain in balance next week? Absolutely, and if so, the resulting breakout would be more violent. But be prepared for a breakout this coming week to the upside.</p>

<p>This past week, we made many trade adjustments. Keep an eye on <a href="/trades#KORS" title="KORS">KORS</a>, <a href="/trades#NFLX" title="NFLX">NFLX</a>, <a href="/trades#CL_F" title="/CL">/CL</a>, <a href="/trades#SQ" title="SQ">SQ</a>, and <a href="/trades#SLV" title="SLV">SLV</a> as potential winners to manage. As always, I will be tweeting out entries/adjustments/exits on Twitter, so if you haven&rsquo;t already, make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> to get these updates in real-time.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for this week&rsquo;s market recap and outlook. Enjoy the weekend everyone!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Expecting Some Consolidation]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/05/26/expecting-some-consolidation/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-26T05:57:04-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/05/26/expecting-some-consolidation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here&rsquo;s the volume composite again on the /ES over the past month:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05262016/es.png"><img src="/images/blog/05262016/es.png" alt="/ES - 2016-05-26 - 1h Chart - Volume Composite" /></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m still watching the high volume nodes at 2075 and 2085 to see how they develop.</p>

<p>This past week, we&rsquo;ve seen value area gapping higher, which is bullish. After a few sessions, expect a pause and some rebalancing before the trend either continues or reverses. We may get that pause today as we&rsquo;re trading near the highest high volume node.</p>

<p>Yesterday we put on call calendars on AAPL and NFLX. AAPL hasn&rsquo;t done much since, but NFLX looks to be trading up 4 premarket. This is good for our short term calendar, but our longer term call ratio will be hurting a bit here. No worries as we have time to work it out, and our breakeven is a bit above 105, which is the gap fill. We&rsquo;ll see what happens and adjust if necessary.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today&rsquo;s morning market outlook. We&rsquo;ll be doing more trade adjustments today, so as always, make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me there</a> to receive tweets about our trades in real-time.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Watch Development of HVN at 2075-2085]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/05/25/watch-development-of-hvn-at-2075-2085/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-25T06:27:07-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/05/25/watch-development-of-hvn-at-2075-2085</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>/ES broke out of the descending channel yesterday and closed strong above it. This is slightly bullish, but in a long term perspective, still neutral:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05252016/es.png"><img src="/images/blog/05252016/es.png" alt="/ES - 2016-05-25 - 1h Chart - Volume Composite" /></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m expecting tomorrow&rsquo;s action to pause a bit, especially after such a rally. If this happens, it only makes the developing volume node at 2075 more prominent.</p>

<p>Watch how the volume composite develops throughout this week. 2075 to 2085 could become the high volume node over the past 30 days. Also, developing value at the upper end of the balance area primes us for a stronger breakout to the upside.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for the market outlook. As always, we&rsquo;ll be entering new trades and adjusting/exiting our existing positions, so be sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow us on Twitter</a>.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
