<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: how to | ThetaTrades]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/categories/how-to/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-03-05T11:24:31-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[theta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fundamentals - Should They Matter]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/02/28/fundamentals-should-they-matter/"/>
    <updated>2017-02-28T07:47:29-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/02/28/fundamentals-should-they-matter</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When people want to start investing in stocks, usually, they are told to look into the fundamentals of the company.</p>

<p>However, before they start doing that, the most important thing that they should do is ask themselves is why they want to invest in stocks. Do they want to invest because they want to make money?</p>

<p>Sounds like a pretty silly question, we know. Obviously (or hopefully), the answer is yes.</p>

<p>It’s important for everyone to take a moment to clarify this simple question with themselves, because many go into the stock market telling themselves that they want to make money, but when the tide starts to turn and the stocks that they own start selling off, they’re unable to let go of their original bias. They begin to come up with reasons why they should continue holding:</p>

<blockquote><p>There&rsquo;s no way this stock can go to 0. With such positive news coming out on the company these days, it has got to start going up.</p>

<p>The CEO is a amazing person - he/she will turn things around, I know it, and I believe in him/her.</p>

<p>I believe in their product. Last year they increased sales, and they&rsquo;ll do it again this year. I believe the company will continue to innovate and produce results. The market is just panicking right now for no reason.</p></blockquote>

<p>At this point, are these traders still investing because they want to make money? Or are they investing simply because they want to be right?</p>

<p>Though they might not be aware of this bias when they first start out, they eventually are guilty of committing this major investing flaw.</p>

<p>Assuming people want to invest in the stock market because they want to make money, if they want to be successful in this endeavor, it’s important to understand that the only thing that matters is <strong>price</strong>. Very often, the fundamentals of a company cannot easily be predicted. And even if you could predict it, it&rsquo;s more than likely a guess, and the market probably would have already priced in the outlook, so by the time that people actually want to trade that knowledge, it is already too late and not actionable.</p>

<p>Using the fundamentals of a company to buy or sell a stock is very dangerous, because it creates a bias which may cause traders to hold on to losers longer than they probably should. In the end, people invest in stocks in order to make money. If a company were to go bankrupt, it makes sense that they won’t continue to hold the stock and watch the net liquidity in their stock position go to 0.</p>

<p>However, you would be surprised to find that many continue to hold on to their losers, because they don’t want to be wrong. It’s human nature to feed our egos; we all have a “need to be right” mentality somewhere deep inside us, so we start looking at fundamentals to find reasons why we’re still holding on to a losing stock. We look for news that substantiates our bias, and ignore those that don&rsquo;t support our position.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, even when the company is cashflow positive, P/E ratios are reasonable, and dividends are high, a stock can still continue to sell off, and novice traders are left holding the bag for the next X years, praying that all else goes well and that they get their money back.</p>

<p>With all due respect to many of fundamentalists out there, we believe that looking towards fundamentals ultimately ends up creating unnecessary noise for traders, causing them to use the news as excuses to explain why they either buy, hold, or sell a stock.</p>

<p>It doesn&rsquo;t need to be that complicated. Just tune out the noise, ignore the fundamentals, and focus on price.</p>

<p>What is the price telling you? Is the stock trending up? Down? Sideways? If so, trade in the direction of the trend. It&rsquo;s that simple! Looking at price and trading with the trend, with proper risk management through position sizing (an arena often glossed over by many beginning investors), is what ultimately yields big profits in the long run.</p>

<p><em>Stay tuned for our next post, where we discuss in detail how to look at price to determine the trend and trade with it.</em></p>

<p><em>If you haven&rsquo;t yet, subscribe to our email list below to receive notifications on new posts and special offers.</em></p>

<p><div class="subscribe-button">
	<button>Subscribe to Our Updates</button>
</div>
</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Type of Trader Should I Be?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/02/27/what-type-of-trader-should-i-be/"/>
    <updated>2017-02-27T21:36:15-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/02/27/what-type-of-trader-should-i-be</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Have you ever asked yourself the question - what type of trader should I be?</p>

<p>If you’re just starting to trade, you’ve probably heard of many different styles of trading. Some may even sound scary, but don&rsquo;t worry! We’ll go over them in a little bit of detail here, and with a bit of self-assessment, you&rsquo;ll be able to figure out what trading style best suits you. Here is a table of the main different styles of trading, with their time frames listed:</p>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th> Trading Style    </th>
<th> Time Frame </th>
<th> Holding Period                              </th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td> Day Trading      </td>
<td> Short term </td>
<td> Seconds to minutes - no overnight positions </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td> Swing Trading    </td>
<td> Short term </td>
<td> Days to weeks                               </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td> Position Trading </td>
<td> Long Term  </td>
<td> Months to years                             </td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


<p>Let’s go over these styles one by one. As you read, please refer to this table above.</p>

<h3>Day Trading</h3>

<p>This is the typical picture that pops up in your head when you think about day trading - a trader sitting behind 8 different monitors, usually constantly monitoring the charts throughout the day. Day traders typically execute anywhere from 1 trade a day to 50+ trades a day. They do not hold any positions overnight, meaning they balance their account and close any open positions before the market closes at the end of the day. Day trading requires an intense amount of focus. If trading is indeed your one and only job, this can be an area for you to explore.</p>

<h3>Swing Trading</h3>

<p>In swing trading, traders typically capture market moves from days to weeks. This type of trading does not necessarily require constant monitoring because traders are more focused on where prices open at the beginning of the day and where they close at the end of the day, not anytime in between. Because trades last over the course of at least multiple days, swing traders hold positions overnight. Generally speaking, swing trading captures larger directional moves than those of day trading, but less than those of position trading.</p>

<h3>Position Trading</h3>

<p>This is essentially the Warren Buffet types of investing. Investors looking for long term buy and hold or long term shorts are position traders. They generally look at their accounts even less than swing traders, typically once or twice a week, and their trades can last from months to years. Generally speaking, position trading captures larger directional moves than those of swing trading and day trading.</p>

<hr />

<p><br/>
<strong>What time frame does ThetaTrades employ?</strong></p>

<p>At ThetaTrades, our trades operate on the daily time frame, and we maintain our position as long as the overall trend of the underlying holds. Usually, our trades last from days to weeks; however, some trends can last a long time, so they can also extend to months and possibly (though rarely) years, so <strong>we’re actually in both the swing and position trading camps</strong>.</p>

<p>With these trading time frames in mind, it&rsquo;s time to ask yourself, which time frame best suits your lifestyle? Do you have a full time job where you can only look at the market once a day or once a week? If you do, If not, styles that require less attention such as swing trading or position trading may be the better option. However, if you do not have a full-time job and are capable of being in front of the markets all day, then day-trading becomes a possibility in your arena. Whatever you decide, make sure that it absolutely fits your personality and lifestyle.</p>

<p>If you have any questions and are still confused as to what type of time frame best suits you, feel free to leave a comment at the bottom of the page, and we&rsquo;ll get back to you!</p>

<p>Cheers!</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re interested in more ideas like this, <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow us on Twitter</a> or <a href="https://facebook.com/thetatrades" title="Follow @thetatrades on Facebook">Facebook</a> to receive our tweets and posts in real time! And if you haven&rsquo;t yet, subscribe to our email listing below to receive special email alerts as well.</p>

<p><div class="subscribe-button">
	<button>Subscribe to Our Updates</button>
</div>
</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
