<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: distributions | ThetaTrades]]></title>
  <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/categories/distributions/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-05-05T06:03:32-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[theta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mind the POCs]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/05/03/mind-the-pocs/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-03T06:11:24-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/05/03/mind-the-pocs</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We formed two distributions yesterday:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05032016/es.png"><img src="/images/blog/05032016/es.png" alt="/ES - 2016-05-03 - 15m Chart" /></a></p>

<p>We closed yesterday&rsquo;s trade in the upper distribution, which resides back in the intermediate balance area. The Bulls were able to get trade back up into the lower distribution from last Thursday&rsquo;s trade. I&rsquo;m not surprised at all - as I mentioned before, I think the trading we continue to see from both the Bulls and Bears is one of low confidence.</p>

<p>Let&rsquo;s take a closer look on the 5-minute chart:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05032016/es_zoomed.png"><img src="/images/blog/05032016/es_zoomed.png" alt="/ES - 2016-05-03 - 5m Chart Taking a Closer Look at POCs and Distributions" /></a></p>

<p>As of now, the /ES is gapping down about 12 points. This is inside yesterday&rsquo;s lower distribution. I want to see how traders acknowledge yesterday&rsquo;s POC at around 2065.75. Do we continue to trade near this POC in this lower distribution, or will traders like the upper distribution more? The former gives me a neutral bias, while the latter gives me more of a bullish bias. A healthy move to the downside would be to gap below yesterday&rsquo;s POC, retrace back up to tag it, and then sell off. Watch for this to happen, as this is a bearish sign. Furthermore, keep in mind Friday&rsquo;s POC at around 2058.50. Ignoring overnight data, this POC is currently untouched. Taking trade lower to that point today is also a bearish sign - watch how traders accept this POC as well.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today&rsquo;s morning market outlook. Hope you caught some of my trades yesterday - I&rsquo;ll be looking to put on more trades today, so make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a>, as that&rsquo;s where I post all of my trade entries/adjustments/exits as they come.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets today!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
