<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: spx | theta trades]]></title>
  <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/categories/spx/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-03-29T22:58:21-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[theta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[More Weak Structure and Reference Points to Keep in Mind]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/29/more-weak-structure-and-reference-points/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-29T22:35:18-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/29/more-weak-structure-and-reference-points</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The market continues to rally on poor structure. Today after Yellen&rsquo;s speech, the /ES created three distributions, separated by single print spikes:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03292016/es.png"><img src="/images/blog/03292016/es.png" alt="/ES - 2016-03-29 - Three Separate Distributions" /></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve highlighted the distribution areas in blue. These single prints tend to act as levels for bounce plays, especially when the market is dominated by mostly short-term traders. For tomorrow, keep these weak reference points in mind. These are 2043.50 and 2033.50.</p>

<p>Here are the broad market indices:</p>

<p>SPX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03292016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03292016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-29 Daily Time Frame - Target 2060" /></a></p>

<p>This will most likely reach our 2060 target.</p>

<p>DJX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03292016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03292016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-03-29 Daily Time Frame - Trendline Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>A retest of the trendline resistance.</p>

<p>NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03292016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03292016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-03-29 Daily Time Frame" /></a></p>

<p>This is well on its way to the trendline resistance.</p>

<p>RUT:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03292016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/03292016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-03-29 Daily Time Frame" /></a></p>

<p>Closing above the 61.8% Fib level.</p>

<p>Bias remains bullish, so don&rsquo;t fight it.</p>

<p>New trades and trade adjustments can be found daily on the <a href="/trades" title="Ongoing Trades">Trades</a> page. Check them out!</p>

<p>I don&rsquo;t have any planned trade ideas for tomorrow, but do <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> in case I do spot some opportunities that I don&rsquo;t see right now, because I do tweet them out real-time.</p>

<p>Trade safe and good luck tomorrow!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Choppy Market with Low Volume]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/28/choppy-market-with-low-volume/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-28T18:36:41-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/28/choppy-market-with-low-volume</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We continue to chop and grind here on low volume. Nothing interesting happening here that I haven&rsquo;t mentioned before. All of the charts pretty much look the same as Friday, but I&rsquo;ll post them here again.</p>

<p>SPX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03282016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03282016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-28 Daily Time Frame - Target 2060" /></a></p>

<p>DJX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03282016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03282016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-03-28 Daily Time Frame - Trendline Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03282016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03282016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-03-28 Daily Time Frame" /></a></p>

<p>RUT:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03282016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/03282016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-03-28 Daily Time Frame" /></a></p>

<p>If you&rsquo;ve been following me on Twitter, you&rsquo;ll know that we got filled on these trades today:</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">SOLD 1/-1/2 CUSTOM <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24EWZ&amp;src=ctag">$EWZ</a> 100 MAY 16/MAY 16/MAY 16 30/25/22.5 CALL/PUT/PUT @.59</p>&mdash; theta (@theta_positive) <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive/status/714445062352949248">March 28, 2016</a></blockquote>


<script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>




<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">BOT BUTTERFLY <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24PCLN&amp;src=ctag">$PCLN</a> 100 (Weeklys) APR1 16 1230/1220/1205 PUT @.15 (Opening)</p>&mdash; theta (@theta_positive) <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive/status/714540072947744768">March 28, 2016</a></blockquote>


<script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>


<p>Also, we got filled on a closing order today on PCLN:</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Booking another winner: #1617415600, BOT VERTICAL <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24PCLN&amp;src=ctag">$PCLN</a> 100 APR 16 1375/1380 CALL @.48</p>&mdash; theta (@theta_positive) <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive/status/714470002909315072">March 28, 2016</a></blockquote>


<script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>


<p>Congratulations if you took that trade with me!</p>

<p>The other trades currently look good still. To see the most recent risk graphs on our open positions, check out the <a href="/trades" title="Trades">Trades page</a>. If you&rsquo;re interested in the trades we&rsquo;ve closed, check out the <a href="/history" title="History">History page</a>.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ll leave you with one trade idea for tomorrow. We&rsquo;ve been putting on quite some trades, so its wise we have time each day to manage each as necessary (though not a lot of management has been necessary so far for many of our trades).</p>

<p>Anyway, here&rsquo;s a trade idea on LNKD:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03282016/lnkd.png"><img src="/images/blog/03282016/lnkd.png" alt="LNKD - 2016-03-28 Range-Bound" /></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m expecting for the stock to slowly grind lower or meander in between the 100 to 125 price range. If it does manage to get down to 100, I&rsquo;m expecting a bounce to occur, as it has been a while since we&rsquo;ve tested that prior support level. Because of these reasons, I think a put backratio would allow us to capture profits on a slow move down, as well as any moves up. Here is the 105/102 put backratio in APR:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03282016/lnkd_risk_graph.png"><img src="/images/blog/03282016/lnkd_risk_graph.png" alt="LNKD Risk Graph - 2016-03-28 Put Backratio" /></a></p>

<p>We have big downside risk, so management is key here. We may be able to turn this into a cheap butterfly later as well, so stay tuned.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s all for today. If you haven&rsquo;t yet, make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> to receive my trade entries and adjustments in real time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bias Remains to the Upside Currently]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/26/bias-remains-to-the-upside-currently/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-26T17:38:12-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/26/bias-remains-to-the-upside-currently</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Remember this chart from last Friday?</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03182016/esm6_thurs_fri.png"><img src="/images/blog/03182016/esm6_thurs_fri.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-03-18 Hourly Time Frame - Single Prints Separating Distributions as Weak Reference Points" /></a></p>

<p>If you missed the explanation of what these reference points mean, <a href="/blog/2016/03/18/the-most-dangerous-aspect-of-the-recent-rally/" title="/ES Weak Reference Points">please take a look</a>.</p>

<p>Prior to Thursday&rsquo;s action, I was thinking that perhaps this could be the turning point for the Bears to step in and take the market back lower. However, from Thursday&rsquo;s action:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03262016/es_f.png"><img src="/images/blog/03262016/es_f.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-03-18 Hourly Time Frame - Bias Continues to Upside" /></a></p>

<p>We came close to the 2012 level, and instead of taking out that weak reference point, we bounced off hard and the Bulls took the market back up to fill the gap between Wednesday and Thursday. So the way we edge lower has me thinking that we will test 2060 soon on the SPX and possibly take that out and move higher to about 2090.</p>

<p>At the same time, value built lower on Thursday because most of the time was spent trading around 2016 on the /ES. And while we did finish the day filling the gap, late day rallies (and selloffs) are usually suspect and unsustainable. So Bulls, don&rsquo;t get too excited here. Keep value in mind, and don&rsquo;t be fooled by price (don&rsquo;t fight it, either).</p>

<p>Shorter term time frame traders are still dominating here, and structure remains weak. The only way the edge will shift to the Bears is if we take out that 2012 level (basically Thursday&rsquo;s low). After that, look for the next weak low at 1995 to be taken out.</p>

<p>Until then, bias still remains to the upside.</p>

<p>Taking a look at the SPX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03262016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03262016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-26 Daily Time Frame - Target 2060" /></a></p>

<p>As mentioned earlier, I believe the 2060 target is not out of play and may be reached soon. Looking at the other indices, I think we may consolidate there more before moving higher, which makes for a possible trade here which I&rsquo;ll show below.</p>

<p>DJX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03262016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03262016/djx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-26 Daily Time Frame - Target 2060" /></a></p>

<p>Same comment as the SPX.</p>

<p>NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03262016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03262016/ndx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-26 Daily Time Frame - Target 2060" /></a></p>

<p>Still under the 61.8% fib level, which doesn&rsquo;t mean much as a resistance level given how much we&rsquo;ve traded back and forth between this level.</p>

<p>RUT:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03262016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/03262016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-03-26 Daily Time Frame - Target 2060" /></a></p>

<p>The 61.8 fib level is still in play here as resistance.</p>

<p>Ok, trade ideas:</p>

<p>Because I&rsquo;m looking for the SPX to head to 2060 and stall there a bit, here&rsquo;s the play:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03262016/spx_diagonal.png"><img src="/images/blog/03262016/spx_diagonal.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-26 - Diagonal Call Spread" /></a></p>

<p>We front some debit here, and will incur losses if SPX blows through the 2060 very quickly, so this will need to be managed if that happens (keep a close eye on this and my Twitter). We want SPX to expire near our short strike by its expiration. Now this will have to be priced in again on Monday and will depend on how the futures trade Sunday night. I&rsquo;ll tweet this trade out if I end up putting it on.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m also looking at AMZN:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03262016/amzn.png"><img src="/images/blog/03262016/amzn.png" alt="AMZN - 2016-03-26 Daily Time Frame - Range Extension - 61.8% Fibonnaci Retracement" /></a></p>

<p>Last week we put a trade on for AMZN that would take advantage of a slow grind down to prior support levels at around 475. After doing so, we got faked out when the 547 support broke, and for the rest of the week, AMZN grinded higher. This is great for our position, as we had put it on for a credit, so the further it&rsquo;s away from our unbalanced butterfly, the higher the probability that we win on this trade (of course, we would like AMZN to trade near our short strikes for max profit, but a winner is a winner).</p>

<p>This week, I&rsquo;m looking for upside follow-through in this stock. Notice how the 50% fib level acts as the resistance level. If we pierce through this, and if the market does indeed turn around and move higher, I think we at least head to the 61.8 fib level and possibly double the range of the consolidation area that we&rsquo;ve had since February (between 547 and 585, ~ 35 points) and head to 620. Of course, because we&rsquo;ve retraced a long way from the 547 lows, the best way to hit 620 would be for AMZN to make a slight pullback before breaking the 50% fib level. Keep that point in mind, because we&rsquo;ll use that information to manage our trade. So here&rsquo;s the trade I&rsquo;m thinking:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03262016/amzn_condor.png"><img src="/images/blog/03262016/amzn_condor.png" alt="AMZN - 2016-03-26 Risk Graph - Condor" /></a></p>

<p>We can place a condor with a slight debit (.92 currently) with 1 week to go. If AMZN is able to reach the 61.8% fib level and close around there, we&rsquo;ll collect the max profit of 9.05. We should be looking to manage this trade by looking at the market action, in case we get a look above and fail. I&rsquo;ll also tweet out this trade when I end up putting it on, so keep watch.</p>

<p>Another one is EWZ:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03262016/ewz.png"><img src="/images/blog/03262016/ewz.png" alt="EWZ - 2016-03-26 Support and Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m looking to sell a strangle here in May - not sure why the implied volatility here is pretty rich. But I also have a bearish bias on this, so I&rsquo;m looking to buy a put spread as well. Here is the trade:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03262016/ewz_strangle_put_vertical.png"><img src="/images/blog/03262016/ewz_strangle_put_vertical.png" alt="EWZ - 2016-03-26 Strangle and Put Vertical" /></a></p>

<p>Breakevens are at around 19.1 and 30.9. We can put this on for about a .84 cr.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today. Good luck in the markets. Remember to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> as that is where I&rsquo;ll be posting my trades up in real-time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Edge to the Bears]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/23/an-edge-to-the-bears/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-23T17:47:43-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/23/an-edge-to-the-bears</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We finally saw a bone thrown to the Bears camp. When traders accepted prices below the value area today, that was a bearish signal. All of this could change, but this is definitely an edge to the Bears.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the SPX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03232016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03232016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-23 Daily Time Frame - Target 2060" /></a></p>

<p>From a candlestick pattern analysis, on the SPX, we formed a Doji yesterday and traded below that. This is once again negative on the year, so watch for continuation here. 2060 could still be the target until we see more downside.</p>

<p>The DJX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03232016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03232016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-03-23 Daily Time Frame - Trendline Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>We fell back from tagging that trendline resistance mentioned a couple of days ago - we may be starting to pick up momentum, so similar to the SPX, watch for continuation as well.</p>

<p>The NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03232016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03232016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-03-23 Daily Time Frame - Trading Below 61.% Fibonacci Retracement Level" /></a></p>

<p>As it has been recently, it was the weakest of the bunch, closing today below the 200 DMA and trading right below the 61.8% fib.</p>

<p>The RUT:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03232016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/03232016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-03-23 Daily Time Frame - 50% Fibonacci Retracement Level - Look Above and Fail" /></a></p>

<p>The look-above-and-fail pattern confirmed today and we took out all the gains, now sitting at the 50% fib. Also monitor for continuation to the downside here.</p>

<p>Essentially, all indices pointing down, and in my opinion, we should continue to see lower prices.</p>

<p>Here are the trades we entered in today if you followed me on Twitter:</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">SOLD 1/-1/1 CUSTOM <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24GDX&amp;src=ctag">$GDX</a> 100 APR 16/APR 16/APR 16 20.5/19.5/18.5 CALL/PUT/PUT @.14</p>&mdash; theta (@theta_positive) <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive/status/712634816756195329">March 23, 2016</a></blockquote>


<script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>




<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">SOLD VERTICAL <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24TSLA&amp;src=ctag">$TSLA</a> 100 APR 16 245/250 CALL <a href="https://twitter.com/1">@1</a>.20</p>&mdash; theta (@theta_positive) <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive/status/712658282419060738">March 23, 2016</a></blockquote>


<script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>




<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">SOLD VERTICAL <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24DIA&amp;src=ctag">$DIA</a> 100 (Weeklys) APR5 16 177.5/180 CALL @.88</p>&mdash; theta (@theta_positive) <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive/status/712712949941477376">March 23, 2016</a></blockquote>


<script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>


<p>No management is necessary for all current and existing trades. These have been added to the <a href="/trades" title="Trades">Trades page</a>, with risk graphs shown. I try to keep the risk graphs up-to-date as often as possible.</p>

<p>With that, I&rsquo;ll leave us once again with just one trade idea for tomorrow - FXI:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03232016/fxi.png"><img src="/images/blog/03232016/fxi.png" alt="FXI - 2016-03-23 Daily Time Frame - Fade China" /></a></p>

<p>We had a nice pop from last week, and a nice rally for a whole month now. I think a fade play here would be nice. Something like selling the APR 34 call and buying the 32/31 put vertical. I&rsquo;ll tweet out the trade.</p>

<p>Remember that the markets are closed on Friday.</p>

<p>If you haven&rsquo;t yet, <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> - you can see all my trades in real-time as they fill.</p>

<p>Trade safe, and trade small!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Decision Point]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/22/decision-point/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-22T20:38:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/22/decision-point</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Market stalls here.</p>

<p>We had the SPX close today on a Doji - this doesn&rsquo;t mean a reversal is coming, it just means indecision, or consolidation, before a break out higher or lower. The longer we consolidate, the more forceful the breakout, so do keep that in mind. Here&rsquo;s the SPX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03222016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03222016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-22 Daily Time Frame - Target 2060 - Consolidation" /></a></p>

<p>We actually peeked above the consolidation area not once, but twice, since yesterday. While that may seem bearish, keep in mind we did the same look-below-and-fail today. So still, trade is being dominated by short-term traders.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the DJX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03222016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03222016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-03-22 Daily Time Frame - Trendline Resistance Tag" /></a></p>

<p>It actually tagged that trendline resistance and fell back a bit, which was what we expected. If the markets continue to exhibit weakness tomorrow, I&rsquo;m considering the APR5 177.5/180 call spread going for .98 cr right now.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03222016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03222016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-03-22 Daily Time Frame - Grinding Higher" /></a></p>

<p>It actually continued higher today and was the strongest of the bunch. Not surprising here as it was the laggard for most of the huge rally that the SPX had.</p>

<p>And the RUT:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03222016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/03222016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-03-22 Daily Time Frame - Look Everywhere and Fail - Consolidation" /></a></p>

<p>Yesterday we were looking for either a follow through higher from possibly a bounce off of the trendline support, but we did not get that. Earlier during today&rsquo;s session, it appeared that yesterday&rsquo;s session was nothing but a look-above-and-fail, but by the end of today, we didn&rsquo;t have a look-below-and-fail, either. Again, indecision here, so keep your eyes peeled.</p>

<p>Overall, the indices spell very mixed signals. On one hand, you have the NDX up and the DJX down, but both SPX and RUT aren&rsquo;t sure where to go. The longer the market stays in a tight consolidation range, the more explosive the breakout. Stay aware.</p>

<p>Today we got filled on three trades:</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Still working the fly on it, but in the meantime: SOLD VERTICAL <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24PCLN&amp;src=ctag">$PCLN</a> 100 APR 16 1375/1380 CALL <a href="https://twitter.com/1">@1</a>.25</p>&mdash; theta (@theta_positive) <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive/status/712273450153283584">March 22, 2016</a></blockquote>


<script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>




<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">SOLD -COMBO <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24UNG&amp;src=ctag">$UNG</a> 100 (Weeklys) APR5 16 6.5/6 CALL/PUT @.13</p>&mdash; theta (@theta_positive) <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive/status/712295330461552640">March 22, 2016</a></blockquote>


<script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>




<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="ro" dir="ltr">SOLD VERTICAL <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24VXX&amp;src=ctag">$VXX</a> 100 APR 16 17.5/15 PUT @.58</p>&mdash; theta (@theta_positive) <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive/status/712352871283470336">March 22, 2016</a></blockquote>


<script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>


<p>These trades are now being logged in the <a href="/trades" title="Trades">Trades page</a> section of the site, so we&rsquo;ll continue monitoring these trades and managing as necessary. Updates will be posted on that page over time.</p>

<p>Potential trades for tomorrow:</p>

<p>Earlier today I was looking at PCLN as a potential candidate for a balanced butterfly, centered around the 1300 level. Here&rsquo;s why:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03222016/pcln.png"><img src="/images/blog/03222016/pcln.png" alt="PCLN - 2016-03-22 Daily Time Frame - Trendline Channel Support" /></a></p>

<p>There is an ascending trendline support which should end up at around 1300 by this Thursday. In the event of a slight downdraft in the markets, we may be able to find support here. There&rsquo;s also a rising channel support going back to the gap up from earnings. This should help the 1300 level act as a support as well.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03222016/pcln_risk_graph.png"><img src="/images/blog/03222016/pcln_risk_graph.png" alt="PCLN Risk Graph - 2016-03-22 - Balanced Butterfly" /></a></p>

<p>The 1310/1300/1290 butterfly is currently being priced for about .80 db. I&rsquo;ll be trying to lowball this for about .50.</p>

<p>And for DIA:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03222016/dia.png"><img src="/images/blog/03222016/dia.png" alt="DIA - 2016-03-22 Daily Time Frame - Short &amp; Long Strikes" /></a></p>

<p>In the market recap before, I mentioned that if the market exhibits weakness and we see all indices drop, a 177.5/180 call vertical on DIA would not be a bad idea.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03222016/dia_risk_graph.png"><img src="/images/blog/03222016/dia_risk_graph.png" alt="DIA Risk Graoh - 2016-03-22 - Vertical Credit Call Spread" /></a></p>

<p>It&rsquo;s currently being priced at about 1.01 cr for the spread expiring on APR5, but depending on when the fill happens and how much the market drops, it&rsquo;ll be lower.</p>

<p>Another trade idea here is GDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03222016/gdx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03222016/gdx.png" alt="GDX - 2016-03-22 Daily Time Frame - Channel Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m looking for a bit of a pullback from this big run that we&rsquo;ve had. As GDX stalls here, I&rsquo;m hoping to collect some premium on the call side, possibly the APR 21.5 naked call, and I&rsquo;m also looking to add a more bearish bias, as we&rsquo;re at the top of this channel resistance. To that effect, I&rsquo;m considering buying the 20/19 put spread, also in APR. Together, this should bring in about .22 cr.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03222016/gdx_risk_graph.png"><img src="/images/blog/03222016/gdx_risk_graph.png" alt="GDX Risk Graph - 2016-03-22 Daily Time Frame - Look Everywhere and Fail - Consolidation" /></a></p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today. I&rsquo;ll be posting my trades <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">live on Twitter</a>, so follow me to get those real-time notifications.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
