<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: value area | ThetaTrades]]></title>
  <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/categories/value-area/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-11-26T14:33:50-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[theta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nothing New]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/05/13/nothing-new/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-13T05:32:26-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/05/13/nothing-new</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="/images/blog/05132016/es.png"><img src="/images/blog/05132016/es.png" alt="/ES - 2016-05-13 - 15m Chart - Volume Profile" /></a></p>

<p>Yesterday, we had another day where value area overlapped the prior days&rsquo;s value area. Again, this spells low confidence - traders have a tough time getting prices to trend in any direction whatsoever. We had liquidation breaks followed by short squeezes closely following each other in many of the recent sessions (yesterday&rsquo;s price action showed that very clearly), so the struggle between the Bulls and the Bears continue.</p>

<p>The /ES is currently down approximately 4 points at the time of this writing. For today, I&rsquo;m not expecting much, as I&rsquo;m still neutral here until we get out of this low confidence environment and are able to establish a trend. Remember guys, don&rsquo;t be fooled by price; continue watching those value areas, and keep in mind the HVN at 2050 below us, and 2075 above us.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today&rsquo;s market outlook. As a side note, I&rsquo;ll be out of town until 5/23 and will have limited access to the blog during this time; however, I will still be managing our trades, so make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> - that&rsquo;s where I post all of my trade entries/adjustments/exits in real-time. To get the most out of Twitter, turn on notifications specifically from me to be able to get my tweets on your phone as they come.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets, and enjoy the weekend.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
