<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: books | ThetaTrades]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/categories/books/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-03-05T11:24:31-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[theta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Best Stock Trading Books Every Trader Should Read]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/02/18/the-best-stock-trading-books-every-trader-should-read/"/>
    <updated>2017-02-18T13:41:22-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/02/18/the-best-stock-trading-books-every-trader-should-read</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Whether or not you’re a professional trader, or just an average trader looking to become a professional, we believe that there are important books that discuss in depths the foundation of trading success. From psychology and discipline to execution, the concepts covered by the following books are a must-have in order to be successful in the trading business. Here is a list of the top four trading books we recommend, our detailed review of each, and why every trader should have them in their arsenal to create long-lasting wealth.<br/></p>

<p class="title">
<a href="http://amzn.to/2luN8En">Van Tharp - Trade Your Way to Financial Freedom</a> | (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/book/trade-your-way-to-financial/id502276916?mt=11">iBooks</a>)<br/>
<a class="book-image" target="_blank"  href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/007147871X/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&camp=1789&creative=9325&creativeASIN=007147871X&linkCode=as2&tag=thetatrades-20&linkId=c4b8fb5a73301abe6d1c790a889ba14f"><img border="0" src="//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?_encoding=UTF8&MarketPlace=US&ASIN=007147871X&ServiceVersion=20070822&ID=AsinImage&WS=1&Format=_SL250_&tag=thetatrades-20" ></a><img src="//ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=thetatrades-20&l=am2&o=1&a=007147871X" width="1" height="1" border="0" alt="" style="border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" />
</p>


<p>This is by far the best book that we believe every consistently profitable trader should read. Many average traders blindly believe that having a high probability of profit brings trading success, only to find out that in the long run, they still do not make money. Why is is that they have a track record of having more wins than losses, but still end up being net negative in their liquidity? In his book <em>Trade Your Way to Financial Freedom,</em> Van Tharp discusses the fundamental concepts from position sizing and risk management, to the more crucial concepts of R-multiples and proper backtesting. If you’re still looking for the “holy grail” chart setup or strategy that will make you rich an in instant, you need to stop where you are and pick up this book. Because the truth is, the only “holy grail” that you need to be looking for already exists within you - once you’ve read this book, you’ll figure out what is holding you back from scoring those big winners and being consistently profitable in the long run.<br/> <br/> <br/></p>

<p class="title">
<a href="http://amzn.to/2luFnyq">Mike Bellafiore - The Playbook</a> |
(<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/author/mike-bellafiore/id383955358?mt=11">iBooks</a>)<br/>
<a class="book-image" target="_blank"  href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0132937646/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&camp=1789&creative=9325&creativeASIN=0132937646&linkCode=as2&tag=thetatrades-20&linkId=f041a15427dae7c8762c15abd8af30f1"><img border="0" src="//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?_encoding=UTF8&MarketPlace=US&ASIN=0132937646&ServiceVersion=20070822&ID=AsinImage&WS=1&Format=_SL250_&tag=thetatrades-20" ></a><img src="//ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=thetatrades-20&l=am2&o=1&a=0132937646" width="1" height="1" border="0" alt="" style="border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" />
</p>


<p>In terms of trading discipline, <em>The Playbook</em> offers numerous accounts of day traders in Mike’s firm who went from just the average Joe to flat out professional. Through rigorous journaling and documentation of their trades and emotions, these traders eventually became consistent in following their methodology, and as a result, became consistently profitable. As you read through this book, pay attention to the journey of each of the traders - how they started, what their thought process was like, and how, eventually, the lightbulb went off in their head. But don’t expect to find the one chart setup that’ll make you rich quickly in this book either, unless you’re absolutely willing, like the mentioned traders, to put in the effort of creating your own Playbook and having the discipline to constantly review and refine your process.<br/> <br/> <br/></p>

<p class="title">
<a href="http://amzn.to/2luzykF">Michael Covel - Trend Following: Learn to Make Millions in Up or Down Markets</a> |
(<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/book/trend-following-updated-edition/id401494235?mt=11">iBooks</a>)<br/>
<a class="book-image" target="_blank"  href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/013702018X/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&camp=1789&creative=9325&creativeASIN=013702018X&linkCode=as2&tag=thetatrades-20&linkId=d4f3a693f1b481eed7b2da3cda3c0f67"><img border="0" src="//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?_encoding=UTF8&MarketPlace=US&ASIN=013702018X&ServiceVersion=20070822&ID=AsinImage&WS=1&Format=_SL250_&tag=thetatrades-20" ></a><img src="//ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=thetatrades-20&l=am2&o=1&a=013702018X" width="1" height="1" border="0" alt="" style="border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" />
</p>


<p>One of the biggest mistakes that average traders make is that they try to predict where the market goes, whether it is through fundamental analysis, or technical analysis via chart patterns like Head and Shoulders, Cup and Handle, Fibonacci Extensions, etc… The truth is, it doesn’t need to be that hard - there’s only one constant in trading that traders can trade off of, and that is price. And to make money off of price, one should follow the direction of price. In <em>Trend Following</em>, Michael Covel discusses the simple strategy of eliminating discretionary trading and implementing the systematic process of trading in the direction of the trend, in all types of markets To those that believe that this sounds boring because it may not seem like a “get rich quick” type of strategy, you’ll want to think about this next point: good trading isn’t fun - it’s mechanical, methodical, and should be outright boring, because that’s the kind of trading that makes money. If you’re still holding on to your losers and quickly taking profits when you see winners, but are having a hard time cutting your losses short and letting your winners run, then we highly recommend this book.<br/> <br/> <br/></p>

<p class="title">
<a href="http://amzn.to/2li6gU1">Edwin Lefevre - Reminiscences of a Stock Operator</a> |
(<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/audiobook/reminiscences-stock-operator/id371680538">iBooks</a>)<br/>
<a class="book-image" target="_blank"  href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0471770884/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&camp=1789&creative=9325&creativeASIN=0471770884&linkCode=as2&tag=thetatrades-20&linkId=d5dfe694031baee69506c078319044df"><img border="0" src="//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?_encoding=UTF8&MarketPlace=US&ASIN=0471770884&ServiceVersion=20070822&ID=AsinImage&WS=1&Format=_SL250_&tag=thetatrades-20" ></a><img src="//ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=thetatrades-20&l=am2&o=1&a=0471770884" width="1" height="1" border="0" alt="" style="border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" />
</p>


<p>This is a book which walks through the life of Jesse Livermore, a securities trader. Throughout his trading career, Livermore learned many lessons, now shared in this book, from making a lot of money, to losing a lot more. Like some of the other books, this too does not offer the perfect “chart setup” that will make you get rich quickly - instead, it provides the fundamental strategies of maintaining proper trading psychology, the ultimate aspect of consistently profitable traders. To quote from an excerpt in the book:</p>

<blockquote><p>The reason is that a man may see straight and clearly and yet become impatient or doubtful when the market takes its time about doing as he figured it must do. That is why so many men in Wall Street, who are not at all in the sucker class, not even in the third grade, nevertheless lose money. The market does not beat them. They beat themselves, because though they have brains they cannot sit tight.</p></blockquote>

<p>If you want to know what you should and should not do when it comes to trading psychology, then start reading this entertaining, yet inspiring novel, and be prepared to change your trading psychology and approach to the markets.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
