<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: cmg | ThetaTrades]]></title>
  <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/categories/cmg/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-11-26T14:33:50-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[theta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Couple of Weekend Trade Ideas]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/05/01/weekend-trade-ideas/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-01T19:37:05-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/05/01/weekend-trade-ideas</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If we&rsquo;re expecting a bit of retracement in the broad market indices, we can take a look at IWM.</p>

<p>With volatility picking up, we can also look at put calendars.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the Fibonacci fan on the IWM over the February rally which shows us potential retracement areas in the future:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05012016/iwm_fib_fan.png"><img src="/images/blog/05012016/iwm_fib_fan.png" alt="IWM - 2016-05-01 - Volume Composite" /></a></p>

<p>If we&rsquo;re looking for an upcoming retracement, it helps to combine this fan with the volume profile over the past 20 days to figure out where price would have a predisposition to trade near, and see where the fan and the high volume node areas intersect. This will help us figure out the strike and expiry of our put calendar. With that, here&rsquo;s the volume profile over the past 20 days:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05012016/iwm_volume.png"><img src="/images/blog/05012016/iwm_volume.png" alt="IWM - 2016-05-01 - Volume Composite" /></a></p>

<p>The high volume node is near 109.5 and it seems to intersect the fan about two weeks out. I&rsquo;ve highlighted this potential area in oval. This means a potential trade setup is the 109.5 put calendar, with the short strike expiring next Friday, and the long strike next next Friday. Here&rsquo;s the risk graph:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05012016/iwm_risk_graph.png"><img src="/images/blog/05012016/iwm_risk_graph.png" alt="IWM - 2016-05-01 - Risk Graph" /></a></p>

<p>The same thing can be done with others as well. Here&rsquo;s CMG on the weekly:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05012016/cmg_weekly.png"><img src="/images/blog/05012016/cmg_weekly.png" alt="CMG - 2016-05-01 - Weekly" /></a></p>

<p>Hanging on right above that long-term trendline support. Zooming in:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05012016/cmg_hourly.png"><img src="/images/blog/05012016/cmg_hourly.png" alt="CMG - 2016-05-01 - Hourly" /></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m expecting CMG to bounce, unless the overall market exhibits extreme bearishness. If we do see that bounce, the gap made post-earnings could fill and we could potentially place a trade near the high volume node around 460 over the next couple of weeks.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the risk graph:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05012016/cmg_risk_graph.png"><img src="/images/blog/05012016/cmg_risk_graph.png" alt="CMG - 2016-05-01 - Risk Graph" /></a></p>

<p>If the debit is too much, consider selling some credit spreads against it.</p>

<p>This is just an idea - combining the volume composite with other TA tools like the Fibonacci fan. Feel free to apply this to things you plan on trading - it only helps. Anyway, we&rsquo;ll see how well these couple of trade ideas work out. I&rsquo;ll be looking to place these trades on, so make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a>, because that&rsquo;s where I post all of my trades in real-time.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets tomorrow!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Market Still Pausing]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/05/market-still-pausing/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-05T21:23:05-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/05/market-still-pausing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There isn&rsquo;t a lot pointing to the Bears being in full control, yet. For now, it still appears to just be consolidation. I am still watching for a break below 2033.5 on the /ES with strong follow-through before I turn bearish.</p>

<p>Looking at the SPX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04052016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04052016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-04-05 - Daily - Look-Above-And-Fail" /></a></p>

<p>Today it appears we formed a look-above-and-fail pattern - I&rsquo;d like to see follow-through to the downside for confirmation.</p>

<p>DJX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04052016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04052016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-04-05 - Daily - Sitting at Trendline Support" /></a></p>

<p>We closed just at trendline support. Let&rsquo;s see if it holds.</p>

<p>NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04052016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04052016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-04-05 - Daily - Consolidation" /></a></p>

<p>This appears to just be consolidating over the past 5 trading days.</p>

<p>RUT:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04052016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/04052016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-04-05 - Daily - Consolidation" /></a></p>

<p>We&rsquo;re now below the 61.8% Fib level. We&rsquo;ve now traded near and around the 61.8% Fib level many times - consolidation is still happening here.</p>

<p>Ok - we haven&rsquo;t been putting on many trades this week. This is largely due to my reluctance to sell premium in a cycle that contains earnings, but I&rsquo;ve managed to find some that avoid it with good weeklies.</p>

<p>I wanted to go back to GS which I mentioned the other day:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04032016/gs_batman.png"><img src="/images/blog/04032016/gs_batman.png" alt="GS - 2016-04-05 - Put Backratio With Call Backratio" /></a></p>

<p>Though this play contains an earnings cycle, I&rsquo;ve noticed that it doesn&rsquo;t quite move much from earnings reports. I wouldn&rsquo;t mind putting this on tomorrow - with pretty wide breakevens, we can aim for a move towards both ends of the spectrum, regardless of which way the market moves. Just as long as it doesn&rsquo;t crash, of course. This is currently being priced in at a .67 cr.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve also got a couple of calendars/diagonals for play here.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s DIS:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04052016/dis.png"><img src="/images/blog/04052016/dis.png" alt="DIS - 2016-04-05 - Daily" /></a></p>

<p>Aiming for 90 by the 4th week of April:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04052016/dis_diagonal.png"><img src="/images/blog/04052016/dis_diagonal.png" alt="DIS - 2016-04-05 - Diagonal Put" /></a></p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s EEM:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04052016/eem.png"><img src="/images/blog/04052016/eem.png" alt="EEM - 2016-04-05 - Daily" /></a></p>

<p>Aiming for 30 by the 5th week of April:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04052016/eem_calendar.png"><img src="/images/blog/04052016/eem_calendar.png" alt="EEM - 2016-04-05 - Put Calendar" /></a></p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s CMG:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04052016/cmg.png"><img src="/images/blog/04052016/cmg.png" alt="CMG - 2016-04-05 - Daily - Slow Grind to 420" /></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m looking for a slow grind down to 420:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04052016/cmg_calendar.png"><img src="/images/blog/04052016/cmg_calendar.png" alt="CMG - 2016-04-05 - Put Calendar" /></a></p>

<p>All of these require a debit, but when volatility is low, these are good deals. If we get the directional move we want and volatility expands and time decays the nearer-term option, the spread can really expand nicely.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for now. I&rsquo;ll most likely be putting these trades on, so <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> to get my updates. Also, to make the most out of Twitter, make sure you turn on notifications specifically from me. Just visit my Twitter profile on mobile, select the Settings gear, and turn on notifications.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets tomorrow!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monitoring for Continuation]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/04/monitoring-for-continuation/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-04T20:26:18-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/04/monitoring-for-continuation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today&rsquo;s action is just balancing after a trending move. For me to consider this bearish, I&rsquo;d want to see 2033.5 on the /ES get taken out. I&rsquo;d like to see value move lower as well. Also, the highs from the overnight session usually don&rsquo;t mark the end of up-moves, so expect 2071.5 to be revisited sometime soon, and if it doesn&rsquo;t, carry that information forward.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the SPX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04042016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04042016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-04-04 - Daily - Consolidation Above Trendline Support" /></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m looking for this to hold up at the trendline support. A failure to remain above it is an edge to the Bears.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the DJX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04042016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04042016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-04-04 - Daily - Consolidation" /></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m also looking for this to hold up at the trendline support.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04042016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04042016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-04-04 - Daily - Consolidation" /></a></p>

<p>Looks like a pause before a continuation higher.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the RUT:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04042016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/04042016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-04-04 - Daily - 61.8% Fib Level" /></a></p>

<p>This is a bit more interesting. Still holding above the 61.8 Fib level and may just slowly grind around here until it touches the trendline resistance.</p>

<p>For those looking for a bearish play, I&rsquo;ve been looking at CMG. We have a trendline support coming up on the weekly:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04042016/cmg_weekly.png"><img src="/images/blog/04042016/cmg_weekly.png" alt="CMG - 2016-04-04 - Weekly" /></a></p>

<p>As well as a revisit of the prior lows at 400 on the daily:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04042016/cmg.png"><img src="/images/blog/04042016/cmg.png" alt="CMG - 2016-04-04 - Daily" /></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m looking to place a small butterfly to capture a move down into the 400 area:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04042016/cmg_risk_graph.png"><img src="/images/blog/04042016/cmg_risk_graph.png" alt="CMG - 2016-04-04 - Risk Graph" /></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;ll be tweeting out my entry on this trade depending on how it&rsquo;s priced, so make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> <em>and</em> turn on notifications from my profile (on mobile - hit the settings gear on my profile and then select &ldquo;Turn On Notifications&rdquo;). You&rsquo;ll receive push notifications for all of my tweets.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets tomorrow!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sideways Until ECB]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/09/sideways-until-ecb/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-09T19:24:58-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/09/sideways-until-ecb</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The markets continue to move sideways before the ECB announcement tomorrow. Not a lot of volume was traded today. Be cautious heading into the event.</p>

<p>TRIP continues to move to the downside. For those who shorted this from yesterday&rsquo;s trade idea, just trail your stop loss. We may get another bounce at around 60 (we got one today) before we head to the previous lows.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03092016/trip.png"><img src="/images/blog/03092016/trip.png" alt="TRIP - 2016-03-09 Daily Time Frame - Rising Wedge Breakdown" /></a></p>

<p>CMG gapped lower due to some news. For those who shorted this from yesterday&rsquo;s trade idea, just continue to trail your stop loss here as well.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03092016/cmg.png"><img src="/images/blog/03092016/cmg.png" alt="CMG - 2016-03-09 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement" /></a></p>

<p>Personally, I don&rsquo;t know how much Draghi can do to rally the markets higher. In my opinion, whatever easing he&rsquo;s thinking of implementing is already priced in by the market. If he fails to deliver nothing more than a huge amount of money, the market will probably not take that as a good sign. Just saying. Whatever the case, be prepared.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today, have a safe trading day tomorrow.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monitor for Continuation]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/08/monitor-for-continuation/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-08T18:24:59-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/08/monitor-for-continuation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>All broad market indices traded lower today.</p>

<p>SPX erases the past 3 days of trading:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03082016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03082016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-08 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement" /></a></p>

<p>NDX continues to form lower Dojis:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03082016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03082016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-03-08 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement" /></a></p>

<p>DJX forms a swing high:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03082016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03082016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-03-08 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement" /></a></p>

<p>RUT forms a swing high and had the biggest drop in % today.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03082016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/03082016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-03-08 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement" /></a></p>

<p>This could be the start of a new (down) trend, but given how nervous traders are out there, I would not be surprised if we gap up tomorrow; thus, monitor the markets for a continued move down.</p>

<p>Let&rsquo;s take a look at a couple of bearish trades that may pan out if the market continues to roll over:</p>

<p>/CL erased all of its gains from yesterday - this is quite bearish. Look for a break below 36. If sellers start coming in hard, then we&rsquo;ve got a &ldquo;look above and fail&rdquo; pattern, which would be a short signal. Keep a close eye on this.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03082016/cl_f.png"><img src="/images/blog/03082016/cl_f.png" alt="/CL - 2016-03-08 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement and Harmonic Pattern" /></a></p>

<p>CMG exhibited a dark cloud cover pattern today, with a double top on the daily, and a small topping tail. The APR 600/610 call spread is currently trading for 0.97 cr.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03082016/cmg.png"><img src="/images/blog/03082016/cmg.png" alt="CMG - 2016-03-08 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement, Dark Cloud Cover, Double Top" /></a></p>

<p>TRIP has been a bit confused about where it wanted to go for the previous 4 days before today. Today&rsquo;s price action broke us out of a rising wedge. If bearishness continues, we can easily head to the lower 50s.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03082016/cmg.png"><img src="/images/blog/03082016/cmg.png" alt="TRIP - 2016-03-08 Daily Time Frame - Rising Wedge" /></a></p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today. Good luck in the markets tomorrow. Stay small, and stay safe.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
