<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: hal | ThetaTrades]]></title>
  <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/categories/hal/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-05-05T06:03:32-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[theta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Will the Bears Continue the Selling Pressure?]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/21/will-the-bears-continue-the-selling-pressure/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-21T18:49:01-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/21/will-the-bears-continue-the-selling-pressure</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We saw a nice liquidation break today, and actually saw the first sign of sellers being able to keep that pressure on throughout the entire RTH session. Let&rsquo;s take a look at the overall volume profile over the past 20 days:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04212016/es.png"><img src="/images/blog/04212016/es.png" alt="/ES - 2016-04-21 - Volume Profile - 20 days" /></a></p>

<p>We can see that today, not only did we clearly create value lower, but also look where the point of control migrated to: basically back to where it was on Monday. We&rsquo;re now exploring this area to see if this is the fairest price to do business.</p>

<p>And if we zoom in and take a closer look at the past couple of weeks:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04212016/es_zoomed.png"><img src="/images/blog/04212016/es_zoomed.png" alt="/ES - 2016-04-21 - Volume Profile - Zoomed In - Value Area Gapping Lower" /></a></p>

<p>Notice today, our value area not only migrated lower, but also it did not overlap yesterday&rsquo;s value area. When value areas gap like this, it <em>generally</em> signifies the start of a new trend (although a larger gap would&rsquo;ve been better to signify stronger selling pressure). Will the selling continue tomorrow? We can only wait to find out, but until then, bias is neutral.</p>

<p>Going forward, here are important reference points to keep in mind: I&rsquo;ll be watching how the <strong>2081.75</strong> level holds tomorrow. <strong>The area between 2067 and 2081.75 can be considered a balance area</strong>, which was formed last week for a few days before we broke higher out of it this Monday. If we fall back into this area tomorrow and we start seeing some really strong selling pressure (watch the internals), look to target the other side of that balance area, which is <strong>2067</strong>.</p>

<p>Before wrapping up, I&rsquo;d like to propose a trade idea, which I haven&rsquo;t in a while. Here&rsquo;s <strong>HAL</strong> on the daily:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04212016/hal.png"><img src="/images/blog/04212016/hal.png" alt="HAL - 2016-04-21 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m looking to position a trade around <strong>HAL</strong> that assumes the analog of what happened last year would happen again this year. If so, a trade that captures a slow retracement to the bottom of the right orange rectangle over the next month or so would probably be ideal.</p>

<p>I couldn&rsquo;t find any butterflies/put backratios that were great, so I was thinking a small calendar play may work here, specifically, the JUN/MAY 36 PUT calendar:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04212016/hal_calendar.png"><img src="/images/blog/04212016/hal_calendar.png" alt="HAL - 2016-04-21 - Put Calendar" /></a></p>

<p>This is a much longer-term play, and we&rsquo;ll need to wait probably around a month or so for the premium to really start coming in. If you have a slight bearish bias on the energy sector, this could be the play for you.</p>

<p>One thing to note is that this company does have earnings coming up, but I&rsquo;m not really expecting the stock to move much to the downside, and we have quite some time for the trade to work out for us. I&rsquo;ll be looking to put this trade on tomorrow, so be on the lookout for that.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today - as always, make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a>. That is where I post all of my trades in real-time. Make sure you turn on notifications specifically from me. Just go to my Twitter profile on your mobile device, select the Settings gear, and then select the option to turn on notifications.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets tomorrow, and remember to keep those reference points in mind on the /ES.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
