<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: nflx | ThetaTrades]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/categories/nflx/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-02-28T18:07:53-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[theta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Long NFLX]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/02/07/long-nflx/"/>
    <updated>2017-02-07T18:17:01-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/02/07/long-nflx</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Those that love $NFLX, it just broke to a new all time high. Here are a few ways to play it.</p>

<p>Please observe the chart below.</p>

<h3 id="20170207-nflx">$NFLX</h3>


<p><a href="/images/blog/20170207/nflx.png"><img src="/images/blog/20170207/nflx.png" alt="$NFLX - 2017-02-07 - Daily" /></a></p>

<p>With the new high today for this stock, it has the potential to continue its thrust upwards in the near term. Consider buying front-month call spreads or naked calls. Perhaps an OOM naked call, or a call vertical like so:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/20170207/nflxoc.png"><img src="/images/blog/20170207/nflxoc.png" alt="NFLX Options Chain - Call Vertical - 2017-02-07 - Daily" /></a></p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re interested in more ideas like this, <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow us on Twitter</a> or <a href="https://facebook.com/thetatrades" title="Follow @thetatrades on Facebook">Facebook</a> to receive our tweets and posts in real time! And if you haven&rsquo;t yet, subscribe to our email listing below to receive special email alerts as well.</p>

<p><div class="subscribe-button">
	<button>Subscribe to Our Updates</button>
</div>
</p>

<!-- <script src="//z-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/onejs?MarketPlace=US&adInstanceId=3c36f001-e4b7-4c98-bffa-716b4f4878ab"></script>
 -->

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Expecting Some Consolidation]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/05/26/expecting-some-consolidation/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-26T05:57:04-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/05/26/expecting-some-consolidation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here&rsquo;s the volume composite again on the /ES over the past month:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05262016/es.png"><img src="/images/blog/05262016/es.png" alt="/ES - 2016-05-26 - 1h Chart - Volume Composite" /></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m still watching the high volume nodes at 2075 and 2085 to see how they develop.</p>

<p>This past week, we&rsquo;ve seen value area gapping higher, which is bullish. After a few sessions, expect a pause and some rebalancing before the trend either continues or reverses. We may get that pause today as we&rsquo;re trading near the highest high volume node.</p>

<p>Yesterday we put on call calendars on AAPL and NFLX. AAPL hasn&rsquo;t done much since, but NFLX looks to be trading up 4 premarket. This is good for our short term calendar, but our longer term call ratio will be hurting a bit here. No worries as we have time to work it out, and our breakeven is a bit above 105, which is the gap fill. We&rsquo;ll see what happens and adjust if necessary.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today&rsquo;s morning market outlook. We&rsquo;ll be doing more trade adjustments today, so as always, make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me there</a> to receive tweets about our trades in real-time.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Market Still Remains in Balance - Be Theta Positive]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/05/24/market-still-remains-in-balance-be-theta-positive/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-24T05:17:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/05/24/market-still-remains-in-balance-be-theta-positive</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In a market that barely moves these days, it&rsquo;s great when the core of your portfolio is theta positive. We already are, but this is just an emphasis on that fact.</p>

<p>The market is still stuck within the large balance area between 2080 and 2012, with 2052 being a very prominent volume node:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05242016/es.png"><img src="/images/blog/05242016/es.png" alt="/ES - 2016-05-24 - 1h Chart - Volume Composite" /></a></p>

<p>The next prominent HVN over the past 30 days appears to be 2075, which is towards the upper end of this balance area. 2075 would be the first upside target to aim for if we see the market move higher. Placing a butterfly there for a credit would be a great play, or some kind of a call ratio with more room to the upside. I&rsquo;ll be looking for something to do here.</p>

<p>Volume has been extremely low during these past trading sessions, but for us, it doesn&rsquo;t really matter. Keep that in mind, though, as a breakout of the balance area may cause volume to start picking back up again, and depending on your portfolio, you may need to adjust.</p>

<p>Yesterday we opened new trades on $NFLX, $TGT and $ES_F. These all seem to be looking good so far. Keep an eye on $NFLX - I think it&rsquo;s going to be interesting seeing how it plays out.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for the market outlook. As always, we&rsquo;ll be entering new trades and adjusting/exiting our existing positions, so be sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow us on Twitter</a>.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets today!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
