<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: /cl | theta trades]]></title>
  <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/categories/slash-cl/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-03-24T22:07:31-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[theta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Short Term Traders Dominating]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/10/short-term-traders-dominating/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-10T19:09:16-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/10/short-term-traders-dominating</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The market has been doing nothing other than balancing over the past 8 trading sessions. We&rsquo;re bracketing, and it&rsquo;s apparent that the market is being dominated by the shorter term traders looking to buy at the bottom of balance and sell at the top. We&rsquo;re unable to push prices higher, and today, we look below and failed. All of this price action over the past couple of weeks paints a very clear picture: traders have extremely low confidence.</p>

<p>While one can argue that the market seems bearish because Mario wasn&rsquo;t able to push prices higher with his market manipulation techniques, one can also argue that if we were truly bearish, we wouldn&rsquo;t have look outside below balance, and then come back in. We settled today at the point of control, which has just been getting more and more prominent over the past couple of weeks. Traders just like it here.</p>

<p>Today we formed a poor low in the /ES. Expect that to be repaired in the (possibly near) future.</p>

<p>/CL seems a bit confused about where it wants to go. We&rsquo;ve had back to back days that just completely engulfed the previous days, until today, when we closed on a Doji:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03102016/cl_f.png"><img src="/images/blog/03102016/cl_f.png" alt="/CL - 2016-03-10 Daily Time Frame - Doji, Fibonacci" /></a></p>

<p>Crude looks like it wants to hit 40 or the 61.8% fib level. I&rsquo;ve set up the 39.5/40/40.5 balanced butterfly for a 0.30 debit.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today. Good luck and happy trading in in the markets tomorrow.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monitor for Continuation]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/08/monitor-for-continuation/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-08T18:24:59-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/08/monitor-for-continuation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>All broad market indices traded lower today.</p>

<p>SPX erases the past 3 days of trading:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03082016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03082016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-08 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement" /></a></p>

<p>NDX continues to form lower Dojis:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03082016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03082016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-03-08 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement" /></a></p>

<p>DJX forms a swing high:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03082016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03082016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-03-08 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement" /></a></p>

<p>RUT forms a swing high and had the biggest drop in % today.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03082016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/03082016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-03-08 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement" /></a></p>

<p>This could be the start of a new (down) trend, but given how nervous traders are out there, I would not be surprised if we gap up tomorrow; thus, monitor the markets for a continued move down.</p>

<p>Let&rsquo;s take a look at a couple of bearish trades that may pan out if the market continues to roll over:</p>

<p>/CL erased all of its gains from yesterday - this is quite bearish. Look for a break below 36. If sellers start coming in hard, then we&rsquo;ve got a &ldquo;look above and fail&rdquo; pattern, which would be a short signal. Keep a close eye on this.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03082016/cl_f.png"><img src="/images/blog/03082016/cl_f.png" alt="/CL - 2016-03-08 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement and Harmonic Pattern" /></a></p>

<p>CMG exhibited a dark cloud cover pattern today, with a double top on the daily, and a small topping tail. The APR 600/610 call spread is currently trading for 0.97 cr.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03082016/cmg.png"><img src="/images/blog/03082016/cmg.png" alt="CMG - 2016-03-08 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement, Dark Cloud Cover, Double Top" /></a></p>

<p>TRIP has been a bit confused about where it wanted to go for the previous 4 days before today. Today&rsquo;s price action broke us out of a rising wedge. If bearishness continues, we can easily head to the lower 50s.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03082016/cmg.png"><img src="/images/blog/03082016/cmg.png" alt="TRIP - 2016-03-08 Daily Time Frame - Rising Wedge" /></a></p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today. Good luck in the markets tomorrow. Stay small, and stay safe.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Keeping an Eye Out on Indices and Crude Oil]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/07/indices/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-07T13:42:40-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/07/indices</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The markets continue to grind higher, with the SPX closing today above the 61.8% fib level. The likely target is the descending trendline resistance, which should be around 2020:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03072016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03072016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-07 Daily Time Frame - Descending Trendline Resistance &amp; Fibonacci Retracement" /></a></p>

<p>Looking at the DJX, it has also closed above the 61.8% fib level:
<a href="/images/blog/03072016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03072016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-03-07 Daily Time Frame - Descending Trendline Resistance and Fibonacci Retracement" /></a></p>

<p>Of course, the strongest of them all, RUT, grinds higher:
<a href="/images/blog/03072016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/03072016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-03-07 Daily Time Frame - Ascending Trendline Support as Resistance and Fibonacci Retracement" /></a></p>

<p>And then, interestingly enough the NDX, which has been having a hard time getting some love:
<a href="/images/blog/03072016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03072016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-03-07 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement" /></a></p>

<p>Whatever the case, it looks like the markets are mostly pointing to being neutral or moving higher. Unless the Bears have more confidence, this market will most likely continue to meander up here, dominated by many short term traders. Look for yesterday&rsquo;s trade idea on the market for ideas on trade location.</p>

<p>Moving over to /CL.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03072016/cl_f.png"><img src="/images/blog/03072016/cl_f.png" alt="/CL - 2016-03-07 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement and Harmonic Pattern" /></a></p>

<p>/CL is approaching its previous resistance levels, as well as the 50% fib level (Oct - Feb). Furthermore, a <a href="http://www.harmonictrader.com/price_patternsabcd.htm" title="harmonic pattern">harmonic pattern AB=CD</a> could be forming again (we saw one form from last May to last August, and a completion of the pattern from last October to last month). If we do see crude oil begin to roll over, we can initiate a short position, giving us a good trade location. However, for confirmation, I&rsquo;d like to see it trade below 35 again before shorting. For now, do keep an eye out on /CL.</p>

<p>For those that are a bit more aggressive, you may consider selling a call vertical here on /CL. The MAY 42/42.5 call spread (39 DTE) is trading for .15 cr currently, or the 42/43 call spread, currently trading for .28 cr.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today, happy trading out there, and enjoy the markets tomorrow.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
