<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: fomc | theta trades]]></title>
  <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/categories/fomc/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-03-17T18:05:30-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[theta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Market Continues to Upside]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/16/market-continues-to-upside/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-16T19:27:04-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/16/market-continues-to-upside</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yellen did it again, and the markets rally higher. Let&rsquo;s take a look:</p>

<p>As mentioned for a while now, SPX is still on track to tag the 2060 level:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03162016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03162016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-16 Daily Time Frame - Target 2060 - Harmonic Pattern" /></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve outlined the range of last year&rsquo;s October rally and duplicated that line over to the rally we&rsquo;ve had from February to estimate the target of this rally (AKA Harmonic Pattern), and it matches perfectly with the descending trendline resistance. Given this projection, we should reach that target zone in about two weeks.</p>

<p>Keep in mind that SPX opened this year at 2038.2. Look for some resistance over there as well. A failure to take this market back up through the open (just like in day-trading when we fail to take out the open) is a short signal. But if we plow through this and move higher with ease, expect 2060.</p>

<p>Taking a look at the DJX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03162016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03162016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-03-16 Daily Time Frame - Descending Trendline Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>Pretty bullish here. It just broke the descending trendline resistance, which makes a big dent in the bear case. The next target is that next trendline resistance.</p>

<p>Moving over to the NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03162016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03162016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-03-16 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci" /></a></p>

<p>This tagged the 61.8% fib today and backed off, but given how all the other indices look, this would have no problem busting through it that, which makes the next target the descending trendline resistance.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the RUT:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03162016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/03162016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-03-16 Daily Time Frame - Bull Flag" /></a></p>

<p>Though it&rsquo;s weak, we could be setting up for a bull flag breakout.</p>

<p>Watch all of the indices closely. The best trade idea for SPX is setting up a butterfly with the short strikes centered at 2060, expiring on Mar5.</p>

<p>That wraps it up for today. Trade safe, and trade small. Good luck in the markets!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
