<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: weak sellers | ThetaTrades]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/categories/weak-sellers/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-03-05T11:24:31-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[theta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bullish into Next Week]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/02/bullish-into-next-week/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-02T11:29:57-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/02/bullish-into-next-week</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m certain the markets will continue to climb higher next week.</p>

<p>There are just not enough sellers out there. On Friday, we were able to enter into the second distribution area from the Janet Yellen day:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04022016/es.png"><img src="/images/blog/04022016/es.png" alt="/ES - 2016-04-02 - Weak Sellers Failing to Take Market Lower Regardless of Poor Structure" /></a></p>

<p>But before spending enough time there, we couldn&rsquo;t find more sellers to come in. What I was expecting to happen when we broke into the second distribution area was that we at least test the 2033.5 level (and it should be relatively easy to get there due to the extremely poor structure). Obviously that didn&rsquo;t happen, and instead, on Friday during RTH, we ended up moving back up over the overnight low and through the open (which was a strong buy signal). Overnight shorts did not get paid, got nervous, and we saw the market run higher for the rest of the day.</p>

<p>Is that bearish? No. Sellers are extremely nervous out there still, and looking at the tape, every time they tried to take this market lower, they completely failed, even when structurally it was easy for them to do so. So regardless of how overbought this market is right now, we should be thinking bullish into next week. We&rsquo;ll have some trade ideas presented later this weekend based around this bullish bias, but first:</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the SPX on the daily:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04022016/spx_daily.png"><img src="/images/blog/04022016/spx_daily.png" alt="SPX - 2016-04-02 - Daily - Bullish - Trendline Resistance Becomes Trendline Support" /></a></p>

<p>Notice how we tried to break down, but ended up finding support at what was previously the trendline resistance. A classic look below and fail pattern - <strong>pretty bullish</strong>. First target here is the top of the range extension denoted by the top right pink box, which is around 2084, followed by the next trendline resistance at around 2090, and then the even 2100.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the SPX on the weekly:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04022016/spx_weekly.png"><img src="/images/blog/04022016/spx_weekly.png" alt="SPX - 2016-04-02 - Weekly" /></a></p>

<p>Strong momentum.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the DJX on the weekly:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04022016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04022016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-04-02 - Weekly - Breaking Trendline Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>Again, strong momentum. It actually broke through the trendline resistance. Target here would be 180.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the NDX on the weekly:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04022016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04022016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-04-02 - Weekly - 61.8% Fib Level Acts as Support" /></a></p>

<p>It found support off that 61.8% Fib level. Next target is that trendline resistance.</p>

<p>Finally the RUT:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04022016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/04022016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-04-02 - Weekly" /></a></p>

<p>Which looks like it may just plow through that trendline resistance, and if so, the next target would be back up to 1200.</p>

<p>Given the doubt that many have on how much higher this market can really run, but keeping in mind the bullish targets explained just above, I have a few options trade ideas that may work well just for this scenario. This will be done in a separate post which I will tweet out later this weekend, so stay tuned, and <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me</a> if you haven&rsquo;t already so that you&rsquo;ll know about it right when I tweet it out.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
