<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: fundamentals | ThetaTrades]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/categories/fundamentals/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-02-28T18:07:53-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[theta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fundamentals - Should They Matter]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/02/28/fundamentals-should-they-matter/"/>
    <updated>2017-02-28T07:47:29-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/02/28/fundamentals-should-they-matter</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When people want to start investing in stocks, usually, they are told to look into the fundamentals of the company.</p>

<p>However, before they start doing that, the most important thing that they should do is ask themselves is why they want to invest in stocks. Do they want to invest because they want to make money?</p>

<p>Sounds like a pretty silly question, we know. Obviously (or hopefully), the answer is yes.</p>

<p>It’s important for everyone to take a moment to clarify this simple question with themselves, because many go into the stock market telling themselves that they want to make money, but when the tide starts to turn and the stocks that they own start selling off, they’re unable to let go of their original bias. They begin to come up with reasons why they should continue holding:</p>

<blockquote><p>There&rsquo;s no way this stock can go to 0. With such positive news coming out on the company these days, it has got to start going up.</p>

<p>The CEO is a amazing person - he/she will turn things around, I know it, and I believe in him/her.</p>

<p>I believe in their product. Last year they increased sales, and they&rsquo;ll do it again this year. I believe the company will continue to innovate and produce results. The market is just panicking right now for no reason.</p></blockquote>

<p>At this point, are these traders still investing because they want to make money? Or are they investing simply because they want to be right?</p>

<p>Though they might not be aware of this bias when they first start out, they eventually are guilty of committing this major investing flaw.</p>

<p>Assuming people want to invest in the stock market because they want to make money, if they want to be successful in this endeavor, it’s important to understand that the only thing that matters is <strong>price</strong>. Very often, the fundamentals of a company cannot easily be predicted. And even if you could predict it, it&rsquo;s more than likely a guess, and the market probably would have already priced in the outlook, so by the time that people actually want to trade that knowledge, it is already too late and not actionable.</p>

<p>Using the fundamentals of a company to buy or sell a stock is very dangerous, because it creates a bias which may cause traders to hold on to losers longer than they probably should. In the end, people invest in stocks in order to make money. If a company were to go bankrupt, it makes sense that they won’t continue to hold the stock and watch the net liquidity in their stock position go to 0.</p>

<p>However, you would be surprised to find that many continue to hold on to their losers, because they don’t want to be wrong. It’s human nature to feed our egos; we all have a “need to be right” mentality somewhere deep inside us, so we start looking at fundamentals to find reasons why we’re still holding on to a losing stock. We look for news that substantiates our bias, and ignore those that don&rsquo;t support our position.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, even when the company is cashflow positive, P/E ratios are reasonable, and dividends are high, a stock can still continue to sell off, and novice traders are left holding the bag for the next X years, praying that all else goes well and that they get their money back.</p>

<p>With all due respect to many of fundamentalists out there, we believe that looking towards fundamentals ultimately ends up creating unnecessary noise for traders, causing them to use the news as excuses to explain why they either buy, hold, or sell a stock.</p>

<p>It doesn&rsquo;t need to be that complicated. Just tune out the noise, ignore the fundamentals, and focus on price.</p>

<p>What is the price telling you? Is the stock trending up? Down? Sideways? If so, trade in the direction of the trend. It&rsquo;s that simple! Looking at price and trading with the trend, with proper risk management through position sizing (an arena often glossed over by many beginning investors), is what ultimately yields big profits in the long run.</p>

<p><em>Stay tuned for our next post, where we discuss in detail how to look at price to determine the trend and trade with it.</em></p>

<p><em>If you haven&rsquo;t yet, subscribe to our email list below to receive notifications on new posts and special offers.</em></p>

<p><div class="subscribe-button">
	<button>Subscribe to Our Updates</button>
</div>
</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
