<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: hvn | ThetaTrades]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/categories/hvn/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-02-04T16:15:11-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[theta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Watch Development of HVN at 2075-2085]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/05/25/watch-development-of-hvn-at-2075-2085/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-25T06:27:07-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/05/25/watch-development-of-hvn-at-2075-2085</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>/ES broke out of the descending channel yesterday and closed strong above it. This is slightly bullish, but in a long term perspective, still neutral:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05252016/es.png"><img src="/images/blog/05252016/es.png" alt="/ES - 2016-05-25 - 1h Chart - Volume Composite" /></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m expecting tomorrow&rsquo;s action to pause a bit, especially after such a rally. If this happens, it only makes the developing volume node at 2075 more prominent.</p>

<p>Watch how the volume composite develops throughout this week. 2075 to 2085 could become the high volume node over the past 30 days. Also, developing value at the upper end of the balance area primes us for a stronger breakout to the upside.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for the market outlook. As always, we&rsquo;ll be entering new trades and adjusting/exiting our existing positions, so be sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow us on Twitter</a>.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Market Still Remains in Balance - Be Theta Positive]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/05/24/market-still-remains-in-balance-be-theta-positive/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-24T05:17:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/05/24/market-still-remains-in-balance-be-theta-positive</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In a market that barely moves these days, it&rsquo;s great when the core of your portfolio is theta positive. We already are, but this is just an emphasis on that fact.</p>

<p>The market is still stuck within the large balance area between 2080 and 2012, with 2052 being a very prominent volume node:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05242016/es.png"><img src="/images/blog/05242016/es.png" alt="/ES - 2016-05-24 - 1h Chart - Volume Composite" /></a></p>

<p>The next prominent HVN over the past 30 days appears to be 2075, which is towards the upper end of this balance area. 2075 would be the first upside target to aim for if we see the market move higher. Placing a butterfly there for a credit would be a great play, or some kind of a call ratio with more room to the upside. I&rsquo;ll be looking for something to do here.</p>

<p>Volume has been extremely low during these past trading sessions, but for us, it doesn&rsquo;t really matter. Keep that in mind, though, as a breakout of the balance area may cause volume to start picking back up again, and depending on your portfolio, you may need to adjust.</p>

<p>Yesterday we opened new trades on $NFLX, $TGT and $ES_F. These all seem to be looking good so far. Keep an eye on $NFLX - I think it&rsquo;s going to be interesting seeing how it plays out.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for the market outlook. As always, we&rsquo;ll be entering new trades and adjusting/exiting our existing positions, so be sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow us on Twitter</a>.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets today!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Expecting Consolidation Before Next HVN at 2085]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/05/11/expecting-consolidation-before-next-hvn-at-2085/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-11T05:50:34-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/05/11/expecting-consolidation-before-next-hvn-at-2085</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We had a tremendous rally yesterday:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05112016/es.png"><img src="/images/blog/05112016/es.png" alt="/ES - 2016-05-11 - 15m Chart - Volume Profile &amp; 20d Composite" /></a></p>

<p>Profile is a bit stretched and volume a bit low; regardless, the edge here is clearly to the Bulls. <a href="/blog/2016/05/10/mind-the-hvns/" title="Mind the HVNs">As mentioned yesterday morning</a>, for the Bulls, we were looking for a move to near one of the HVNs, either 2075 or 2085. We got that first one, with yesterday&rsquo;s POC right at 2074.50, so the next target now is 2085.</p>

<p>Bias here is now slightly bullish. I wouldn&rsquo;t be surprised to see some consolidation or retracement here before we continue the movement higher. However, an entire retracement of yesterday&rsquo;s upmove puts yesterday&rsquo;s rally into question, so watch out for that as well.</p>

<p>I mentioned I would place some trades near the HVNs of 2075 and 2085, but due to lack of good pricing, I wasn&rsquo;t able to find one. However, I&rsquo;ll still be looking for some, possibly to the downside as well, so stay tuned.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today&rsquo;s market outlook. If you haven&rsquo;t already, make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> to receive my tweets in real time. I&rsquo;ll be posting all of my trade entries, adjustments, and exits.</p>

<p>Happy trading, and good luck in the markets!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mind the HVNs]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/05/10/mind-the-hvns/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-10T05:32:39-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/05/10/mind-the-hvns</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday&rsquo;s trade was very evenly distributed around the POC, with a small value area range, so it was a fairly decent balance day:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05102016/es.png"><img src="/images/blog/05102016/es.png" alt="/ES - 2016-05-10 - 5m Chart - Volume Profile" /></a></p>

<p>Traders were able to find acceptance back in the upper distributions of last Thursday&rsquo;s and Friday&rsquo;s trade. They managed to build value higher, albeit overlapping, thus not really a sign of any momentum. Again, we&rsquo;re seeing low confidence as traders have no idea where to go from here.</p>

<p>/ES is currently trading at 2062. Overnight inventory is net long. On an intraday basis, when we open, watch the internals and see if the $TICKs have a hard time reaching 0. That will tell you whether or not there is a gap fade play. If the $TICK quickly shoots downwards, here are some downside targets for the gap fade:</p>

<ol>
<li>yesterday&rsquo;s high at 2057.75</li>
<li>value area high at 2056.75</li>
<li>POC at 2054</li>
<li>value area low 2051.50</li>
<li>yesterday&rsquo;s low at 2048.25</li>
</ol>


<p>Note the High Volume Nodes (HVN) at around <strong>2051</strong>, <strong>2075</strong>, and <strong>2085</strong>. Remember that prices tend to get pulled in those directions. With the /ES currently at 2062 (low volume node), expect prices to migrate away from here and possibly find acceptance near one of the HVNs.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today&rsquo;s morning market outlook. If you haven&rsquo;t already, make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> to receive my tweets in real time. I&rsquo;ll be posting all of my trade entries, adjustments, and exits.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
