<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: market outlook | ThetaTrades]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/categories/market-outlook/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-02-04T18:23:38-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[theta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Yesterday's Liquidation Break Going Forward]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/29/yesterdays-liquidation-break-going-forward/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-29T05:03:36-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/29/yesterdays-liquidation-break-going-forward</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday&rsquo;s liquidation was one which I haven&rsquo;t seen in a while and showed some signs of life from the sellers.</p>

<p>Whether or not Icahn contributed to the scare doesn&rsquo;t matter. Here&rsquo;s the current volume profile over the past 15 days:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04292016/es.png"><img src="/images/blog/04292016/es.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-04-29 - 15d Chart - Volume Profile" /></a></p>

<p>By the end of the session, we managed to trade back inside the intermediate balance area. Though traders got themselves stretched too short to the downside, notice that they did so with volume and were able to form two distributions (highlighted by the pink boxes):</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04292016/es_zoomed.png"><img src="/images/blog/04292016/es_zoomed.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-04-29 - 5d Chart - Volume Profile" /></a></p>

<p>The profile shows that the trades that occurred at the bottom distribution happened with decent volume, almost as much as there was in the upper distribution. This is definitely an edge to the Bears. However, notice that the volume POC did not migrate lower - it remained at 2087.5 - and most of the time was spent trading up there as well.</p>

<p>Today, I want to see if the POC and value area can migrate lower. I&rsquo;d like to see some continuation of selling from the Bears before switching my bias. For now, however, the Bulls have some work to do as well, and that is to get trading back above the intermediate balance area to at least in the upper distribution. Until then, my bias is neutral.</p>

<p>Also, let&rsquo;s quickly take a look at the major market indices.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the SPX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04292016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04292016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-04-29 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>We&rsquo;ve now fallen back below that trendline which we&rsquo;ve meandered back and forth between. Let&rsquo;s see if the Bears can hold it below here and show some continuation to the downside.</p>

<p>The DJX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04292016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04292016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-04-29 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>We&rsquo;re now below the highs of Nov 2015. Looks like the Bulls failed to keep it above there for now.</p>

<p>The NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04292016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04292016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-04-29 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>That trendline resistance has played out well, and this is still the weakest of the bunch. We&rsquo;re now below that 61.8% Fib retracement, closing yesterday&rsquo;s trade below it on a wide body candle.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the RUT:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04292016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/04292016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-04-29 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>Still holding above the trendline support quite well. We&rsquo;ll need to see if this one will start rolling over.</p>

<p>Keep a close eye on all of these indices, and let&rsquo;s see who wins the struggle up here.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today&rsquo;s morning market outlook. Make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a>, because that&rsquo;s where I post all my trades in real-time. Make sure you turn on notifications specifically from me. Just visit my Twitter profile on mobile, select the Settings gear, and then select the option to turn on notifications.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trading Near Prominent Point of Control]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/27/trading-near-prominent-point-of-control/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-27T05:43:36-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/27/trading-near-prominent-point-of-control</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Good morning traders.</p>

<p>In the <a href="/blog/2016/04/25/watch-for-an-upside-move/" title="Watch for an Upside Move">last post</a>, we discussed how trading near the POC from last Monday, Thursday, or Friday is very possible. We got exactly that yesterday, with another rip higher into the close as traders found themselves unable to take the market lower:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04272016/es.png"><img src="/images/blog/04272016/es.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-04-27 - 15m Chart - Volume Profile" /></a></p>

<p>Notice how we developed most of yesterday&rsquo;s value above 2081.75. Bias here should be neutral to slightly bullish.</p>

<p>The overnight inventory on the /ES is currently net short. We&rsquo;re currently trading around yesterday&rsquo;s POC at around <strong>2082.50</strong>, with the overnight low at <strong>2080.75</strong>:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04272016/es_reference_points.png"><img src="/images/blog/04272016/es_reference_points.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-04-27 - 5m Chart - Reference Points" /></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;ll be looking to see how the overnight low holds - if we break below it but are unable to find more sellers and we begin trading back above it and then through the open, I&rsquo;ll be looking to target yesterday&rsquo;s value area high at <strong>2086.50</strong>, then the overnight high at <strong>2087</strong>, followed by yesterday&rsquo;s settle, which is <strong>2088.75</strong>. Again, watch for internals to confirm.</p>

<p>As for downside references, my opinion remains the same as yesterday&rsquo;s post:</p>

<p><em>&ldquo;I would need to see the 2067 level fail. If we close below there with signs of stronger selling, I&rsquo;ll be looking to target the other side of balance, which is down at 2012. More intermediate targets would occur along the way, but they&rsquo;ll be noted when we do break 2067.&rdquo;</em></p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today&rsquo;s morning market outlook. Make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a>, because that&rsquo;s where I post all my trades in real-time. Make sure you turn on notifications specifically from me. Just visit my Twitter profile on mobile, select the Settings gear, and then select the option to turn on notifications.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets today!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Watch for an Upside Move]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/25/watch-for-an-upside-move/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-25T20:11:37-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/25/watch-for-an-upside-move</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Value continues to build lower:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04242016/es.png"><img src="/images/blog/04252016/es.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-04-25 - 15m Chart - Volume Profile" /></a></p>

<p>That&rsquo;s definitely not a bullish sign; however, just to stay alert, I wanted to point out one thing that I noticed over the past two trading sessions that has me prepared for a move back to the upside, and this is the way in which the Bears have attempted to push prices lower. You may have noticed the slow and steady grind lower during Friday&rsquo;s action and today&rsquo;s action. This has me thinking that the Bears aren&rsquo;t really confident, and they&rsquo;re struggling to push prices lower, but ultimately unable to. You can see this clearly during the past two trading sessions, where much of the grind lower gets wiped out by a big rip to the upside towards the end of each session.</p>

<p>Also, notice that today, we managed to close above the intermediate balance area high. I would not be surprised tomorrow if we hold above that level and trade near the POC from last Monday, Thursday, or Friday, which is around 2085. If so, I would consider that bullish, and would be looking to put on some type of a credit trade that captures a move into the 2100 level going forward.</p>

<p>For me to switch my bias to bearish, I would need to see the 2067 level fail. If we close below there with signs of stronger selling, I&rsquo;ll be looking to target the other side of balance, which is down at 2012. More intermediate targets would occur along the way, but they&rsquo;ll be noted when we do break 2067.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today. For now, I&rsquo;m still keeping my bias neutral, but watching for any bullish/bearish signals.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mixed Signals from Indices]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/24/mixed-signals-from-indices/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-24T14:38:16-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/24/mixed-signals-from-indices</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We ended last week on diverging signals. It&rsquo;s important to look at all broad market indices, so let&rsquo;s do that.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the SPX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04242016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04242016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-04-24 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>We have a very clear look above and fail, topping tail pattern, which is generally a bearish signal. However, although we closed below trendline resistance, the week did end up positive, so keep that in mind.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the DJX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04242016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04242016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-04-24 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>This one is a little bit more bullish than the SPX, as we closed just a bit above that 100% retracement level. I do think we start consolidating around this area for a while before we break any higher.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04242016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04242016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-04-24 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>The weakest of the bunch again due to weak earnings from GOOG. It has been unable to close above that trendline resistance, but do keep a close eye on this.</p>

<p>Finally the RUT:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04242016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/04242016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-04-24 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>The most bullish of all indices. This one clearly closed the week above the trendline resistance and has a lot of clearance to continue running to 1200.</p>

<p>Going forward, keep a close eye on all of these indices. They&rsquo;re currently divergent, so it&rsquo;s hard to say whether we should remain bullish or bearish going forward. For now, bias remains neutral.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for the recap - make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a>, because that&rsquo;s where I post all my trades in real-time. Make sure you turn on notifications specifically from me. Just visit my Twitter profile on mobile, select the Settings gear, and then select the option to turn on notifications.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets tomorrow!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Remaining Cautiously Bullish]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/17/remaining-cautiously-bullish/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-17T12:37:47-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/17/remaining-cautiously-bullish</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m continuing to remain cautiously bullish going into next week, given the massive overhead resistance we still have.</p>

<p>Looking at the broad market indices on the weekly, here&rsquo;s the SPX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04172016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04172016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-04-17 - Weekly Chart" /></a></p>

<p>We finished last week with a wide body candle after <em>consolidating</em> for a couple of weeks prior. This leads me to believe that, if we do continue moving up, the trendline resistance up ahead is less likely to hold, given how close we consolidated just under that.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the DJX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04172016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04172016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-04-17 - Weekly Chart" /></a></p>

<p>The previous trendline resistance (now support) is holding up nicely. The same thing can be seen here - consolidation right underneath the 100% Fib level from back in November. This makes me think it&rsquo;s not hard to pierce that resistance level.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04172016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04172016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-04-17 - Weekly Chart" /></a></p>

<p>Again, same thing.</p>

<p>The RUT probably paints the clearest picture:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04172016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/04172016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-04-17 - Weekly Chart" /></a></p>

<p>We&rsquo;ve consolidated over the past two weeks below the trendline and closed the week right up against it. That trendline can easily be invalidated, in which case we&rsquo;d have clearance to run up to the 1200 levels again.</p>

<p>Given what we just saw in the RUT, come Monday I&rsquo;m looking to put on a Call Calendar (again?!) in the RUT (unfortunately, the market has been extremely boring recently, and this is one of the bread and butter strategies during times of low volatility):</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04172016/rut_call_calendar.png"><img src="/images/blog/04172016/rut_call_calendar.png" alt="RUT - 2016-04-17 - Call Calendar" /></a></p>

<p>We&rsquo;ll manage this over the next month. The debit here is quite small for the potential gains we can achieve. If you have a bearish portfolio, this could be quite beneficial if the market does continue running higher.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for this weekend. I&rsquo;ll be posting that trade, along with all other entries/adjustments, live on Twitter, so be sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> to get all of my updates in real time.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets this week!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
