<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: condor | ThetaTrades]]></title>
  <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/categories/condor/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-06-01T22:02:45-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[theta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Preparing for a Breakout]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/09/preparing-for-a-breakout/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-09T13:26:26-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/09/preparing-for-a-breakout</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This market has been consolidating in a big balance area for a while now, with the volume POC for the past 15 days at around the 2040.75 level in the /ES:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04092016/esm6.png"><img src="/images/blog/04092016/esm6.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-04-09 - Market Profile" /></a></p>

<p>The composite doesn&rsquo;t look quite skewed in any direction, so I would say we&rsquo;re right in the middle of this entire balance area between 2012 and 2067.</p>

<p>Keep in mind 2012 goes back to a spike high from March 16 (refer to <a href="/blog/2016/03/18/the-most-dangerous-aspect-of-the-recent-rally/" title="Weak Reference Points">this post for more info</a> ), as well as a <em>close</em> touch of that point back in March 24. Keep this weak reference point in mind going forward.</p>

<p>Short term traders continue to be the dominant players here, getting themselves overly long or overly short. Until we see some bigger players come into play and break us out of balance, assume that we trade within the denoted range.</p>

<p>Overall, momentum in the board market indices does look like it is slowing and rounding off. My bias here is still neutral, and with such low IV, it doesn&rsquo;t make sense to be selling premium. If you have a directional bias and you&rsquo;re bearish, selling calls might not be a bad idea. Personally, I&rsquo;d want to be buying cheap OOM calendar spreads.</p>

<p>We haven&rsquo;t really traded options on the indices in a while, but here&rsquo;s a trade idea on the SPY utilizing an OOM put calendar:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04092016/spy_put_calendar.png"><img src="/images/blog/04092016/spy_put_calendar.png" alt="SPY - 2016-04-09 - Put Calendar Risk Graph" /></a></p>

<p>We&rsquo;d like SPY to trade between 190 and 202 by expiration. Adjust strikes as necessary. If you want to collect a credit, you can think about moving the nearer term strike higher.</p>

<p>A simple call credit spread on the SPY is also not a bad idea. I may be looking to put some on this coming week, depending on conditions.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m also thinking about a Bullish play on AMZN:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04092016/amzn.png"><img src="/images/blog/04092016/amzn.png" alt="AMZN - 2016-04-09 - Daily - Sitting at Horizontal Support" /></a></p>

<p>AMZN is holding up at the horizontal support level and the upward trendline support level. One of the things I&rsquo;m looking to do is put on a call condor on AMZN that includes the earnings cycle, obviously as an earnings play. I&rsquo;ll also be looking to finance this condor by selling put spreads beneath trendline support for the weeks prior to earnings, as long as the market continues to stay in balance. The reason I&rsquo;m thinking about putting on this trade is that if the market does continue to stay in balance or climb higher, AMZN usually won&rsquo;t sell off and may even climb higher as well into earnings.</p>

<p>Currently the APR5 660/670/690/700 call condor is being priced in for about .89 debit:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04092016/amzn_call_condor.png"><img src="/images/blog/04092016/amzn_call_condor.png" alt="AMZN - 2016-04-09 - Call Condor Risk Graph" /></a></p>

<p>I might buy a few of these. These and the put spreads will need to be managed if AMZN starts to lose the support levels.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ll be looking to put on these trades come Monday, so <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> to get my updates. And to make the most out of Twitter, make sure you turn on notifications specifically from me. Just visit my Twitter profile on mobile, select the Settings gear, and then select the option to turn on notifications.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for the weekend update - enjoy the weekend, and good trading on Monday!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bias Remains to the Upside Currently]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/26/bias-remains-to-the-upside-currently/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-26T17:38:12-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/26/bias-remains-to-the-upside-currently</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Remember this chart from last Friday?</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03182016/esm6_thurs_fri.png"><img src="/images/blog/03182016/esm6_thurs_fri.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-03-18 Hourly Time Frame - Single Prints Separating Distributions as Weak Reference Points" /></a></p>

<p>If you missed the explanation of what these reference points mean, <a href="/blog/2016/03/18/the-most-dangerous-aspect-of-the-recent-rally/" title="/ES Weak Reference Points">please take a look</a>.</p>

<p>Prior to Thursday&rsquo;s action, I was thinking that perhaps this could be the turning point for the Bears to step in and take the market back lower. However, from Thursday&rsquo;s action:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03262016/es_f.png"><img src="/images/blog/03262016/es_f.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-03-18 Hourly Time Frame - Bias Continues to Upside" /></a></p>

<p>We came close to the 2012 level, and instead of taking out that weak reference point, we bounced off hard and the Bulls took the market back up to fill the gap between Wednesday and Thursday. So the way we edge lower has me thinking that we will test 2060 soon on the SPX and possibly take that out and move higher to about 2090.</p>

<p>At the same time, value built lower on Thursday because most of the time was spent trading around 2016 on the /ES. And while we did finish the day filling the gap, late day rallies (and selloffs) are usually suspect and unsustainable. So Bulls, don&rsquo;t get too excited here. Keep value in mind, and don&rsquo;t be fooled by price (don&rsquo;t fight it, either).</p>

<p>Shorter term time frame traders are still dominating here, and structure remains weak. The only way the edge will shift to the Bears is if we take out that 2012 level (basically Thursday&rsquo;s low). After that, look for the next weak low at 1995 to be taken out.</p>

<p>Until then, bias still remains to the upside.</p>

<p>Taking a look at the SPX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03262016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03262016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-26 Daily Time Frame - Target 2060" /></a></p>

<p>As mentioned earlier, I believe the 2060 target is not out of play and may be reached soon. Looking at the other indices, I think we may consolidate there more before moving higher, which makes for a possible trade here which I&rsquo;ll show below.</p>

<p>DJX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03262016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03262016/djx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-26 Daily Time Frame - Target 2060" /></a></p>

<p>Same comment as the SPX.</p>

<p>NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03262016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03262016/ndx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-26 Daily Time Frame - Target 2060" /></a></p>

<p>Still under the 61.8% fib level, which doesn&rsquo;t mean much as a resistance level given how much we&rsquo;ve traded back and forth between this level.</p>

<p>RUT:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03262016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/03262016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-03-26 Daily Time Frame - Target 2060" /></a></p>

<p>The 61.8 fib level is still in play here as resistance.</p>

<p>Ok, trade ideas:</p>

<p>Because I&rsquo;m looking for the SPX to head to 2060 and stall there a bit, here&rsquo;s the play:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03262016/spx_diagonal.png"><img src="/images/blog/03262016/spx_diagonal.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-26 - Diagonal Call Spread" /></a></p>

<p>We front some debit here, and will incur losses if SPX blows through the 2060 very quickly, so this will need to be managed if that happens (keep a close eye on this and my Twitter). We want SPX to expire near our short strike by its expiration. Now this will have to be priced in again on Monday and will depend on how the futures trade Sunday night. I&rsquo;ll tweet this trade out if I end up putting it on.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m also looking at AMZN:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03262016/amzn.png"><img src="/images/blog/03262016/amzn.png" alt="AMZN - 2016-03-26 Daily Time Frame - Range Extension - 61.8% Fibonnaci Retracement" /></a></p>

<p>Last week we put a trade on for AMZN that would take advantage of a slow grind down to prior support levels at around 475. After doing so, we got faked out when the 547 support broke, and for the rest of the week, AMZN grinded higher. This is great for our position, as we had put it on for a credit, so the further it&rsquo;s away from our unbalanced butterfly, the higher the probability that we win on this trade (of course, we would like AMZN to trade near our short strikes for max profit, but a winner is a winner).</p>

<p>This week, I&rsquo;m looking for upside follow-through in this stock. Notice how the 50% fib level acts as the resistance level. If we pierce through this, and if the market does indeed turn around and move higher, I think we at least head to the 61.8 fib level and possibly double the range of the consolidation area that we&rsquo;ve had since February (between 547 and 585, ~ 35 points) and head to 620. Of course, because we&rsquo;ve retraced a long way from the 547 lows, the best way to hit 620 would be for AMZN to make a slight pullback before breaking the 50% fib level. Keep that point in mind, because we&rsquo;ll use that information to manage our trade. So here&rsquo;s the trade I&rsquo;m thinking:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03262016/amzn_condor.png"><img src="/images/blog/03262016/amzn_condor.png" alt="AMZN - 2016-03-26 Risk Graph - Condor" /></a></p>

<p>We can place a condor with a slight debit (.92 currently) with 1 week to go. If AMZN is able to reach the 61.8% fib level and close around there, we&rsquo;ll collect the max profit of 9.05. We should be looking to manage this trade by looking at the market action, in case we get a look above and fail. I&rsquo;ll also tweet out this trade when I end up putting it on, so keep watch.</p>

<p>Another one is EWZ:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03262016/ewz.png"><img src="/images/blog/03262016/ewz.png" alt="EWZ - 2016-03-26 Support and Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m looking to sell a strangle here in May - not sure why the implied volatility here is pretty rich. But I also have a bearish bias on this, so I&rsquo;m looking to buy a put spread as well. Here is the trade:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03262016/ewz_strangle_put_vertical.png"><img src="/images/blog/03262016/ewz_strangle_put_vertical.png" alt="EWZ - 2016-03-26 Strangle and Put Vertical" /></a></p>

<p>Breakevens are at around 19.1 and 30.9. We can put this on for about a .84 cr.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today. Good luck in the markets. Remember to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> as that is where I&rsquo;ll be posting my trades up in real-time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
