<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: volume profile | ThetaTrades]]></title>
  <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/categories/volume-profile/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-05-04T08:45:50-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[theta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[About That High Volume Node]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/05/04/about-that-high-volume-node/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-04T05:13:57-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/05/04/about-that-high-volume-node</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Congratulations to the Bears. Yesterday&rsquo;s action proved that Monday was nothing more than a fake-out, with the value overlapping Friday&rsquo;s value area. It appears that we&rsquo;re now going to explore the big balance area that we&rsquo;ve had going back from mid-March to mid-April - this is the 2012 to 2067 area:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05042016%0A%20/es.png"><img src="/images/blog/05042016/es.png" alt="/ES - 2016-05-03 - 1hr Chart" /></a></p>

<p><a href="www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/30/an-edge-to-the-bears/" title="An Edge to the Bears">As I mentioned multiple times in previous posts</a>, the first target to the downside is 2040.50 - this is where that high volume node sits on the volume composite. Expect any movement to the downside be halted by that area, because that is where a lot of transactions occurred, and traders will most likely be stepping up to buy there (by the way, if you look at the overnight data, look where we stopped - 2040.75 just one tick above that high volume node). If sellers start taking control after that point, then look to target the other side of balance, which is 2012 (again, this is why I&rsquo;ve been having these reference points on the chart for so long, so I can carry this information forward for days like today).</p>

<p>For today, just focus on 2040.50 and how traders accept that high volume node. Currently, the /ES is gapping down about 11.50 points as of the time of this writing. Upside reference points are yesterday&rsquo;s low at 2048, yesterday&rsquo;s value area low at 2051.50, and yesterday&rsquo;s POC at 2055.50. Keep these points in mind for upside targets today. If internals lift, these are potential targets, one after the other.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for the morning market outlook. We posted a few trades on Twitter yesterday, so make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> to receive these tweets in real-time. Make sure you turn on notifications specifically from me. Just visit my Twitter profile on mobile, select the Settings gear, and then select the option to turn on notifications.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets today!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Edge to the Bears]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/30/an-edge-to-the-bears/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-30T09:58:05-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/30/an-edge-to-the-bears</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On Friday, we got an expansion of range yesterday, with value area gapping to the downside:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04302016/es_5m.png"><img src="/images/blog/04302016/es_5m.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-04-30 - 5m Chart - Value Area Gapping to the Downside" /></a></p>

<p><a href="/blog/2016/04/29/yesterdays-liquidation-break-going-forward/" title="Liquidation Break Going Forward - Bulls and Bears Have Work to Do">In my premarket post on Friday morning</a>, I mentioned that it would be beneficial for the Bulls to hold value at or above the upper distribution of Thursday&rsquo;s profile, and for the Bears to maintain the continuation of selling and migrate the POC and value area lower.</p>

<p>Well, congratulations to the Bears, because they did exactly that and were able to keep trade <em>well below</em> both of Thursday&rsquo;s distributions. When the market opened, we saw the Bulls try to push price back into Thursday&rsquo;s value area, but could not even reach it before falling back down. We then tagged the POC from 4/12, and for the rest of the day, we built value in the large balance area developed from mid-March to mid-April. By the end of the day, it was clear that Friday&rsquo;s value area is a gap below Thursday&rsquo;s. That&rsquo;s an expansion of range to the downside, and this generally signifies the start of a new trend (in this case, a down-trend):</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04302016/es_15m.png"><img src="/images/blog/04302016/es_15m.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-04-30 - 15m Chart - Expansion of Range Signifying Beginning of a New Trend" /></a></p>

<p>The only argument that I have against the Bears is that all of this trading seems to be of low confidence. The big rip that we saw at the end of the session tells me that shorts are nervous into the close. Still, Bulls have no confidence, either. I am, however, switching my bias from neutral to slightly bearish.</p>

<p>Taking a look at the volume composite over the past 20 days:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04302016/es_volume_comp.png"><img src="/images/blog/04302016/es_volume_comp.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-04-30 - Volume Composite" /></a></p>

<p>Prices have a predisposition to trade near high volume nodes. They also have a tendency to reject trading around low volume nodes. In accordance with that behavior, we can see that the next target to the downside is around 2040.50. This makes sense - looking back to early April, that was where a lot of the volume traded. So again, as a downside target reference, <strong>I&rsquo;m expecting traders to explore the 2040.50 area next.</strong></p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve also been talking about how falling into this big balance area, <strong>we should expect to target the other side of balance at 2012</strong> if we start to see some sellers step up. Keep this target in mind going forward.</p>

<p>Below that, there are many more weak downside reference points, but I will bring them up as we get closer to them. For now, <strong>focus on the large volume node at 2040.50, and then the balance area low at 2012.</strong></p>

<p>Take this bearish move with a grain of salt, because as I mentioned earlier, all of this trading seems to be done with very low confidence.</p>

<p>Let&rsquo;s take a look at the weeklies for the broad market indices. Here&rsquo;s the SPX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04302016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04302016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-04-30 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>Prior to this past week, we had a green candle that failed to close the week above the trendline resistance. This past week, we confirmed that failure by taking prices lower.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the DJX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04302016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04302016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-04-30 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>Very similar to the SPX. Let&rsquo;s see if we get a continuation to the downside this coming week.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04302016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04302016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-04-30 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>This one, as continuously mentioned, is the weakest of the bunch and exhibits the bearishness more clearly than the other indices. Watch for a break of the 4300 level, and see how the 38% fib level holds.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the RUT:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04302016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/04302016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-04-30 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>Currently testing that trendline support. If that support fails, I&rsquo;ll be looking to target the upward-sloping trendline support first at around 1100.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for this weekend&rsquo;s market recap and outlook. With more volatility coming back into the markets, watch out for more trades from me, which I will tweet out. Make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a>, because that&rsquo;s where I post all of my trades in real-time. Make sure you turn on notifications specifically from me. Just visit my Twitter profile on mobile, select the Settings gear, and then select the option to turn on notifications.</p>

<p>Enjoy the weekend guys, and stay safe out there.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fairest Price to Do Business]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/28/fairest-price-to-do-business/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-28T05:59:13-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/28/fairest-price-to-do-business</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Taking a look at the volume profile:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04282016/es.png"><img src="/images/blog/04282016/es.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-04-28 - 15m Chart - Volume Profile" /></a></p>

<p>Yesterday, although we ripped higher into the end, value was still mostly unchanged, with the POC hovering near 2083.5. Again, this is practically where the POC has been on Tuesday, last Friday, last Thursday, and last Monday. Regardless of trendlines and such, the transactions shown by the profile tell us that this area is the fairest price to do business.</p>

<p>Currently, /ES is trading at 2078, 13 points from yesterday&rsquo;s settle. I would like to see if value can migrate lower back into the intermediate balance area denoted by the range between 2067 and 2081.75. Will the POC develop near this Monday&rsquo;s POC? To give any edge to the Bears, we need to move value area back into this intermediate balance area and take out 2067. Currently, there is just not enough seller strength at all, so my bias remains neutral to bullish.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ll be looking to see how 2083.5 plays out today. On the open, if we climb higher and tag that POC and we manage to continue trading there, then essentially nothing has changed from yesterday. If we tag that POC but fall back down and start developing value lower, that&rsquo;s an edge to the Bears. But again, that&rsquo;s if sellers step up.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today&rsquo;s morning market outlook. I&rsquo;ll be looking to put on more trades today as I haven&rsquo;t done much of it this week. Also, make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> - that&rsquo;s where I post all of my trade entries/adjustments/exits in real-time. To get the most out of Twitter, turn on notifications specifically from me to be able to get my tweets on your phone as they come.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets today!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trading Near Prominent Point of Control]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/27/trading-near-prominent-point-of-control/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-27T05:43:36-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/04/27/trading-near-prominent-point-of-control</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Good morning traders.</p>

<p>In the <a href="/blog/2016/04/25/watch-for-an-upside-move/" title="Watch for an Upside Move">last post</a>, we discussed how trading near the POC from last Monday, Thursday, or Friday is very possible. We got exactly that yesterday, with another rip higher into the close as traders found themselves unable to take the market lower:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04272016/es.png"><img src="/images/blog/04272016/es.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-04-27 - 15m Chart - Volume Profile" /></a></p>

<p>Notice how we developed most of yesterday&rsquo;s value above 2081.75. Bias here should be neutral to slightly bullish.</p>

<p>The overnight inventory on the /ES is currently net short. We&rsquo;re currently trading around yesterday&rsquo;s POC at around <strong>2082.50</strong>, with the overnight low at <strong>2080.75</strong>:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04272016/es_reference_points.png"><img src="/images/blog/04272016/es_reference_points.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-04-27 - 5m Chart - Reference Points" /></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;ll be looking to see how the overnight low holds - if we break below it but are unable to find more sellers and we begin trading back above it and then through the open, I&rsquo;ll be looking to target yesterday&rsquo;s value area high at <strong>2086.50</strong>, then the overnight high at <strong>2087</strong>, followed by yesterday&rsquo;s settle, which is <strong>2088.75</strong>. Again, watch for internals to confirm.</p>

<p>As for downside references, my opinion remains the same as yesterday&rsquo;s post:</p>

<p><em>&ldquo;I would need to see the 2067 level fail. If we close below there with signs of stronger selling, I&rsquo;ll be looking to target the other side of balance, which is down at 2012. More intermediate targets would occur along the way, but they&rsquo;ll be noted when we do break 2067.&rdquo;</em></p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today&rsquo;s morning market outlook. Make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a>, because that&rsquo;s where I post all my trades in real-time. Make sure you turn on notifications specifically from me. Just visit my Twitter profile on mobile, select the Settings gear, and then select the option to turn on notifications.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets today!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
