<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: volume profile | ThetaTrades]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/categories/volume-profile/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-03-01T09:18:48-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[theta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Expecting Consolidation Before Next HVN at 2085]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/05/11/expecting-consolidation-before-next-hvn-at-2085/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-11T05:50:34-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/05/11/expecting-consolidation-before-next-hvn-at-2085</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We had a tremendous rally yesterday:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05112016/es.png"><img src="/images/blog/05112016/es.png" alt="/ES - 2016-05-11 - 15m Chart - Volume Profile &amp; 20d Composite" /></a></p>

<p>Profile is a bit stretched and volume a bit low; regardless, the edge here is clearly to the Bulls. <a href="/blog/2016/05/10/mind-the-hvns/" title="Mind the HVNs">As mentioned yesterday morning</a>, for the Bulls, we were looking for a move to near one of the HVNs, either 2075 or 2085. We got that first one, with yesterday&rsquo;s POC right at 2074.50, so the next target now is 2085.</p>

<p>Bias here is now slightly bullish. I wouldn&rsquo;t be surprised to see some consolidation or retracement here before we continue the movement higher. However, an entire retracement of yesterday&rsquo;s upmove puts yesterday&rsquo;s rally into question, so watch out for that as well.</p>

<p>I mentioned I would place some trades near the HVNs of 2075 and 2085, but due to lack of good pricing, I wasn&rsquo;t able to find one. However, I&rsquo;ll still be looking for some, possibly to the downside as well, so stay tuned.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today&rsquo;s market outlook. If you haven&rsquo;t already, make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> to receive my tweets in real time. I&rsquo;ll be posting all of my trade entries, adjustments, and exits.</p>

<p>Happy trading, and good luck in the markets!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mind the HVNs]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/05/10/mind-the-hvns/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-10T05:32:39-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/05/10/mind-the-hvns</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday&rsquo;s trade was very evenly distributed around the POC, with a small value area range, so it was a fairly decent balance day:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05102016/es.png"><img src="/images/blog/05102016/es.png" alt="/ES - 2016-05-10 - 5m Chart - Volume Profile" /></a></p>

<p>Traders were able to find acceptance back in the upper distributions of last Thursday&rsquo;s and Friday&rsquo;s trade. They managed to build value higher, albeit overlapping, thus not really a sign of any momentum. Again, we&rsquo;re seeing low confidence as traders have no idea where to go from here.</p>

<p>/ES is currently trading at 2062. Overnight inventory is net long. On an intraday basis, when we open, watch the internals and see if the $TICKs have a hard time reaching 0. That will tell you whether or not there is a gap fade play. If the $TICK quickly shoots downwards, here are some downside targets for the gap fade:</p>

<ol>
<li>yesterday&rsquo;s high at 2057.75</li>
<li>value area high at 2056.75</li>
<li>POC at 2054</li>
<li>value area low 2051.50</li>
<li>yesterday&rsquo;s low at 2048.25</li>
</ol>


<p>Note the High Volume Nodes (HVN) at around <strong>2051</strong>, <strong>2075</strong>, and <strong>2085</strong>. Remember that prices tend to get pulled in those directions. With the /ES currently at 2062 (low volume node), expect prices to migrate away from here and possibly find acceptance near one of the HVNs.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today&rsquo;s morning market outlook. If you haven&rsquo;t already, make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> to receive my tweets in real time. I&rsquo;ll be posting all of my trade entries, adjustments, and exits.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Low Confidence Continues]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/05/09/low-confidence-continues/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-09T05:44:41-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/05/09/low-confidence-continues</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last Friday we formed two distributions:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05092016/es.png"><img src="/images/blog/05092016/es.png" alt="/ES - 2016-05-09 - 5m Chart - Volume Profile" /></a></p>

<p>Traders took the market back up to the upper distribution formed on Thursday.</p>

<p>Overall, the market last week moved lower, but did so with a bit of a forced action. Ultimately traders found themselves unable to take the market much lower in multiple sessions, and by the end of these sessions, we saw an end of the day rally. Furthermore, value areas were mostly overlapping throughout last week, meaning it seemed hard for the Bears to get any sort of momentum to the downside or a trend going at all. All of this spells low confidence to me.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m remaining neutral going into this week until things change. For downside targets, I&rsquo;ll be watching last week&rsquo;s RTH low at 2033.75 and overnight low at 2030.50 to see how those hold. For upside targets, we have high volume nodes at around 2075 and 2085. If we have any sort of a rally, I&rsquo;ll be looking to put on a trade that captures a move into those areas, for a credit.</p>

<p>Here is a brief look at the major market indices on the weekly.</p>

<p>SPX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05092016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/05092016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-05-09 - Weekly Chart" /></a></p>

<p>Still holding below trendline resistance, and has room to fall to the downside to the 38% Fib.</p>

<p>DJX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05092016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/05092016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-05-09 - Weekly Chart" /></a></p>

<p>This one is holding well above the trendline support.</p>

<p>NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05092016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/05092016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-05-09 - Weekly Chart" /></a></p>

<p>As the weakest of the bunch, it&rsquo;s spent a long time grinding lower and is holding above the 50% Fib.</p>

<p>RUT:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05092016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/05092016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-05-09 - Weekly Chart" /></a></p>

<p>Just closed below the trendline resistance last week. Let&rsquo;s see how that trendline acts as resistance this week, however.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for this weekend/morning market outlook. We&rsquo;ll be doing more trade adjustments today, so as always, make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me there</a> to receive tweets about our trades in real-time.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Still Grinding Lower]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/05/06/still-grinding-lower/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-06T05:11:48-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/05/06/still-grinding-lower</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We formed two distributions yesterday, with the POC at 2049.25. Although we slowly took trade to the lower distribution of yesterday&rsquo;s trade, value was overlapping to up - not something I would point to as extremely bearish:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05062016/es.png"><img src="/images/blog/05062016/es.png" alt="/ES - 2016-05-06 - 15m Chart - Volume Profile" /></a></p>

<p>Currently, /ES is gapping down about 5 points. As mentioned in previous blog posts, the Bears still have a lot to chew through to get well past the 2040.50 level. The unemployment numbers coming out today could be the deciding factor of whether or not we move up or down. Watch the internals and look for selling backed by volume. If we do head lower, look for a slight bounce at 2032.75. If that doesn&rsquo;t hold, 2012 is that next target:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05062016/es_comp.png"><img src="/images/blog/05062016/es_comp.png" alt="/ES - 2016-05-06 - 1hr Chart - Volume Composite" /></a></p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for the market outlook. We&rsquo;ll be doing more trade adjustments today, so as always, make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me there</a> to receive tweets regarding our trades in real-time. Also, turn on notifications specifically from me. Just visit my Twitter profile on mobile, select the Settings gear, and then select the option to turn on notifications.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Still a Lot to Chew Through for the Bears]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/05/05/still-a-lot-to-chew-through-for-the-bears/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-05T06:00:02-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/05/05/still-a-lot-to-chew-through-for-the-bears</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Value gapped lower yesterday and traders found themselves accepting prices just slightly above the high volume node  at 2040.50. As mentioned before, the Bears have a lot to chew through in order to break through the downside, and that is the entire balance area that we see on the left:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05052016/es.png"><img src="/images/blog/05052016/es.png" alt="/ES - 2016-05-05 - 1hr Chart" /></a></p>

<p>Currently futures are gapping up about 7.50, right inside Tuesday&rsquo;s value area and near its POC. Will traders find acceptance again back in this area? If so, we would&rsquo;ve had 3 days of overlapping value area (last Friday, this Tuesday, and then today if it happens), and it marks this area as an important short-term balance area.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05052016/es_zoomed.png"><img src="/images/blog/05052016/es_zoomed.png" alt="/ES - 2016-05-05 - 5m Chart" /></a></p>

<p>Reference points for today are 2060 (overnight high), 2053.50 (yesterday&rsquo;s high), 2047.50 (yesterday&rsquo;s value area high), 2045.50 (yesterday&rsquo;s POC) and 2041.25 (yesterday&rsquo;s value area low). Watch how the overnight high acts as a reference point: if we rally up to there, but fail to take it out or only take it out by a tick or two and then fail back down, you can look to target yesterday&rsquo;s high back down at 2053.50, followed by the value area high, then the POC, then value area low, and then yesterday&rsquo;s low.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today&rsquo;s market outlook. Yesterday we managed some positions and opened up new trades. Today, we&rsquo;ll be looking to book some winners if we can exit with 50% profitability. All of these are posted live on Twitter, so make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me there</a> to receive these tweets in real-time. Also, turn on notifications specifically from me. Just visit my Twitter profile on mobile, select the Settings gear, and then select the option to turn on notifications.</p>

<p>Happy trading today!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
