<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: trade idea | ThetaTrades]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/categories/trade-idea/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-01-30T22:00:51-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[theta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Comments on Gold Trade]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/05/31/comments-on-existing-gold-trade/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-31T18:49:04-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/05/31/comments-on-existing-gold-trade</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hope everyone had a great Memorial weekend!</p>

<p>Today we placed a couple of new trades, one of them being on Gold:</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">BOT BUTTERFLY /GCQ6 1/100 JUL 16 /OGN6 (27) 1150/1135/1110 P at .20</p>&mdash; theta (@theta_positive) <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive/status/737632334749388800">May 31, 2016</a></blockquote>


<script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>


<p>Let&rsquo;s take a look at the daily chart for /GC:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05312016/gc.png"><img src="/images/blog/05312016/gc.png" alt="/GC - 2016-05-31 - Daily Chart - Channel Support &amp; Analog Retracement" /></a></p>

<p>There&rsquo;s an analog between the first break of the channel &ldquo;resistance&rdquo; and where /GC low-based (first pink rectangle), and where we just broke below that channel &ldquo;resistance&rdquo; later again at a higher price and where we may be low-basing going forward (right pink rectangle). We can expect the channel support to hold, and personally I will be long gold anywhere along that trendline. But for now, as long as /GC nears 1150 by expiration, we should be closing this trade out for a profit when the opportunity presents itself.</p>

<p>This trade was posted live on Twitter this morning, and we&rsquo;ll be managing it together there as well. So if you haven&rsquo;t already, make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> to receive tweets about this trade and our other trades in real-time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Will the Bears Continue the Selling Pressure?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/21/will-the-bears-continue-the-selling-pressure/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-21T18:49:01-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/21/will-the-bears-continue-the-selling-pressure</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We saw a nice liquidation break today, and actually saw the first sign of sellers being able to keep that pressure on throughout the entire RTH session. Let&rsquo;s take a look at the overall volume profile over the past 20 days:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04212016/es.png"><img src="/images/blog/04212016/es.png" alt="/ES - 2016-04-21 - Volume Profile - 20 days" /></a></p>

<p>We can see that today, not only did we clearly create value lower, but also look where the point of control migrated to: basically back to where it was on Monday. We&rsquo;re now exploring this area to see if this is the fairest price to do business.</p>

<p>And if we zoom in and take a closer look at the past couple of weeks:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04212016/es_zoomed.png"><img src="/images/blog/04212016/es_zoomed.png" alt="/ES - 2016-04-21 - Volume Profile - Zoomed In - Value Area Gapping Lower" /></a></p>

<p>Notice today, our value area not only migrated lower, but also it did not overlap yesterday&rsquo;s value area. When value areas gap like this, it <em>generally</em> signifies the start of a new trend (although a larger gap would&rsquo;ve been better to signify stronger selling pressure). Will the selling continue tomorrow? We can only wait to find out, but until then, bias is neutral.</p>

<p>Going forward, here are important reference points to keep in mind: I&rsquo;ll be watching how the <strong>2081.75</strong> level holds tomorrow. <strong>The area between 2067 and 2081.75 can be considered a balance area</strong>, which was formed last week for a few days before we broke higher out of it this Monday. If we fall back into this area tomorrow and we start seeing some really strong selling pressure (watch the internals), look to target the other side of that balance area, which is <strong>2067</strong>.</p>

<p>Before wrapping up, I&rsquo;d like to propose a trade idea, which I haven&rsquo;t in a while. Here&rsquo;s <strong>HAL</strong> on the daily:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04212016/hal.png"><img src="/images/blog/04212016/hal.png" alt="HAL - 2016-04-21 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m looking to position a trade around <strong>HAL</strong> that assumes the analog of what happened last year would happen again this year. If so, a trade that captures a slow retracement to the bottom of the right orange rectangle over the next month or so would probably be ideal.</p>

<p>I couldn&rsquo;t find any butterflies/put backratios that were great, so I was thinking a small calendar play may work here, specifically, the JUN/MAY 36 PUT calendar:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04212016/hal_calendar.png"><img src="/images/blog/04212016/hal_calendar.png" alt="HAL - 2016-04-21 - Put Calendar" /></a></p>

<p>This is a much longer-term play, and we&rsquo;ll need to wait probably around a month or so for the premium to really start coming in. If you have a slight bearish bias on the energy sector, this could be the play for you.</p>

<p>One thing to note is that this company does have earnings coming up, but I&rsquo;m not really expecting the stock to move much to the downside, and we have quite some time for the trade to work out for us. I&rsquo;ll be looking to put this trade on tomorrow, so be on the lookout for that.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today - as always, make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a>. That is where I post all of my trades in real-time. Make sure you turn on notifications specifically from me. Just go to my Twitter profile on your mobile device, select the Settings gear, and then select the option to turn on notifications.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets tomorrow, and remember to keep those reference points in mind on the /ES.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Remaining Cautiously Bullish]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/17/remaining-cautiously-bullish/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-17T12:37:47-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/17/remaining-cautiously-bullish</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m continuing to remain cautiously bullish going into next week, given the massive overhead resistance we still have.</p>

<p>Looking at the broad market indices on the weekly, here&rsquo;s the SPX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04172016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04172016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-04-17 - Weekly Chart" /></a></p>

<p>We finished last week with a wide body candle after <em>consolidating</em> for a couple of weeks prior. This leads me to believe that, if we do continue moving up, the trendline resistance up ahead is less likely to hold, given how close we consolidated just under that.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the DJX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04172016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04172016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-04-17 - Weekly Chart" /></a></p>

<p>The previous trendline resistance (now support) is holding up nicely. The same thing can be seen here - consolidation right underneath the 100% Fib level from back in November. This makes me think it&rsquo;s not hard to pierce that resistance level.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04172016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04172016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-04-17 - Weekly Chart" /></a></p>

<p>Again, same thing.</p>

<p>The RUT probably paints the clearest picture:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04172016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/04172016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-04-17 - Weekly Chart" /></a></p>

<p>We&rsquo;ve consolidated over the past two weeks below the trendline and closed the week right up against it. That trendline can easily be invalidated, in which case we&rsquo;d have clearance to run up to the 1200 levels again.</p>

<p>Given what we just saw in the RUT, come Monday I&rsquo;m looking to put on a Call Calendar (again?!) in the RUT (unfortunately, the market has been extremely boring recently, and this is one of the bread and butter strategies during times of low volatility):</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04172016/rut_call_calendar.png"><img src="/images/blog/04172016/rut_call_calendar.png" alt="RUT - 2016-04-17 - Call Calendar" /></a></p>

<p>We&rsquo;ll manage this over the next month. The debit here is quite small for the potential gains we can achieve. If you have a bearish portfolio, this could be quite beneficial if the market does continue running higher.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for this weekend. I&rsquo;ll be posting that trade, along with all other entries/adjustments, live on Twitter, so be sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> to get all of my updates in real time.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets this week!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Breaking out of Balance]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/13/breaking-out-of-balance/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-13T18:18:12-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/13/breaking-out-of-balance</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The market broke out of balance very clearly today to the upside as we mentioned yesterday:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04132016/esm6.png"><img src="/images/blog/04132016/esm6.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-04-13 - Market Profile - 15d Zoomed In" /></a></p>

<p>We attempted to trade back below balance, but failed as buyers kept the market up.</p>

<p>On the SPX, we now have clearance to tag the uppermost trendline resistance this Friday at around 2090.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04132016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04132016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-04-13 - Trendline Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>Also, from now on for the SPX chart, the pink rectangles will be removed - the target here has been reached.</p>

<p>Watch for the top of the balance area to hold as support, because we can just as easily fail tomorrow and fall back into the balance area, which is not a strong Bullish signal. If that&rsquo;s the case, I&rsquo;ll be looking for a rotation all the way back down to the bottom of the balance area (2012) as a weekly play. However, tomorrow, I&rsquo;m looking for some consolidation before any moves higher.</p>

<p>One of the plays that I&rsquo;m looking at currently is the SPY MAY2/APR5 211/210 Diagonal Call spread, currently going for about .26 debit:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04132016/spy_call_diagonal.png"><img src="/images/blog/04132016/spy_call_diagonal.png" alt="SPY Diagonal Call Spread - 2016-04-13 - Risk Graph" /></a></p>

<p>This has breakevens at around 206 and 212 over the next few weeks. Given the low volatility that we&rsquo;ve been having and the low confidence in any downmove, as long as we stay in this range, we should be good to milk some premium. I&rsquo;ll be looking to put this on tomorrow.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today. I&rsquo;ll keep posting new entries/adjustments on Twitter, so be sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> to get all of my updates in real time.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets and good trading!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Preparing for a Breakout]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/09/preparing-for-a-breakout/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-09T13:26:26-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/09/preparing-for-a-breakout</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This market has been consolidating in a big balance area for a while now, with the volume POC for the past 15 days at around the 2040.75 level in the /ES:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04092016/esm6.png"><img src="/images/blog/04092016/esm6.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-04-09 - Market Profile" /></a></p>

<p>The composite doesn&rsquo;t look quite skewed in any direction, so I would say we&rsquo;re right in the middle of this entire balance area between 2012 and 2067.</p>

<p>Keep in mind 2012 goes back to a spike high from March 16 (refer to <a href="/blog/2016/03/18/the-most-dangerous-aspect-of-the-recent-rally/" title="Weak Reference Points">this post for more info</a> ), as well as a <em>close</em> touch of that point back in March 24. Keep this weak reference point in mind going forward.</p>

<p>Short term traders continue to be the dominant players here, getting themselves overly long or overly short. Until we see some bigger players come into play and break us out of balance, assume that we trade within the denoted range.</p>

<p>Overall, momentum in the board market indices does look like it is slowing and rounding off. My bias here is still neutral, and with such low IV, it doesn&rsquo;t make sense to be selling premium. If you have a directional bias and you&rsquo;re bearish, selling calls might not be a bad idea. Personally, I&rsquo;d want to be buying cheap OOM calendar spreads.</p>

<p>We haven&rsquo;t really traded options on the indices in a while, but here&rsquo;s a trade idea on the SPY utilizing an OOM put calendar:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04092016/spy_put_calendar.png"><img src="/images/blog/04092016/spy_put_calendar.png" alt="SPY - 2016-04-09 - Put Calendar Risk Graph" /></a></p>

<p>We&rsquo;d like SPY to trade between 190 and 202 by expiration. Adjust strikes as necessary. If you want to collect a credit, you can think about moving the nearer term strike higher.</p>

<p>A simple call credit spread on the SPY is also not a bad idea. I may be looking to put some on this coming week, depending on conditions.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m also thinking about a Bullish play on AMZN:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04092016/amzn.png"><img src="/images/blog/04092016/amzn.png" alt="AMZN - 2016-04-09 - Daily - Sitting at Horizontal Support" /></a></p>

<p>AMZN is holding up at the horizontal support level and the upward trendline support level. One of the things I&rsquo;m looking to do is put on a call condor on AMZN that includes the earnings cycle, obviously as an earnings play. I&rsquo;ll also be looking to finance this condor by selling put spreads beneath trendline support for the weeks prior to earnings, as long as the market continues to stay in balance. The reason I&rsquo;m thinking about putting on this trade is that if the market does continue to stay in balance or climb higher, AMZN usually won&rsquo;t sell off and may even climb higher as well into earnings.</p>

<p>Currently the APR5 660/670/690/700 call condor is being priced in for about .89 debit:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04092016/amzn_call_condor.png"><img src="/images/blog/04092016/amzn_call_condor.png" alt="AMZN - 2016-04-09 - Call Condor Risk Graph" /></a></p>

<p>I might buy a few of these. These and the put spreads will need to be managed if AMZN starts to lose the support levels.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ll be looking to put on these trades come Monday, so <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> to get my updates. And to make the most out of Twitter, make sure you turn on notifications specifically from me. Just visit my Twitter profile on mobile, select the Settings gear, and then select the option to turn on notifications.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for the weekend update - enjoy the weekend, and good trading on Monday!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
