<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: recap | ThetaTrades]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/categories/recap/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-02-27T09:30:38-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[theta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Most Dangerous Aspect of the Recent Rally]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/03/18/the-most-dangerous-aspect-of-the-recent-rally/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-18T12:08:39-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/03/18/the-most-dangerous-aspect-of-the-recent-rally</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We all know about the recent rally off of the February lows and how it has devastated the many short players out there. And as you know, I&rsquo;ve been harping about this in my recent posts - regardless of how ridiculous this rally may seem to many, we can&rsquo;t fight price action. The point here is that we should simply trade the trend. Thus, continue to keep the 2060 SPX target in mind.</p>

<p>However, don&rsquo;t get me wrong. While the Bulls sure have gotten quite the relief rally they needed after a terrible start in the first month of 2016, and while it may seem as though all is fine and dandy in the equities market because we&rsquo;re now positive on the year, I have one important message for those die-hard Bulls, or those who have missed out on this rally and are considering jumping in for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fear_of_missing_out" title="FOMO">FOMO</a></p>

<blockquote><p>Price is simply an advertising mechanism</p></blockquote>

<p>Price is simply an advertising mechanism. And yes, it&rsquo;s easy to get sucked in by price. We see it every day in our lives - the dealership we drive by promoting the price slash on that shiny car, the cheap deal from the restaurant serving up their burrito bowls with E. Coli additives, the ads on TV from Macy&rsquo;s promoting price cuts on their clothes, etc&hellip; But is there any value to these items? Some would argue so, since obviously transactions occurred here before, so of course it has value - someone just bought it at this price level.</p>

<p>But the existence of a transaction happening at that price does not provide enough information as to how much value it really provides. The missing dimensions are <strong>time</strong> and <strong>volume</strong> spent at those levels.</p>

<p>The longer the time that traders spend making transactions at a certain price level, the more value that area has. The same can be said for volume, and we&rsquo;ll take a deeper look at that now.</p>

<p>From a candlestick chart, it&rsquo;s hard to see time or volume spent at each of the individual prices/price ranges. So instead, we&rsquo;ll have to look at the <strong>market profile</strong>, specifically, the volume profile:</p>

<p>This is a rough volume profile of the /ES:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03182016/es_volume_composite.png"><img src="/images/blog/03182016/es_volume_composite.png" alt="/ES - 2016-03-18 Hourly Time Frame - Volume Composite" /></a></p>

<p>Looking at this recent rally that we&rsquo;ve had, we can see how much time and volume was spent throughout each area of this up-move.</p>

<p>The first week of the rally was explosive - we gapped up repeatedly the first few days, creating &ldquo;single prints&rdquo; in the market profile as shorts panicked to cover their existing positions. What followed was consolidation around the 1940 area, and then another explosive move higher into the 2000 range before another consolidation, and then finally one more push to our current levels. Each of these pushes can be thought of as being built on &ldquo;poor structure.&rdquo; That means, not a lot of time was spent developing value throughout all of the areas of this rally - there were only two areas so far that we spent about a week or so, each, developing value in. A healthy market rally, instead of screaming higher with single prints, would gradually develop value higher and higher. The gradual, upward migration of value areas prevents a sell off from breaking through these value areas and eliminating longs quickly; more time and volume spent in these areas means there are many traders interested in prices at these levels.</p>

<p>In contrast, the sharp, &ldquo;gappy&rdquo; migration of value is very susceptible to liquidation breaks, as these single-prints or gaps have yet to be filled with value when revisited. However, once price revisits these levels, because no time was spent here, those who got long in these prices will most likely panic, as they did not get in at a value area, but at an area that they felt were &ldquo;forced&rdquo; to get in at because they were &ldquo;chasing&rdquo; bad location. Subsequently, a chain reaction occurs where longs liquidate at market (think of it as the opposite of a short squeeze).</p>

<p>Zooming out and looking at the bigger picture, when viewing the volume profile of the entire rally, we end up with this histogram on the right (chart shown again):</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03182016/es_volume_composite.png"><img src="/images/blog/03182016/es_volume_composite.png" alt="/ES - 2016-03-18 Hourly Time Frame - Volume Composite" /></a></p>

<p>The volume bars on the right is the volume composite, or the sum of all of the volumes at the different price levels for the time frame we&rsquo;re looking at. In the time frame of this ongoing rally, we see that the high volume &ldquo;node&rdquo; currently exists at around 1986. This is the fairest price to do business. The second fairest would be at around 1920. Everything in between (the valleys) are subject to liquidation breaks. In essence, price tends to trade near peaks, and it tends to move away from valleys. Keep this information in mind for when we do begin to trade away from the peaks.</p>

<p>The tone out there in the market is very bullish, no doubt. But besides the <strong>extremely</strong> poor structure of this rally, another thing that bothers me about this rally is that it is the short term traders that have been dominating price action this past couple of weeks. The reason I say this with confidence is that short term traders usually look at short term time frame reference points, i.e. yesterday&rsquo;s high or low, overnight high or low, etc&hellip; and trade mechanically off of these points. And that&rsquo;s precisely what we&rsquo;ve had this past week - the prices at which the market has been bouncing from spell out very clearly that the action is dominated by exactly these players.</p>

<p>Specifically, I&rsquo;m looking at the 1995 level on the /ES:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03182016/esm6_1995.png"><img src="/images/blog/03182016/esm6_1995.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-03-18 Hourly Time Frame - 1995 Weak Reference Point" /></a></p>

<p>Notice how many times we&rsquo;ve come to this level and bounced away from it. Also, notice the distribution areas boxed by the blue areas, with the single prints in between them:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03182016/esm6_thurs_fri.png"><img src="/images/blog/03182016/esm6_thurs_fri.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-03-18 Hourly Time Frame - Single Prints Separating Distributions as Weak Reference Points" /></a></p>

<p>On Thursday&rsquo;s RTH, we came to just 1 tick above the single print spike from Wednesday&rsquo;s RTH and bounced right from there. These weren&rsquo;t value area reference points, but rather short term reference points. Thus, in my opinion, they are weak and should be carried forward into the future for when we do come revisit these points. And when we do, <strong>don&rsquo;t be surprised if all of that poor structure which has been built by short term traders gets wiped out by a hard liquidation break</strong>.</p>

<p>Going forward, I believe we continue rallying to around 2060 in the SPX next week. If we close at or below that point next week, then I think the play would be to take a short there. If we continue selling off, keep those weak reference points I mentioned earlier in mind and know that they are just that: <em>weak</em>. We may see a slight bounce at 1995 given how many times we&rsquo;ve touched this point, but understand that, because it&rsquo;s a weak reference point, it would probably break on a subsequent touch downwards.</p>

<p>So, if you&rsquo;re a die-hard Bull, or if you&rsquo;ve been dying to get in the market, but you haven&rsquo;t yet, it is now very late, so if you do decide to jump in, please be careful and keep those reference points in mind. It is all too easy to fall into the trap of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Herd_mentality," title="chasing price">chasing price</a>.</p>

<p>Again, you can <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive/">Follow me on Twitter</a> to get my real-time updates on the market, including my entries and exits for all trades. Enjoy the weekend and be safe out there.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SPX Gap Filled, Will We Continue to Find Acceptance]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/03/17/spx-gap-filled/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-17T17:43:05-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/03/17/spx-gap-filled</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We filled the gap today on the SPX from last year&rsquo;s close today:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03172016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03172016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-17 Daily Time Frame - Target 2060 - Gap Fill" /></a></p>

<p>Let&rsquo;s continue monitoring the higher movement we&rsquo;ve had for continuation.</p>

<p>The market is dangerously long here, and I mention that due to the multiple poor structures that this rally has made to get up to where it is right now. This makes the market susceptible to huge liquidation breaks once the bigger players step in. For now, I still don&rsquo;t see many long term players coming in. The action feels very squeezed, but it can continue higher. 2060 is that target I&rsquo;m aiming for.</p>

<p>For tomorrow, keep an eye out on SPX to see if we find acceptance here. I think we may stall here for a bit as the players from last year decide whether or not to hold or get out. Thus, value may build here before we move higher.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Market Continues to Upside]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/03/16/market-continues-to-upside/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-16T19:27:04-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/03/16/market-continues-to-upside</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yellen did it again, and the markets rally higher. Let&rsquo;s take a look:</p>

<p>As mentioned for a while now, SPX is still on track to tag the 2060 level:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03162016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03162016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-16 Daily Time Frame - Target 2060 - Harmonic Pattern" /></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve outlined the range of last year&rsquo;s October rally and duplicated that line over to the rally we&rsquo;ve had from February to estimate the target of this rally (AKA Harmonic Pattern), and it matches perfectly with the descending trendline resistance. Given this projection, we should reach that target zone in about two weeks.</p>

<p>Keep in mind that SPX opened this year at 2038.2. Look for some resistance over there as well. A failure to take this market back up through the open (just like in day-trading when we fail to take out the open) is a short signal. But if we plow through this and move higher with ease, expect 2060.</p>

<p>Taking a look at the DJX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03162016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03162016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-03-16 Daily Time Frame - Descending Trendline Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>Pretty bullish here. It just broke the descending trendline resistance, which makes a big dent in the bear case. The next target is that next trendline resistance.</p>

<p>Moving over to the NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03162016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03162016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-03-16 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci" /></a></p>

<p>This tagged the 61.8% fib today and backed off, but given how all the other indices look, this would have no problem busting through it that, which makes the next target the descending trendline resistance.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the RUT:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03162016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/03162016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-03-16 Daily Time Frame - Bull Flag" /></a></p>

<p>Though it&rsquo;s weak, we could be setting up for a bull flag breakout.</p>

<p>Watch all of the indices closely. The best trade idea for SPX is setting up a butterfly with the short strikes centered at 2060, expiring on Mar5.</p>

<p>That wraps it up for today. Trade safe, and trade small. Good luck in the markets!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Further Upside Expected]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/03/11/further-upside-expected/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-11T18:45:36-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/03/11/further-upside-expected</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m expecting further upside in the market.</p>

<p>Yesterday after the ECB announcement, traders attempted to push the market lower but were unable to do so. We looked below balance, failed, made a poor low, and then came back into balance. Then this morning, we gapped up, but with the internals so strong, no chance of a gap fade play was available, and we continued to ratchet higher.</p>

<p>This is a very bullish signal, regardless of how overbought the conditions are. Here&rsquo;s the current SPX chart:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03112016/spx_daily.png"><img src="/images/blog/03112016/spx_daily.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-11 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement, Trendline Resistance, Range Extension" /></a></p>

<p>For those that took a bullish stance on the market during that time, congratulations. In the first SPX chart that I posted a couple of weeks back, I outlined the potential range extension we could see as possible target areas (via the pink rectangles). This week, not only did we break the 61.8% fib level, but we&rsquo;ve also broken the trendline resistance connected by the tops of November and December 2015. I believe we&rsquo;re headed to 2060. So if you&rsquo;re long, continue to hold that position.</p>

<p>Zooming out and taking a look at the market on the weekly:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03112016/spx_weekly.png"><img src="/images/blog/03112016/spx_weekly.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-11 Weekly Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement, Trendline Resistance, Range Extension, Bottoming-Tail Hammer" /></a></p>

<p>Notice the bottoming tail hammer that formed. I count many weekly bars from before that ended with a higher close the following week.</p>

<p>The same bullishness can be seen in the Dow:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03112016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03112016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-03-11 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement, Trendline Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>We&rsquo;re approaching the trendline resistance here as well. Look for a short there. As a side note, DJX has also put in a bottoming-tail hammer on the weekly chart.</p>

<p>For the NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03112016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03112016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-03-11 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement" /></a></p>

<p>A little bit weaker here, as we have not tagged the 61.8% fib level, yet. Still, this has also put in a bottoming-tail hammer on the weekly chart.</p>

<p>Finally the RUT:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03112016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/03112016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-03-11 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement, Trendline Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>Though it exhibited a lot of weakness a couple of days ago, keep in mind it has come off really high from the lows. It looks like it&rsquo;ll break that trendline resistance, and if it does, that&rsquo;ll suggest more short-covering to come.</p>

<p>That about wraps it up for the week going on to next week. I&rsquo;d just like to finish with another note:</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m not bullish on the market - I think the fundamentals are complete garbage, and I think we&rsquo;ll see a crash like we&rsquo;ve never seen before. However, I can&rsquo;t let my biases blind me from seeing the opportunities out there. Instead of falling prey to cognitive dissonance, we can separate our bias and take advantage of these opportunities as they come.</p>

<p>Enjoy the weekend, and good luck to everyone, bull or bear.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Short Term Traders Dominating]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/03/10/short-term-traders-dominating/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-10T19:09:16-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/03/10/short-term-traders-dominating</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The market has been doing nothing other than balancing over the past 8 trading sessions. We&rsquo;re bracketing, and it&rsquo;s apparent that the market is being dominated by the shorter term traders looking to buy at the bottom of balance and sell at the top. We&rsquo;re unable to push prices higher, and today, we look below and failed. All of this price action over the past couple of weeks paints a very clear picture: traders have extremely low confidence.</p>

<p>While one can argue that the market seems bearish because Mario wasn&rsquo;t able to push prices higher with his market manipulation techniques, one can also argue that if we were truly bearish, we wouldn&rsquo;t have look outside below balance, and then come back in. We settled today at the point of control, which has just been getting more and more prominent over the past couple of weeks. Traders just like it here.</p>

<p>Today we formed a poor low in the /ES. Expect that to be repaired in the (possibly near) future.</p>

<p>/CL seems a bit confused about where it wants to go. We&rsquo;ve had back to back days that just completely engulfed the previous days, until today, when we closed on a Doji:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03102016/cl_f.png"><img src="/images/blog/03102016/cl_f.png" alt="/CL - 2016-03-10 Daily Time Frame - Doji, Fibonacci" /></a></p>

<p>Crude looks like it wants to hit 40 or the 61.8% fib level. I&rsquo;ve set up the 39.5/40/40.5 balanced butterfly for a 0.30 debit.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today. Good luck and happy trading in in the markets tomorrow.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
