<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: recap | theta trades]]></title>
  <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/categories/recap/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-03-17T18:08:45-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[theta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SPX Gap Filled, Will We Continue to Find Acceptance]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/17/spx-gap-filled/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-17T17:43:05-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/17/spx-gap-filled</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We filled the gap today on the SPX from last year&rsquo;s close today:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03172016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03172016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-17 Daily Time Frame - Target 2060 - Gap Fill" /></a></p>

<p>Let&rsquo;s continue monitoring the higher movement we&rsquo;ve had for continuation.</p>

<p>The market is dangerously long here, and I mention that due to the multiple poor structures that this rally has made to get up to where it is right now. This makes the market susceptible to huge liquidation breaks once the bigger players step in. For now, I still don&rsquo;t see many long term players coming in. The action feels very squeezed, but it can continue higher. 2060 is that target I&rsquo;m aiming for.</p>

<p>For tomorrow, keep an eye out on SPX to see if we find acceptance here. I think we may stall here for a bit as the players from last year decide whether or not to hold or get out. Thus, value may build here before we move higher.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Market Continues to Upside]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/16/market-continues-to-upside/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-16T19:27:04-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/16/market-continues-to-upside</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yellen did it again, and the markets rally higher. Let&rsquo;s take a look:</p>

<p>As mentioned for a while now, SPX is still on track to tag the 2060 level:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03162016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03162016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-16 Daily Time Frame - Target 2060 - Harmonic Pattern" /></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve outlined the range of last year&rsquo;s October rally and duplicated that line over to the rally we&rsquo;ve had from February to estimate the target of this rally (AKA Harmonic Pattern), and it matches perfectly with the descending trendline resistance. Given this projection, we should reach that target zone in about two weeks.</p>

<p>Keep in mind that SPX opened this year at 2038.2. Look for some resistance over there as well. A failure to take this market back up through the open (just like in day-trading when we fail to take out the open) is a short signal. But if we plow through this and move higher with ease, expect 2060.</p>

<p>Taking a look at the DJX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03162016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03162016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-03-16 Daily Time Frame - Descending Trendline Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>Pretty bullish here. It just broke the descending trendline resistance, which makes a big dent in the bear case. The next target is that next trendline resistance.</p>

<p>Moving over to the NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03162016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03162016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-03-16 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci" /></a></p>

<p>This tagged the 61.8% fib today and backed off, but given how all the other indices look, this would have no problem busting through it that, which makes the next target the descending trendline resistance.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the RUT:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03162016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/03162016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-03-16 Daily Time Frame - Bull Flag" /></a></p>

<p>Though it&rsquo;s weak, we could be setting up for a bull flag breakout.</p>

<p>Watch all of the indices closely. The best trade idea for SPX is setting up a butterfly with the short strikes centered at 2060, expiring on Mar5.</p>

<p>That wraps it up for today. Trade safe, and trade small. Good luck in the markets!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Further Upside Expected]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/11/further-upside-expected/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-11T18:45:36-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/11/further-upside-expected</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m expecting further upside in the market.</p>

<p>Yesterday after the ECB announcement, traders attempted to push the market lower but were unable to do so. We looked below balance, failed, made a poor low, and then came back into balance. Then this morning, we gapped up, but with the internals so strong, no chance of a gap fade play was available, and we continued to ratchet higher.</p>

<p>This is a very bullish signal, regardless of how overbought the conditions are. Here&rsquo;s the current SPX chart:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03112016/spx_daily.png"><img src="/images/blog/03112016/spx_daily.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-11 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement, Trendline Resistance, Range Extension" /></a></p>

<p>For those that took a bullish stance on the market during that time, congratulations. In the first SPX chart that I posted a couple of weeks back, I outlined the potential range extension we could see as possible target areas (via the pink rectangles). This week, not only did we break the 61.8% fib level, but we&rsquo;ve also broken the trendline resistance connected by the tops of November and December 2015. I believe we&rsquo;re headed to 2060. So if you&rsquo;re long, continue to hold that position.</p>

<p>Zooming out and taking a look at the market on the weekly:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03112016/spx_weekly.png"><img src="/images/blog/03112016/spx_weekly.png" alt="SPX - 2016-03-11 Weekly Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement, Trendline Resistance, Range Extension, Bottoming-Tail Hammer" /></a></p>

<p>Notice the bottoming tail hammer that formed. I count many weekly bars from before that ended with a higher close the following week.</p>

<p>The same bullishness can be seen in the Dow:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03112016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03112016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-03-11 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement, Trendline Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>We&rsquo;re approaching the trendline resistance here as well. Look for a short there. As a side note, DJX has also put in a bottoming-tail hammer on the weekly chart.</p>

<p>For the NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03112016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/03112016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-03-11 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement" /></a></p>

<p>A little bit weaker here, as we have not tagged the 61.8% fib level, yet. Still, this has also put in a bottoming-tail hammer on the weekly chart.</p>

<p>Finally the RUT:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03112016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/03112016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-03-11 Daily Time Frame - Fibonacci Retracement, Trendline Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>Though it exhibited a lot of weakness a couple of days ago, keep in mind it has come off really high from the lows. It looks like it&rsquo;ll break that trendline resistance, and if it does, that&rsquo;ll suggest more short-covering to come.</p>

<p>That about wraps it up for the week going on to next week. I&rsquo;d just like to finish with another note:</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m not bullish on the market - I think the fundamentals are complete garbage, and I think we&rsquo;ll see a crash like we&rsquo;ve never seen before. However, I can&rsquo;t let my biases blind me from seeing the opportunities out there. Instead of falling prey to cognitive dissonance, we can separate our bias and take advantage of these opportunities as they come.</p>

<p>Enjoy the weekend, and good luck to everyone, bull or bear.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Short Term Traders Dominating]]></title>
    <link href="http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/10/short-term-traders-dominating/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-10T19:09:16-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kenniyu.github.io/blog/2016/03/10/short-term-traders-dominating</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The market has been doing nothing other than balancing over the past 8 trading sessions. We&rsquo;re bracketing, and it&rsquo;s apparent that the market is being dominated by the shorter term traders looking to buy at the bottom of balance and sell at the top. We&rsquo;re unable to push prices higher, and today, we look below and failed. All of this price action over the past couple of weeks paints a very clear picture: traders have extremely low confidence.</p>

<p>While one can argue that the market seems bearish because Mario wasn&rsquo;t able to push prices higher with his market manipulation techniques, one can also argue that if we were truly bearish, we wouldn&rsquo;t have look outside below balance, and then come back in. We settled today at the point of control, which has just been getting more and more prominent over the past couple of weeks. Traders just like it here.</p>

<p>Today we formed a poor low in the /ES. Expect that to be repaired in the (possibly near) future.</p>

<p>/CL seems a bit confused about where it wants to go. We&rsquo;ve had back to back days that just completely engulfed the previous days, until today, when we closed on a Doji:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/03102016/cl_f.png"><img src="/images/blog/03102016/cl_f.png" alt="/CL - 2016-03-10 Daily Time Frame - Doji, Fibonacci" /></a></p>

<p>Crude looks like it wants to hit 40 or the 61.8% fib level. I&rsquo;ve set up the 39.5/40/40.5 balanced butterfly for a 0.30 debit.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today. Good luck and happy trading in in the markets tomorrow.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
