<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: iwm | ThetaTrades]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/categories/iwm/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-11-26T16:28:15-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[theta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Couple of Weekend Trade Ideas]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/05/01/weekend-trade-ideas/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-01T19:37:05-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/05/01/weekend-trade-ideas</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If we&rsquo;re expecting a bit of retracement in the broad market indices, we can take a look at IWM.</p>

<p>With volatility picking up, we can also look at put calendars.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the Fibonacci fan on the IWM over the February rally which shows us potential retracement areas in the future:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05012016/iwm_fib_fan.png"><img src="/images/blog/05012016/iwm_fib_fan.png" alt="IWM - 2016-05-01 - Volume Composite" /></a></p>

<p>If we&rsquo;re looking for an upcoming retracement, it helps to combine this fan with the volume profile over the past 20 days to figure out where price would have a predisposition to trade near, and see where the fan and the high volume node areas intersect. This will help us figure out the strike and expiry of our put calendar. With that, here&rsquo;s the volume profile over the past 20 days:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05012016/iwm_volume.png"><img src="/images/blog/05012016/iwm_volume.png" alt="IWM - 2016-05-01 - Volume Composite" /></a></p>

<p>The high volume node is near 109.5 and it seems to intersect the fan about two weeks out. I&rsquo;ve highlighted this potential area in oval. This means a potential trade setup is the 109.5 put calendar, with the short strike expiring next Friday, and the long strike next next Friday. Here&rsquo;s the risk graph:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05012016/iwm_risk_graph.png"><img src="/images/blog/05012016/iwm_risk_graph.png" alt="IWM - 2016-05-01 - Risk Graph" /></a></p>

<p>The same thing can be done with others as well. Here&rsquo;s CMG on the weekly:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05012016/cmg_weekly.png"><img src="/images/blog/05012016/cmg_weekly.png" alt="CMG - 2016-05-01 - Weekly" /></a></p>

<p>Hanging on right above that long-term trendline support. Zooming in:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05012016/cmg_hourly.png"><img src="/images/blog/05012016/cmg_hourly.png" alt="CMG - 2016-05-01 - Hourly" /></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m expecting CMG to bounce, unless the overall market exhibits extreme bearishness. If we do see that bounce, the gap made post-earnings could fill and we could potentially place a trade near the high volume node around 460 over the next couple of weeks.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the risk graph:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05012016/cmg_risk_graph.png"><img src="/images/blog/05012016/cmg_risk_graph.png" alt="CMG - 2016-05-01 - Risk Graph" /></a></p>

<p>If the debit is too much, consider selling some credit spreads against it.</p>

<p>This is just an idea - combining the volume composite with other TA tools like the Fibonacci fan. Feel free to apply this to things you plan on trading - it only helps. Anyway, we&rsquo;ll see how well these couple of trade ideas work out. I&rsquo;ll be looking to place these trades on, so make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a>, because that&rsquo;s where I post all of my trades in real-time.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets tomorrow!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
