<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: low confidence | ThetaTrades]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/categories/low-confidence/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-01-30T22:00:51-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[theta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Market Remains in Balance]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/05/23/market-remains-in-balance/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-23T05:25:23-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/05/23/market-remains-in-balance</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last week, we had a whole lot of nothing, closing the week flat where we started:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05232016/es.png"><img src="/images/blog/05232016/es.png" alt="/ES - 2016-05-23 - Weekly Chart" /></a></p>

<p>Notice the developing high volume node around 2050 on the /ES:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05232016/es_profile.png"><img src="/images/blog/05232016/es_profile.png" alt="/ES - 2016-05-23 - 4h Chart - Volume Composite" /></a></p>

<p>Traders love this spot, and it&rsquo;s smack in the middle of our big balance area. Consider buying wide, weekly butterflies in this area to capture a lot of theta.</p>

<p>So what I&rsquo;m looking for this week on the /ES is for us to continue staying in balance along this descending channel:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05232016/es_channel.png"><img src="/images/blog/05232016/es_channel.png" alt="/ES - 2016-05-23 - 1d Chart - Descending Channel" /></a></p>

<p>Watch for bounces off of the channel support and resistance.</p>

<p>Last week we booked many winners. We had a few losers which were the small calendar debits we payed for, but they were offset by the winners significantly. As always, we&rsquo;ll be entering new trades and adjusting/exiting our existing positions, so be sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow us on Twitter</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nothing New]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/05/13/nothing-new/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-13T05:32:26-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/05/13/nothing-new</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="/images/blog/05132016/es.png"><img src="/images/blog/05132016/es.png" alt="/ES - 2016-05-13 - 15m Chart - Volume Profile" /></a></p>

<p>Yesterday, we had another day where value area overlapped the prior days&rsquo;s value area. Again, this spells low confidence - traders have a tough time getting prices to trend in any direction whatsoever. We had liquidation breaks followed by short squeezes closely following each other in many of the recent sessions (yesterday&rsquo;s price action showed that very clearly), so the struggle between the Bulls and the Bears continue.</p>

<p>The /ES is currently down approximately 4 points at the time of this writing. For today, I&rsquo;m not expecting much, as I&rsquo;m still neutral here until we get out of this low confidence environment and are able to establish a trend. Remember guys, don&rsquo;t be fooled by price; continue watching those value areas, and keep in mind the HVN at 2050 below us, and 2075 above us.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today&rsquo;s market outlook. As a side note, I&rsquo;ll be out of town until 5/23 and will have limited access to the blog during this time; however, I will still be managing our trades, so make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> - that&rsquo;s where I post all of my trade entries/adjustments/exits in real-time. To get the most out of Twitter, turn on notifications specifically from me to be able to get my tweets on your phone as they come.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets, and enjoy the weekend.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Extremely Low Confidence - Remaining Neutral For Now]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/05/12/extremely-low-confidence-remaining-neutral-for-now/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-12T06:05:12-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/05/12/extremely-low-confidence-remaining-neutral-for-now</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="/images/blog/05122016/es.png"><img src="/images/blog/05122016/es.png" alt="/ES - 2016-05-12 - 15m Chart - Volume Profile &amp; 20d Composite" /></a></p>

<p>On Wednesday, we had an entire retracement of Tuesday&rsquo;s rally. <a href="/blog/2016/05/11/expecting-consolidation-before-next-hvn-at-2085/" title="Expecting Consolidation Before Next HVN at 2085">In the blog post yesterday</a>, we mentioned that if we did see that, it puts the rally in question. All of this just goes to show the low confidence that traders have in the market. If we were in a high confidence market, you wouldn&rsquo;t see a rally give back like this. You would see a slight pullback or pause, before a continuation higher. You would definitely see things trend more easily without value areas grinding slowly in one direction, overlapping the previous day&rsquo;s. And you would definitely see more volume. Last week it felt like the Bears couldn&rsquo;t get a good momentum to the downside, and now, the Bulls can&rsquo;t seem to hold up their end either.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m going to have to remain neutral here, keeping focus on the HVNs at 2075 and 2085 on the upside, and 2050 on the downside. As of the time of this writing, /ES is trading at 2069, which is within yesterday&rsquo;s value area. I would not be surprised if we continue to build value here.</p>

<p>As always, keep putting on theta and vega positive positions. And if you haven&rsquo;t already, make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> to receive my tweets in real time. I&rsquo;ll be posting all of my trade entries, adjustments, and exits.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets today!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mind the HVNs]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/05/10/mind-the-hvns/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-10T05:32:39-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/05/10/mind-the-hvns</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday&rsquo;s trade was very evenly distributed around the POC, with a small value area range, so it was a fairly decent balance day:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05102016/es.png"><img src="/images/blog/05102016/es.png" alt="/ES - 2016-05-10 - 5m Chart - Volume Profile" /></a></p>

<p>Traders were able to find acceptance back in the upper distributions of last Thursday&rsquo;s and Friday&rsquo;s trade. They managed to build value higher, albeit overlapping, thus not really a sign of any momentum. Again, we&rsquo;re seeing low confidence as traders have no idea where to go from here.</p>

<p>/ES is currently trading at 2062. Overnight inventory is net long. On an intraday basis, when we open, watch the internals and see if the $TICKs have a hard time reaching 0. That will tell you whether or not there is a gap fade play. If the $TICK quickly shoots downwards, here are some downside targets for the gap fade:</p>

<ol>
<li>yesterday&rsquo;s high at 2057.75</li>
<li>value area high at 2056.75</li>
<li>POC at 2054</li>
<li>value area low 2051.50</li>
<li>yesterday&rsquo;s low at 2048.25</li>
</ol>


<p>Note the High Volume Nodes (HVN) at around <strong>2051</strong>, <strong>2075</strong>, and <strong>2085</strong>. Remember that prices tend to get pulled in those directions. With the /ES currently at 2062 (low volume node), expect prices to migrate away from here and possibly find acceptance near one of the HVNs.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today&rsquo;s morning market outlook. If you haven&rsquo;t already, make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> to receive my tweets in real time. I&rsquo;ll be posting all of my trade entries, adjustments, and exits.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Low Confidence Continues]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/05/09/low-confidence-continues/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-09T05:44:41-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/05/09/low-confidence-continues</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last Friday we formed two distributions:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05092016/es.png"><img src="/images/blog/05092016/es.png" alt="/ES - 2016-05-09 - 5m Chart - Volume Profile" /></a></p>

<p>Traders took the market back up to the upper distribution formed on Thursday.</p>

<p>Overall, the market last week moved lower, but did so with a bit of a forced action. Ultimately traders found themselves unable to take the market much lower in multiple sessions, and by the end of these sessions, we saw an end of the day rally. Furthermore, value areas were mostly overlapping throughout last week, meaning it seemed hard for the Bears to get any sort of momentum to the downside or a trend going at all. All of this spells low confidence to me.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m remaining neutral going into this week until things change. For downside targets, I&rsquo;ll be watching last week&rsquo;s RTH low at 2033.75 and overnight low at 2030.50 to see how those hold. For upside targets, we have high volume nodes at around 2075 and 2085. If we have any sort of a rally, I&rsquo;ll be looking to put on a trade that captures a move into those areas, for a credit.</p>

<p>Here is a brief look at the major market indices on the weekly.</p>

<p>SPX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05092016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/05092016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-05-09 - Weekly Chart" /></a></p>

<p>Still holding below trendline resistance, and has room to fall to the downside to the 38% Fib.</p>

<p>DJX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05092016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/05092016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-05-09 - Weekly Chart" /></a></p>

<p>This one is holding well above the trendline support.</p>

<p>NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05092016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/05092016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-05-09 - Weekly Chart" /></a></p>

<p>As the weakest of the bunch, it&rsquo;s spent a long time grinding lower and is holding above the 50% Fib.</p>

<p>RUT:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/05092016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/05092016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-05-09 - Weekly Chart" /></a></p>

<p>Just closed below the trendline resistance last week. Let&rsquo;s see how that trendline acts as resistance this week, however.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for this weekend/morning market outlook. We&rsquo;ll be doing more trade adjustments today, so as always, make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me there</a> to receive tweets about our trades in real-time.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
