<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: targets | ThetaTrades]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/categories/targets/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-03-05T11:24:31-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[theta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Edge to the Bears]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/30/an-edge-to-the-bears/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-30T09:58:05-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/30/an-edge-to-the-bears</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On Friday, we got an expansion of range yesterday, with value area gapping to the downside:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04302016/es_5m.png"><img src="/images/blog/04302016/es_5m.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-04-30 - 5m Chart - Value Area Gapping to the Downside" /></a></p>

<p><a href="/blog/2016/04/29/yesterdays-liquidation-break-going-forward/" title="Liquidation Break Going Forward - Bulls and Bears Have Work to Do">In my premarket post on Friday morning</a>, I mentioned that it would be beneficial for the Bulls to hold value at or above the upper distribution of Thursday&rsquo;s profile, and for the Bears to maintain the continuation of selling and migrate the POC and value area lower.</p>

<p>Well, congratulations to the Bears, because they did exactly that and were able to keep trade <em>well below</em> both of Thursday&rsquo;s distributions. When the market opened, we saw the Bulls try to push price back into Thursday&rsquo;s value area, but could not even reach it before falling back down. We then tagged the POC from 4/12, and for the rest of the day, we built value in the large balance area developed from mid-March to mid-April. By the end of the day, it was clear that Friday&rsquo;s value area is a gap below Thursday&rsquo;s. That&rsquo;s an expansion of range to the downside, and this generally signifies the start of a new trend (in this case, a down-trend):</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04302016/es_15m.png"><img src="/images/blog/04302016/es_15m.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-04-30 - 15m Chart - Expansion of Range Signifying Beginning of a New Trend" /></a></p>

<p>The only argument that I have against the Bears is that all of this trading seems to be of low confidence. The big rip that we saw at the end of the session tells me that shorts are nervous into the close. Still, Bulls have no confidence, either. I am, however, switching my bias from neutral to slightly bearish.</p>

<p>Taking a look at the volume composite over the past 20 days:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04302016/es_volume_comp.png"><img src="/images/blog/04302016/es_volume_comp.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-04-30 - Volume Composite" /></a></p>

<p>Prices have a predisposition to trade near high volume nodes. They also have a tendency to reject trading around low volume nodes. In accordance with that behavior, we can see that the next target to the downside is around 2040.50. This makes sense - looking back to early April, that was where a lot of the volume traded. So again, as a downside target reference, <strong>I&rsquo;m expecting traders to explore the 2040.50 area next.</strong></p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve also been talking about how falling into this big balance area, <strong>we should expect to target the other side of balance at 2012</strong> if we start to see some sellers step up. Keep this target in mind going forward.</p>

<p>Below that, there are many more weak downside reference points, but I will bring them up as we get closer to them. For now, <strong>focus on the large volume node at 2040.50, and then the balance area low at 2012.</strong></p>

<p>Take this bearish move with a grain of salt, because as I mentioned earlier, all of this trading seems to be done with very low confidence.</p>

<p>Let&rsquo;s take a look at the weeklies for the broad market indices. Here&rsquo;s the SPX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04302016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04302016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-04-30 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>Prior to this past week, we had a green candle that failed to close the week above the trendline resistance. This past week, we confirmed that failure by taking prices lower.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the DJX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04302016/djx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04302016/djx.png" alt="DJX - 2016-04-30 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>Very similar to the SPX. Let&rsquo;s see if we get a continuation to the downside this coming week.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the NDX:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04302016/ndx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04302016/ndx.png" alt="NDX - 2016-04-30 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>This one, as continuously mentioned, is the weakest of the bunch and exhibits the bearishness more clearly than the other indices. Watch for a break of the 4300 level, and see how the 38% fib level holds.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the RUT:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04302016/rut.png"><img src="/images/blog/04302016/rut.png" alt="RUT - 2016-04-30 - Daily Chart" /></a></p>

<p>Currently testing that trendline support. If that support fails, I&rsquo;ll be looking to target the upward-sloping trendline support first at around 1100.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for this weekend&rsquo;s market recap and outlook. With more volatility coming back into the markets, watch out for more trades from me, which I will tweet out. Make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a>, because that&rsquo;s where I post all of my trades in real-time. Make sure you turn on notifications specifically from me. Just visit my Twitter profile on mobile, select the Settings gear, and then select the option to turn on notifications.</p>

<p>Enjoy the weekend guys, and stay safe out there.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
