<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: spy | ThetaTrades]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/categories/spy/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-02-16T17:45:09-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[theta]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Conservative SPY Short Against Trend]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/01/30/a-conservative-spy-short-against-trend/"/>
    <updated>2017-01-30T21:56:33-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2017/01/30/a-conservative-spy-short-against-trend</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Many bears coming out today.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s always quite hard to fight against the trend - bears usually find themselves frustrated as it has taken some time for down moves to play out.</p>

<p>Knowing this, it&rsquo;s possible to put on a trade that captures a slow dribble down to the middle of the channel we&rsquo;ve been forming on the SPY. Observe chart below:</p>

<h3 id="20170130-spy">SPY</h3>


<p><a href="/images/blog/20170130/spy.png"><img src="/images/blog/20170130/spy.png" alt="SPY - 2017-01-30 - Daily" /></a></p>

<p>If we&rsquo;re looking for a pullback to near the 222.5 level, we can buy a 5-point wide Feb put butterfly centered around there, currently going for .74 debit:</p>

<h3 id="20170130-spy-fly">SPY Put Butterfly</h3>


<p><a href="/images/blog/20170130/spy_butterfly.png"><img src="/images/blog/20170130/spy_butterfly.png" alt="Put Butterfly" /></a></p>

<p>Profit target should be about half the max profit, or 2.50. That&rsquo;s roughly a bit over 3R. Adjust number of contracts to fit your risk tolerance.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re interested in more ideas like this, <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow us on Twitter</a> or <a href="https://facebook.com/thetatrades" title="Follow @thetatrades on Facebook">Facebook</a> to receive our tweets and posts in real time! And if you haven&rsquo;t yet, subscribe to our email listing below to receive special email alerts as well.</p>

<p><div class="mailchimp-container">
<!-- Begin MailChimp Signup Form -->
<link href="//cdn-images.mailchimp.com/embedcode/classic-10_7.css" rel="stylesheet" type="text/css">
<style type="text/css">
	#mc_embed_signup{background:#fff; clear:left; font:14px Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif; }
	/* Add your own MailChimp form style overrides in your site stylesheet or in this style block.
	   We recommend moving this block and the preceding CSS link to the HEAD of your HTML file. */
</style>
<div id="mc_embed_signup">
<form action="//thetatrades.us15.list-manage.com/subscribe/post?u=6bda6bf3f9f26dec5de37ce46&amp;id=0e87c74d0f" method="post" id="mc-embedded-subscribe-form" name="mc-embedded-subscribe-form" class="validate" target="_blank" novalidate>
    <div id="mc_embed_signup_scroll">
	<h2>Subscribe to our mailing list</h2>
<div class="indicates-required"><span class="asterisk">*</span> indicates required</div>
<div class="mc-field-group">
	<label for="mce-EMAIL">Email Address  <span class="asterisk">*</span>
</label>
	<input type="email" value="" name="EMAIL" class="required email" id="mce-EMAIL">
</div>
<div class="mc-field-group">
	<label for="mce-FNAME">First Name </label>
	<input type="text" value="" name="FNAME" class="" id="mce-FNAME">
</div>
<div class="mc-field-group">
	<label for="mce-LNAME">Last Name </label>
	<input type="text" value="" name="LNAME" class="" id="mce-LNAME">
</div>
	<div id="mce-responses" class="clear">
		<div class="response" id="mce-error-response" style="display:none"></div>
		<div class="response" id="mce-success-response" style="display:none"></div>
	</div>    <!-- real people should not fill this in and expect good things - do not remove this or risk form bot signups-->
    <div style="position: absolute; left: -5000px;" aria-hidden="true"><input type="text" name="b_6bda6bf3f9f26dec5de37ce46_0e87c74d0f" tabindex="-1" value=""></div>
    <div class="clear"><input type="submit" value="Subscribe" name="subscribe" id="mc-embedded-subscribe" class="button"></div>
    </div>
</form>
</div>

<!--End mc_embed_signup-->
</div>

<script src="//z-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/onejs?MarketPlace=US&adInstanceId=3c36f001-e4b7-4c98-bffa-716b4f4878ab"></script>
</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Breaking out of Balance]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/13/breaking-out-of-balance/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-13T18:18:12-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/13/breaking-out-of-balance</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The market broke out of balance very clearly today to the upside as we mentioned yesterday:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04132016/esm6.png"><img src="/images/blog/04132016/esm6.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-04-13 - Market Profile - 15d Zoomed In" /></a></p>

<p>We attempted to trade back below balance, but failed as buyers kept the market up.</p>

<p>On the SPX, we now have clearance to tag the uppermost trendline resistance this Friday at around 2090.</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04132016/spx.png"><img src="/images/blog/04132016/spx.png" alt="SPX - 2016-04-13 - Trendline Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>Also, from now on for the SPX chart, the pink rectangles will be removed - the target here has been reached.</p>

<p>Watch for the top of the balance area to hold as support, because we can just as easily fail tomorrow and fall back into the balance area, which is not a strong Bullish signal. If that&rsquo;s the case, I&rsquo;ll be looking for a rotation all the way back down to the bottom of the balance area (2012) as a weekly play. However, tomorrow, I&rsquo;m looking for some consolidation before any moves higher.</p>

<p>One of the plays that I&rsquo;m looking at currently is the SPY MAY2/APR5 211/210 Diagonal Call spread, currently going for about .26 debit:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04132016/spy_call_diagonal.png"><img src="/images/blog/04132016/spy_call_diagonal.png" alt="SPY Diagonal Call Spread - 2016-04-13 - Risk Graph" /></a></p>

<p>This has breakevens at around 206 and 212 over the next few weeks. Given the low volatility that we&rsquo;ve been having and the low confidence in any downmove, as long as we stay in this range, we should be good to milk some premium. I&rsquo;ll be looking to put this on tomorrow.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today. I&rsquo;ll keep posting new entries/adjustments on Twitter, so be sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> to get all of my updates in real time.</p>

<p>Good luck in the markets and good trading!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Preparing for a Breakout]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/09/preparing-for-a-breakout/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-09T13:26:26-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/09/preparing-for-a-breakout</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This market has been consolidating in a big balance area for a while now, with the volume POC for the past 15 days at around the 2040.75 level in the /ES:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04092016/esm6.png"><img src="/images/blog/04092016/esm6.png" alt="/ESM6 - 2016-04-09 - Market Profile" /></a></p>

<p>The composite doesn&rsquo;t look quite skewed in any direction, so I would say we&rsquo;re right in the middle of this entire balance area between 2012 and 2067.</p>

<p>Keep in mind 2012 goes back to a spike high from March 16 (refer to <a href="/blog/2016/03/18/the-most-dangerous-aspect-of-the-recent-rally/" title="Weak Reference Points">this post for more info</a> ), as well as a <em>close</em> touch of that point back in March 24. Keep this weak reference point in mind going forward.</p>

<p>Short term traders continue to be the dominant players here, getting themselves overly long or overly short. Until we see some bigger players come into play and break us out of balance, assume that we trade within the denoted range.</p>

<p>Overall, momentum in the board market indices does look like it is slowing and rounding off. My bias here is still neutral, and with such low IV, it doesn&rsquo;t make sense to be selling premium. If you have a directional bias and you&rsquo;re bearish, selling calls might not be a bad idea. Personally, I&rsquo;d want to be buying cheap OOM calendar spreads.</p>

<p>We haven&rsquo;t really traded options on the indices in a while, but here&rsquo;s a trade idea on the SPY utilizing an OOM put calendar:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04092016/spy_put_calendar.png"><img src="/images/blog/04092016/spy_put_calendar.png" alt="SPY - 2016-04-09 - Put Calendar Risk Graph" /></a></p>

<p>We&rsquo;d like SPY to trade between 190 and 202 by expiration. Adjust strikes as necessary. If you want to collect a credit, you can think about moving the nearer term strike higher.</p>

<p>A simple call credit spread on the SPY is also not a bad idea. I may be looking to put some on this coming week, depending on conditions.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m also thinking about a Bullish play on AMZN:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04092016/amzn.png"><img src="/images/blog/04092016/amzn.png" alt="AMZN - 2016-04-09 - Daily - Sitting at Horizontal Support" /></a></p>

<p>AMZN is holding up at the horizontal support level and the upward trendline support level. One of the things I&rsquo;m looking to do is put on a call condor on AMZN that includes the earnings cycle, obviously as an earnings play. I&rsquo;ll also be looking to finance this condor by selling put spreads beneath trendline support for the weeks prior to earnings, as long as the market continues to stay in balance. The reason I&rsquo;m thinking about putting on this trade is that if the market does continue to stay in balance or climb higher, AMZN usually won&rsquo;t sell off and may even climb higher as well into earnings.</p>

<p>Currently the APR5 660/670/690/700 call condor is being priced in for about .89 debit:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04092016/amzn_call_condor.png"><img src="/images/blog/04092016/amzn_call_condor.png" alt="AMZN - 2016-04-09 - Call Condor Risk Graph" /></a></p>

<p>I might buy a few of these. These and the put spreads will need to be managed if AMZN starts to lose the support levels.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ll be looking to put on these trades come Monday, so <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> to get my updates. And to make the most out of Twitter, make sure you turn on notifications specifically from me. Just visit my Twitter profile on mobile, select the Settings gear, and then select the option to turn on notifications.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for the weekend update - enjoy the weekend, and good trading on Monday!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Potential Upside Plays]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/03/potential-upside-plays/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-03T21:34:10-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.thetatrades.com/blog/2016/04/03/potential-upside-plays</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been looking at a couple of trade setups given the bullish follow-through I&rsquo;m expecting this coming week and the lack of bearishness out there.</p>

<p>First is GS:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04032016/gs.png"><img src="/images/blog/04032016/gs.png" alt="GS - 2016-04-03 - Daily - Trendline Resistance" /></a></p>

<p>We&rsquo;ve currently put in a rounded-bottom / inverted head-and-shoulders pattern, and on Friday it appears that we&rsquo;re just breaking out of that right shoulder. If we continue to see bullishness, GS has room to run up to the trendline resistance. This should bring us to about 177 by the time of their earnings. As I&rsquo;m expecting a short term run up, this could make for a (slightly aggressive) potential options play:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04032016/gs_risk_reversal.png"><img src="/images/blog/04032016/gs_risk_reversal.png" alt="GS - 2016-04-03 - Bull Call Spread Financed by Put Backratio" /></a></p>

<p>We&rsquo;ll buy a slightly OOM call vertical and finance it by selling a put backratio with 11 days to go. We&rsquo;re currently getting a credit for this, but of course this will have to be priced again on Monday.</p>

<p>For those that are a bit more conservative and would like more room for error in case we do have a downside move, consider a longer term play that <em>includes</em> the earnings cycle:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04032016/gs_batman.png"><img src="/images/blog/04032016/gs_batman.png" alt="GS - 2016-04-03 - Put Backratio With Call Backratio" /></a></p>

<p>Your range of profit potential is wide, with the peaks denoting the max profits (about $500 per spread). With pretty wide breakevens, and the fact that GS doesn&rsquo;t usually move much from earnings, this is a safer approach that could help you profit from either a move up to the 175 area which is near the trendline resistance, or down to the 140 area which is near prior support levels. I personally like this trade more, as we have duration to help us out, too, in case we&rsquo;re wrong on direction.</p>

<p>Another idea is the SPY:</p>

<p><a href="/images/blog/04032016/spy_diagonal.png"><img src="/images/blog/04032016/spy_diagonal.png" alt="SPY - 2016-04-03 - Diagonal Call Spread" /></a></p>

<p>This is not a short term trade, but one that has a wide breakeven as well by expiration. If you don&rsquo;t expect the SPY to move past 211 by the next few weeks, or if you expect it to slowly grind higher, a cheap diagonal here could be the play.</p>

<p>These are just a couple of ideas that I&rsquo;m looking to put on for Monday - they may be adjusted slightly depending on how the market opens on Monday and where things are priced. I will tweet out the exact trade that I put on in real time, though. Make sure to <a href="https://twitter.com/theta_positive" title="Follow @thetatrades on Twitter">follow me on Twitter</a> and turn on notifications from me to get my posts in real time (no I don&rsquo;t post pictures of cats or food - no spam, just trades only).</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for now - good luck, and let&rsquo;s have another week of good trading.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
